Unsupervised Learning.
Unlike supervised learning,
unsupervised learning algorithms train on unlabeled data.
The training model learns from data without
any guidance or known outputs and labels.
It scans through the input data, trying
to group them together according to their similarities,
such as colors,
sizes, shapes, and others.
There is no right and wrong answers.
The objective is to analyze the data to
find hidden patterns and groupings within the data.
As the training data
for unsupervised learning
does not require labeling,
setup is easy.
It saves a data scientist from having to
label everything, which can be a challenging task.
No data labeling also means no preconceived ideas and no bias.
However, the limitation of this method is that
it cannot give precise predictions.
Here are some problem types or use cases
that can be addressed by unsupervised learning.
Dimension reduction.
Dimension reduction is used to determine the most
relevant features to use for model construction.
It is the process of reducing the dimension
of your feature set such that it still retains
the most significant properties of the original data.
This helps in data compression
and feature selection.
Cluster analysis.
Cluster analysis
is used to classify objects into groups
called clusters.
It attempts to find discrete groupings within data
where members of a group are as similar as possible to one another,
and as different as possible from members of other groups.
Cluster analysis is used in applications
such as market research and image processing.
Anomaly detection.
Anomaly detection
is the identification of outliers or observations in a dataset
which raise suspicions, because they differ significantly
from the rest of the data.
The identification of anomalous items can be used, for example,
to detect bank fraud and medical errors.