Amazon S3 - More features
Amazon S3 also provides a wide range of
storage classes:
S3 standard
S3 intelligent tiering
S3 standard infrequent access, or IA
S3 one zone infrequent access, or S3 one
zone IA.
and the three Amazon S3 Glacier storage
classes
Each S3 storage class supports a specific
data access level.
S3 standard is for general purpose storage
of frequently accessed data.
It delivers low latency and high
throughput, and can access data in milliseconds.
S3 Intelligent Tiering is for data with
unknown or changing access patterns.
It automatically moves your data between a
frequent access and an infrequent access tier based on changing access patterns - without performance impact, or operational overhead.
S3 standard IA  and S3 one zone IA are
for long lived but less frequently accessed data.
Since S3 one zone infrequent access only
stores data in one availability zone, it fits best for data that can be recreated.
S3 Glacier storage classes are for long
term archive and digital preservation.
S3 intelligent Tiering, S3 standard IA
and S3 one zone IA also have the same low latency and high throughput performance as S3 standard.
S3 glacier instant retrieval storage class
delivers the lowest cost storage with milliseconds retrieval. It is designed for archive data that needs immediate access
For archive data that does not require
immediate access, choose S3 Glacier flexible retrieval, with retrieval in minutes, or free bulk retrievals in 5 to 12 hours
To save even more on long lived archive
storage, choose S3 Glacier Deep Archive, the lowest cost storage, with data retrieval from 12 to 48 hours.
With a wide range of storage classes
offered by S3. You can choose which ones best fits your data profile and use cases
To classify, manage and report on your
data, Amazon S3 also provides easy to use management tools for granular data control.
You can use S3 storage class analysis to
discover data that should move to a lower cost storage class based on access patterns.
Then you can use this information to
configure an S3 lifecycle policy that makes the data transfer
S3 lifecycle policy defines when objects
transition to another storage class and when objects expire.
It helps to manage your objects so that
they are stored cost effectively throughout their life cycle.
In addition, you can use S3 cross-region
replication to replicate data into other AWS regions. You can also replicate data within the same AWS region.
S3 Object Lock. Objects are locked for the
duration of the retention period that you define and are protected from deletion.
You can enforce, write-once, read-many
policies with S3 object lock
S3 Inventory report lists your stored
objects, their metadata and encryption status
You can also use S3 batch operations
to change object properties and perform storage management tasks for billions of objects.
With S3 batch operations and a single S3
API request, or a few clicks In the Amazon S3 management console, you can perform batch operations such as, copy objects between buckets, replace object tag sets, modify access controls and restore archived objects from Amazon S3 Glacier.
Since Amazon S3 works with AWS Lambda, you
can log activities, define alerts and automate workflows without managing additional infrastructure.
With query in-place services, you can run
big data analytics directly across your S3 objects and other data sets in AWS.
This means you can run big data analytics
directly on your data stored in Amazon S3 that allows you to query data without needing to copy and load it into a separate analytics platform or data warehouse.
Amazon S3 is also compatible with AWS
analytic services, Amazon Athena and Amazon redshift spectrum.
You can use Amazon Athena to query S3 data
with standard SQL expressions.
Amazon Redshift spectrum also runs SQL
queries directly against data at rest in Amazon S3, and is more appropriate for complex queries and large data sets up to exabytes.
You can also use S3 select to retrieve
subsets of object data instead of the entire object, which can be up to five terabytes in size.
It is designed to increase query
performance by up to 400 percent and reduce querying costs as much as 80%.
Versioning is a means of keeping multiple
variants of an object in the same bucket.
Buckets can be in one of three states:
un-versioned, which is the default, versioning enabled, or versioning suspended.
When versioning is suspended It will
suspend the creation of version ID for new objects but preserve all the existing object versions.
Once you enable versioning the combination
of a bucket key and version ID uniquely identify each object.
After the bucket is version enabled, it
can never return to an un-versioned state.
You can, however, suspend versioning on
that bucket
You can use versioning to preserve,
retrieve and restore every version of every object stored in your Amazon S3 bucket
Versioning enabled buckets enable you to
recover objects from accidental deletion or overwrite.
If you delete an object it is not
permanently deleted, Amazon S3 inserts a delete marker.
If you overwrite an object, it results in
a new object version in the bucket. You can restore the previous version as long as the object has not been deleted.