Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud Overview.
Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud, or EC2,
is a web service that provides
secure, resizable compute capacity in the cloud.
It eliminates your need
for up-front hardware investment,
so you can develop and deploy applications faster.
You can use Amazon EC2 to launch as many or as few virtual servers as you need.
Amazon EC2 enables you to scale up or down within minutes
to handle changes or spikes in requirements,
reducing your need to forecast traffic.
It provides you with complete control of your computing resources and
lets you run on Amazon's proven, reliable, and scalable computing environment.
Amazon EC2 is hosted in multiple locations worldwide comprised of
AWS Regions which consists of at least three Availability Zones.
This computing environment provides high availability
with service-level agreement, or SLA,
commitment of 99.99% availability for each Amazon EC2 region.
In addition, security at AWS is our top priority.
AWS is built to meet the requirements
of the most security-sensitive organizations.
First, let's go through some of the Amazon EC2 basics.
What is an instance?
An instance is a virtual server in the cloud.
Amazon EC2 provides a wide selection of instance
types to enable you to choose the CPU,
memory, storage, networking capacity,
and GPU for your applications.
Here are the instance type categories:
General-purpose instances
are instances that provide a balance of compute, memory, and networking resources.
Compute-optimized instances are optimized for compute-intensive workloads.
Memory-optimized instances.
These instances are for memory-intensive workloads
that process large datasets in memory.
Storage-optimized instances.
They are designed for workloads that require sequential read and
write access to very large datasets on local storage.
Accelerated computing instances.
These are GPU instances that use hardware accelerators.
HPC optimized instances.
These instances are optimized for high-performance computing workloads.
These instance types are optimized to fit different use cases.
Here is just one of the many examples for each instance type.
In addition,
each instance type includes one or more instance sizes,
allowing you to scale your resources
to the requirements of your target workload.
AMI stands for Amazon Machine Image.
An AMI provides the information required to launch an instance.
It is a template that contains
a software configuration such as an operating system,
applications, and an application server.
You must specify an AMI when you launch an instance.
You can launch a single instance or multiple instances from an AMI.