Amazon Pinpoint Overview
Amazon Pinpoint is an AWS service that
you can use to engage with your customers across multiple messaging channels.
You can use Amazon Pinpoint to send email,
SMS text messages, voice messages, and push notifications.
The Amazon Pinpoint Email API  provides
programmatic access to options that are unique to the email channel, and supplement the options provided by the Amazon Pinpoint API.
Features of Amazon Pinpoint
Define audience segments
Reach the right audience for your messages
by defining audience segments.
A segment designates which users receive
the messages that are sent from a campaign or journey.
You can define dynamic segments based on
data that's reported by your application, such as operating system or mobile device type.
Messaging Campaigns
Engage your audience by creating a
messaging campaign.
A campaign sends tailored messages on a
schedule that you define.
You can create campaigns that send push
notifications, email, SMS text messages, and voice messages.
Create User Journeys
Create custom, multi-step experiences for
your customers by designing and building journeys.
With journeys, you can send messages to
your customers based on their attributes, behaviors, and activities.
When you build a journey, you design an
automated workflow of activities that perform a variety of different actions.
Provide Consistent Messaging
Design consistent messages, and reuse
content more effectively, by creating and using message templates.
A message template contains content and
settings that you want to reuse in messages that you send for any of your Amazon Pinpoint projects.
You can create templates for email, push
notifications, SMS messages, and voice messages.
Deliver personalized content
Send content that's customized for each
recipient of a message.
Using message variables and attributes,
you can deliver dynamic, personalized content in messages that you send from campaigns and journeys.
With message templates, this content can
come from attributes that you create directly in Amazon Pinpoint, or from a machine learning model that you create in Amazon Personalize.
Analyze User Behavior
Gain insight into your audience and the
effectiveness of your campaigns and messaging activities by using the analytics that Amazon Pinpoint provides.
You can view trends, in your users' level
of engagement, purchase activity, demographics, and more.