Amazon Comprehend.
Natural language processing, or NLP,
is a way for computers
to analyze, understand,
and derive meaning
from textual information
in a smart and useful way.
Amazon Comprehend is an NLP service that uses machine
learning to find meaning and insights in text.
You can use Amazon Comprehend to identify the language of the text
and identify the main topics from a library of documents.
You can extract key phrases, places, people, brands, or events
and understand sentiment about products or services.
The source of this text could be web pages, social-media feeds,
emails, or articles, or a set of text documents.
Amazon Comprehend is a fully managed and continuously trained service,
so you don't have to manage the scaling of resources,
maintenance of code, or maintenance of the training data.
To use Amazon Comprehend,
you don't need NLP expertise.
You only need to call the Amazon Comprehend API,
and the service will handle the machine learning required
to extract the relevant data from the text.
Let's look at some benefits.
Discover insights. Uncover valuable insights from text
such as customer support tickets,
support emails,
and social-media feeds
to understand customer sentiment and generate voice-of-the-customer analytics.
Differentiate your business.
Differentiate the capabilities of your business
by training a model to classify documents
and identify terms from text
with no ML experience required.
Document processing.
Simplify document processing workflows by extracting text, topics,
key phrases, and more from documents such as insurance claims.
Protect access to PII.
Protect and control who has access
to your sensitive data
by identifying
and redacting
personally identifiable information, or PII, from documents.
Let's look at some more features.
Language Support.
Amazon Comprehend can perform text analysis on English, French, German, Italian,
Portuguese, and Spanish texts.
The language detection API
automatically identifies text written in over 100 languages
and returns the dominant language with a confidence score.
Custom Entity Recognition.
Custom entity recognition allows you to
identify terms that are specific to your domain.
Using AutoML,
Comprehend learns terms from examples,
then trains a private custom model
to recognize terms
within PDFs,
plain text, or Microsoft Word documents.
Custom Classification.
The custom classification API enables you to easily build custom
text classification models without a single line of code.
Using your business-specific labels,
you can automatically categorize inbound requests
by customer description of the issue.
And an SDK
is available to integrate your
custom classifier into your current applications.
Comprehend Medical.
Medical named entity and relationship extraction returns
medical information from texts such as medication,
medical condition, treatment and procedures, or TTP, anatomy,
and protected health information, or PHI.