Amazon OpenSearch Overview.
Amazon OpenSearch Service is a managed service that makes it easy to deploy,
operate, and scale open-search clusters in the AWS Cloud.
Amazon OpenSearch Service is
the successor to Amazon Elasticsearch Service and
supports OpenSearch and legacy Elasticsearch.
OpenSearch is a fully open-source search and
analytics engine for use cases such as log analytics,
real-time application monitoring,
and clickstream analysis.
Amazon OpenSearch Service provisions
all the resources for your cluster and launches it.
It also automatically detects and replaces failed nodes,
reducing the overhead associated with self-managed infrastructures.
You can scale your cluster with a single API call or a few clicks in the console.
Here are the key benefits. Harness the power of OpenSearch.
Amazon OpenSearch Service offers the latest versions of OpenSearch,
support for 19 versions of open-source Elasticsearch versions 1.5 to 7.10,
and visualization capabilities powered by OpenSearch
dashboards and corresponding versions of Kibana.
Operate OpenSearch with the leading contributor of the community-driven
open-source software.
Increase efficiency.
Eliminate operational overhead and reduce cost with automated provisioning,
software installation,
patching,
storage tiering,
and more.
Go beyond basic search and analytics.
Use machine learning to detect anomalies in real time.
Auto-tune your clusters and personalize your search results.
Access operational data in real time.
You can use Amazon OpenSearch Service to quickly search and analyze
your unstructured and semi-structured data to find what you need.
OpenSearch Features.
Scale.
OpenSearch provides a highly scalable system
for fast access to large volumes of data
and many configurations of CPU, memory,
and storage capacity up to three petabytes,
with cost-effective, UltraWarm,
and cold storage for read-only data.
Security.
Meet and maintain high security for authentication,
authorization, encryption, audit,
and regulatory compliance using index, document, and field-level security,
HTTP basic or SAML authentication,
and integration with AWS IAM, Amazon VPC, and Amazon Cognito.
Flexibility.
OpenSearch provides SQL integration with business-intelligence
applications and custom packages to improve search results.
Stability.
OpenSearch is available in multiple Regions and
allocates nodes across two or three Availability Zones
And dedicated management nodes automate cluster tasks,
such as snapshots to back up and restore your domains.