Amazon MSK Overview.
Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka, or Amazon MSK,
is a fully managed service that helps you build
and run applications that use Apache Kafka to collect,
process, store, and analyze data at scale.
Apache Kafka is a distributed datastore optimized for
ingesting and processing streaming data in real time.
Kafka provides three main functions to its users.
Publish and subscribe to streams of records,
effectively store streams of records in the
order in which the records were generated,
and process streams of records in real time.
The streaming data solution for Amazon MSK helps you address
real-time streaming use cases such as capturing high volume application
log files,
analyzing website click streams, processing
database event streams, tracking financial transactions,
aggregating social media feeds, and continuously delivering to a data lake.
Features.
High availability.
Amazon MSK clusters are distributed across multiple Availability Zones
with three AZs as the default.
These clusters are also supported by the Amazon MSK service-level agreement
and by automated systems that detect and respond
to issues within the cluster infrastructure
and Apache Kafka software.
Highly secure.
Your Apache Kafka clusters run in a Virtual Private Cloud, or VPC,
managed by Amazon MSK.
A cluster authentication is streamlined by using AWS Identity and
Access Management roles or user policies to control access.
Amazon MSK also encrypts your data at
rest without special configuration or third-party tools.
Deeply integrated.
Amazon MSK offers integrations with many
AWS services including IAM,
Amazon Kinesis Data Analytics,
AWS IoT Core,
AWS Database Migration Service,
Amazon Key Management Service,
and many more.