Amazon Personalize overview.
Amazon Personalize is a machine learning service
that generates item recommendations for your users
primarily based on data gathered when users interact with items in your catalog.
This data can come from historical bulk interaction records
in a CSV file and from real time user interactions.
Common use cases for Amazon Personalize include
adding product recommendations to an
e-commerce app,
segmenting users based on preferences
such as product category and brand,
and personalizing video recommendations to a streaming app.
To get started - step one, create a dataset group.
A dataset group is a container for Amazon Personalize resources.
Dataset groups come in two types.
A domain dataset group creates resources for a specific use case,
such as a streaming video
or an e-commerce application.
A custom dataset group includes custom resources for custom use cases
based on your business needs.
Step two - import data to Amazon Personalize.
Data can be imported in bulk, individually, or both.
Bulk data can be prepared and imported by using Amazon SageMaker Data Wrangler
or from a CSV file stored in Amazon's simple storage service.
Individual records can be imported through
the Amazon Personalize console and API operations
or interactions data from live events can be imported in real time.
Step three - create recommenders or custom resources.
A recommender is a resource in a domain dataset group.
The recommenders use machine learning models trained
by Amazon personalize to generate recommendations.
Custom resources are resources in a custom dataset group.
Custom resources include a solution, solution version, and campaign.
A solution includes an Amazon Personalize recipe,
customized parameters, and one or more solution versions.
Solution version is a trained machine
learning model that generates recommendations.
Finally, a campaign deploys a solution version for real-time recommendations.
Step four - get recommendations
Recommenders in a domain dataset group and custom resources
in a custom dataset group support real-time recommendations.
However,
batch recommendation can only be generated by
custom resources in a custom dataset group.
Custom resources and imported data should be kept up
to date to maintain the relevance of recommendations.
This is the end of Amazon Personalize overview.
Thanks for watching.