Amazon API Gateway Overview
Amazon API Gateway is a fully managed
service that developers can use to publish, maintain, monitor, secure, and operate APIs at any scale.
API Gateway is a pay-as-you-go service
that removes the heavy lifting involved in securely and reliably running APIs at scale.
APIs act as the front door for
applications to access data, business logic, or functionality from your backend services.
Using API Gateway, you can create RESTful
APIs and WebSocket APIs that enable real-time, two-way communication applications.
Key Features
Support for RESTful APIs and WebSocket
APIs
With API Gateway, you can create RESTful
APIs by using either HTTP APIs or REpresentational State Transfer, or REST APIs.
HTTP APIs are the best way to build APIs
that do not require API management features.
They are optimized for serverless
workloads and HTTP backends.
REST APIs are used for workloads that
require API proxy functionality and API management features.
WebSocket APIs are used to build
real-time, two-way communication applications, such as chat apps and streaming dashboards.
Resiliency
You can use API Gateway to set throttling
rules based on the number of requests per second for each HTTP method in your APIs.
This helps you manage traffic to your
backend systems. API Gateway handles any level of traffic received by an API, so you are free to focus on your business logic and services rather than maintaining infrastructure.
AWS authorization
To authorize and verify API requests to
AWS services, API Gateway can help you leverage signature version 4 for REST APIs and WebSocket APIs.
Using signature version 4 authentication,
you can use AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) and access policies to authorize access to your APIs and all your other AWS resources.
Benefits
Performance at any scale
Provide end users with the lowest possible
latency for API requests and responses by taking advantage of the AWS global network of edge locations using Amazon CloudFront.
Streamlined monitoring
Monitor performance metrics and
information on API calls, data latency, and error rates from the API Gateway dashboard, which allows you to visually monitor calls to your services using Amazon CloudWatch.
Efficient API development
Run multiple versions of the same API
simultaneously, allowing you to quickly iterate, test, and release new versions.
Applications can continue to call previous
API versions even after the latest versions are published.
API Gateway also helps you manage multiple
release stages for each API version, such as alpha, beta, and production.