Amazon Translate Overview
Amazon Translate is a text translation
service
that uses advanced machine learning
technologies
to provide translation on demand.
Amazon Translate uses attention mechanisms
to understand context.
These mechanisms help Amazon Translate
decide
which words in the source text
are most relevant
for generating the next target word.
Amazon Translate can automatically
detect the language used
in your source text.
You can use Amazon Translate to translate
unstructured text documents,
or to build applications that work in
multiple languages.
Amazon Translate Use Cases
Translate user-generated content
Automatically translate
high volumes of user-generated content in real time,
such as social media feed stories,
profile descriptions,
and comments.
Analyze online conversations in different
languages.
Understand sentiments toward your brand,
product, or service
by using a natural language processing
application
that analyzes text in multiple languages.
Create cross-lingual communications
between users.
Add real-time translation within chat,
email, helpdesk,
and ticketing applications,
so that an English-speaking agent
can communicate with customers
across multiple languages.
Amazon Translate Benefits
Uses deep learning techniques.
Amazon Translate uses deep learning
techniques
that consider the entire context
of the source sentence
and the translation it has generated so
far
to produce more accurate and fluent
translation.
Perform batch and real-time translations.
Amazon Translate can perform batch
translations
when you have large quantities
of text to translate.
It can perform real-time translations
when you want to deliver
on-demand translations of content
as a feature of your applications.
Customize translations
You can use the following settings
to customize the translations
that you produce with Amazon Translate.
The Do Not Translate Tag setting.
specifies content
that you do not want to translate.
The custom terminology setting helps to
define
how you want Amazon Translate to translate specific terms such as brand names.
The profanity setting masks profane words and phrases in your translation output.
Set the level of language formality in your translation output.
The Parallel Data setting helps you customize the output of your batch translations
jobs.
.
This is the end of Amazon Translate
overview. Thanks for watching.