Welcome to an Overview of Amazon Route 53.
Amazon Route 53
is a highly available
and scalable cloud domain name system,
that provides a reliable and cost effective way
for developers and businesses
to route end users to internet applications.
This is achieved by translating names like www.example.com
into numeric IP addresses like
192.0.2.1,
that enable computers to connect to each other.
Amazon Route 53 is also fully compliant
with internet protocol version six, or IPv6.
Amazon Route 53
connects user requests to infrastructure running in AWS
such as Amazon S3 buckets or Amazon Elastic Load Balances,
and can also be used to route users to infrastructure outside of AWS.
Amazon Route 53 traffic flow
simplifies traffic management globally
through a variety of rooting types,
including latency based routing
that routes uses to the AWS region that provides the lowest possible latency.
Geo DNS routing
that routes users to a particular endpoint that you
specify based on the end user's geographic location.
Geoproximity routing
that routes traffic to your resources based on
the geographic location of your users and your resources.
Weighted round robin routing
that specifies the frequency
with which different DNS responses
are returned to end users.
And Failover routing
that lets you route traffic to a resource when
the resource is healthy, or to a different resource
when the first resource is unhealthy.
You can also use Amazon Route 53 Application Recovery Controller
to configure DNS health checks,
that continuously monitor your application's ability to recover from failures
and control application recovery.
Amazon Route 53 has a simple web services interface
that lets you get started in minutes.
You start by creating an Amazon Route 53 Hosted Zone
that can store DNS records for your domain.
Once you create a hosted zone,
you receive four Route 53 name servers
to help ensure a high level of availability for your applications.
If you don't have a domain name, you can create one with route 53
or transfer an existing domain that you already own.
So you can conveniently manage your domain names
and DNS configuration in a single location.
Your hosted zone will be initially populated with a basic set of DNS records,
including four virtual name servers
that will answer queries for your domain.
You can add,
delete or change records in this set
using the AWS Management Console
or by calling the change resource record set API.
Amazon Route 53
supports many DNS record types,
including a records that route traffic to a resource
such as a web server
and CNAME records that allow you to redirect one domain name to another.
Route 53 also includes alias records
that let you route traffic to selected AWS resources
like Amazon S3,
and Amazon CloudFront.