Amazon Relational Database Service (RDS) - Features.
Manageability and Cost Effectiveness.
Here are the Amazon RDS key features related to manageability.
Monitoring and metrics.
Amazon RDS provides Amazon CloudWatch metrics for
your database instances at no additional charge.
You can use the RDS Management Console to view
key operational metrics including compute, memory, storage capacity
utilization, IO
activity, and instance connections.
Amazon RDS also provides enhanced monitoring which provides
access to over 50 metrics including CPU, memory,
file system, and disk I/O metrics as well as performance insights.
Performance Insights is an easy-to-use
database performance tuning and monitoring tool that
helps you quickly access the load on
your database and detect performance problems.
Event notifications.
Amazon RDS can notify you using email or SMS text message
of database events through Amazon SNS.
You can use the AWS Management Console or the Amazon RDS APIs to subscribe
to over 40 different database events associated with your database instances.
Configuration governance.
Amazon RDS integrates with AWS Config
to support compliance and enhance security by recording and
auditing changes to the configuration of your DB instance,
including parameter groups, subnet groups, snapshots,
security groups, and event subscriptions.
Here are the key features related to cost-effectiveness. Pay only for what you use.
There is no up-front commitment with Amazon RDS.
You simply pay a monthly charge for each database instance
that you launch. When you're finished with a database instance,
you can easily delete it.
Reserved instances.
Amazon RDS Reserved Instances give you the option
to reserve a DB instance for a 1- or
3-year term and in turn receive a
significant discount compared to the on-demand instance
pricing for the DB instance.
Stop and start. Amazon RDS allows you to easily stop and start
your database instances for up to 7 days at a time.
This makes it easy and affordable to
use databases for development and test purposes
where the database is not required to be running all of the time.