Amazon Elastic File System (Amazon EFS) Features.
Storage Classes and Lifecycle Management.
Amazon EFS offers two storage classes,
the standard storage class and the infrequent access storage class, or EFS IA.
The standard storage class is used to store frequently accessed files.
The infrequent access, or IA, is a lower-cost storage class
that's designed for storing files not accessed every day.
You can start using EFS IA
by simply enabling EFS Lifecycle Management for your file system.
When enabled, lifecycle management migrates files
that have not been accessed for a set period of time
to the infrequent access, or IA, storage class.
You can define the period of time by using a lifecycle policy.
Using the industry accepted estimate that 20% of data is actively used
and 80% is infrequently accessed,
you can store your files on EFS
at an effective price of $0.08 per gigabyte-month.
Performance modes.
Amazon EFS offers two performance modes, General Purpose and Max I/O.
General Purpose provides the lowest latency per file system operation
and can achieve this for random or sequential IO patterns.
Max IO can scale to higher levels of aggregate throughput and operations per second
and is ideal for highly parallelized applications
that can scale up to thousands of Amazon EC2 instances.
Throughput modes.
The throughput mode helps determine the overall throughput a file system can achieve.
Amazon EFS offers two throughput modes, bursting and provisioned.
With bursting throughput, the throughput scales with the size of the file system.
Dynamically bursting is needed to support the spiky nature of many file-based workloads.
Provisioned throughput is designed to support applications
that require higher dedicated throughput than the default bursting mode
and can be configured independently of the amount of data stored on the file system.
Encryption.
Amazon EFS offers encryption of data at rest and in transit,
providing a comprehensive encryption solution.
Data at rest is transparently encrypted using encryption keys
managed by the AWS Key Management Service,
AWS KMS, eliminating the need to build and maintain a key management infrastructure.
Encryption of data in transit uses industry-standard transport layer security, or TLS
to secure network traffic without having to modify your applications.
Containers and serverless file storage.
Amazon EFS is integrated with containers and serverless compute services from AWS
that require shared storage for latency-sensitive
and IOPS-heavy workloads at any scale.
In a single step, Amazon EFS provides applications
running on Amazon Elastic Container Service, or ECS,
Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service, or EKS,
AWS Fargate, and AWS Lambda access to shared file systems for stateful workloads.