Amazon Relational Database Service Features (RDS) - Scalability.
Here are the key features for scalability.
Push-button compute scaling.
You can scale the compute and memory resources vertically up
or down up to a maximum of 32 vCPUs
and 244 gibibytes of RAM.
Compute-scaling operations typically complete in a few minutes.
Easy storage scaling.
The Amazon Aurora engine will automatically grow the size of your database volume,
as your database storage needs to grow up to a
maximum of 64 terabytes or a maximum you define.
The MySQL, MariaDB, Oracle, and PostgreSQL engines
allow you to scale up to 64 terabytes of storage.
And SQL Server supports up to 16 terabytes.
Storage scaling is on the fly
with zero downtime.
Amazon RDS read replicas
provide enhanced performance
and durability for RDS database DB instances.
It helps to offload read-heavy database workloads.
You can create one or more read replicas of a given primary DB instance
within an Availability Zone, cross-AZ, or cross-Region.
The read replica operates as a DB instance that allows only read-only connections,
while master or primary DB instance allows
both read and write connections to your application.
Updates made to the primary DB instance are
asynchronously copied to the read replica.
Using read replicas, you can elastically scale out beyond the capacity constraints of a single DB.
This increases the aggregate read throughput.
Let's look at a common use case. You
want to run a reporting application that performs some
analytics on the RDS database. In order to
reduce the read traffic in the primary database,
you can create a read replica for the reporting
application to read data directly from the read replica instead.
Read replicas can also be promoted to stand-alone
DB instances as a disaster recovery solution
if the primary DB instance fails.
As you can see, read replica help scaling out read operations.
What about write operations?
Amazon Aurora Multi-Master Clusters feature provides the capability
to scale out both your read and write operations
in a multi-master cluster.
An Aurora Cluster consists of a set of master database nodes
and a shared storage volume across multiple Availability Zones
for high availability and durability of user data.
All DB instances can perform read and write operations.
The multi-master cluster
doesn't use the failover mechanism because it doesn't need
to promote another DB instance to have read/write capability.
It offers continuous availability.
Any DB instance in this case
can take over the work of the failed instance.