Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2) Overview - Storage and Networking.
Amazon EC2 provides you with flexible, cost-effective,
and easy-to-use data storage options for your instances.
Instances can access storage from disks
that are physically attached to the host computer.
This disk storage is referred as instance store,
which provides temporary block-level storage for your instance.
You can also attach an Amazon Elastic Block Storage, or EBS,
volume to your EC2 instance for persistent block-level storage.
EBS behaves like a raw, unformatted
external block device.
Your EBS data can be backed up using EBS snapshots and stored in Amazon S3.
Amazon EC2 also uses Amazon S3 for storing Amazon Machine Images, or AMIs.
In addition,
you can also create a file system for use with Amazon EC2.
Amazon Elastic File System, or EFS, provides scalable file storage.
Applications running on your EC2 instances can access your file system at the same time.
Networking defines your network access to your EC2 instances.
Amazon Virtual Private Cloud, or VPC,
lets you provision a logically isolated area within the AWS Cloud,
where you can launch your EC2 instances in a virtual network that you define.
Alternatively, your AWS account comes with a
preconfigured default VPC in each region.
You can launch your EC2 instances into the default VPC right away.
A VPC can also span multiple Availability Zones, or AZs, in a region.
You can add subnets in different AZs and launch instances
into the subnets to improve fault tolerance in your applications.
You can also use multiple layers of security to help control access to
Amazon EC2 instances in each subnet.
For example, you can define a security group
which acts as a virtual firewall that controls the traffic for your instances.
Now, let's look at how these EC2 basic concepts
are used to launch Amazon EC2 instances.
To launch Amazon EC2 instances, first,
you need to determine whether you want to run your Amazon EC2 instances
in a single location or multiple locations, regions,
availability zones.
Select an Amazon Machine Image, or AMI.
Then determine which Amazon EC2 instance types and sizes you want.
You will also need to configure network access and
specify any preferred subnet on your Amazon EC2 instances.
A default route storage is used to boot the instance.
You can edit the root volume or attach additional storage to your instances.
As an option,
you can add tags to your instances.
Tags are used to categorize your resources and
help in searching and managing your resources.
Configure security on your Amazon EC2 instances
such as configure security groups.
You can also secure your login information for your instances using key pairs:
public and private key.
With these simple steps, you can use Amazon EC2
to launch as many or as few instances as you need within minutes.