Amazon DynamoDB Queries - Overview.
You can query any Amazon DynamoDB table
or secondary index and find items based on primary key values.
For the query operation,
you must provide the name of the partition key attribute
and a single value for that attribute.
Query returns all items with that partition key value.
Optionally, you can provide a sort key attribute
and use a comparison operator condition to refine the search results.
Let's start by looking at a DynamoDB query example
using the AWS Command Line Interface, or AWS CLI.
The DynamoDB query CLI command is used to query the "Music" table.
If you want to specify search criteria, you can use a key condition expression.
The expression contains a string that determines the items
to be read from the table or index.
You must specify the partition key name
the "Artist".
Optionally, you can provide a second condition for the sort key if present,
in this case, the song title, and use the following supported comparison operators.
A single query operation can retrieve a maximum of one megabyte of data.
Query results are always sorted by the sort key value.
By default, the sort order is ascending.
To reverse the order, set the scan index forward parameter to false.
If you need to further refine the query results,
after applying the key condition expression,
you can optionally provide a filter expression.
A filter expression cannot contain partition key or sort key attributes.
The expression determines which items within the query results
should be returned to you.
All of the other results are discarded.
It does not consume any additional read capacity units, or RCUs.
The syntax and comparison operators for a filter expression
are identical to that of a condition expression.
If you need to compare an attribute with a value,
define an expression attribute value as a placeholder.
They are used as substitutes for the actual values that you want to compare.
In this example,
we are substituting searched Artist
with a string value of Artist 2,
search Song Title with a string value of Song B,
and the search Year with a number-type value of 2018.
With these expressions and substituted values,
you can find the item with Artist 2,
Song Title Song B that is released after 2018.