Amazon Elastic File System (Amazon EFS) Data Transfer and Backup.
Moving your Amazon EFS file data can be managed simply with AWS DataSync.
AWS DataSync is a managed data transfer service that
simplifies, automates, and accelerates copying data between NFS file shares,
EFS file systems, S3 buckets, and on-premises storage.
AWS DataSync can transfer your file data and also
file system metadata such as ownership, timestamps, and access permissions.
AWS DataSync uses a software agent to connect to your EFS file systems.
It automates scaling and validating transfers.
So you don't have to write scripts,
modify your applications, or manage infrastructure.
You can transfer active datasets over AWS Direct Connect or the internet
at speeds up to 10 times faster than open-source tools.
You can use the service for one-time data migrations,
ongoing workflows with periodic synchronization, and
replication for data protection and recovery.
AWS Backup is a fully managed backup service
that makes it easy to centrally manage and
automate backups of your Amazon EFS file systems,
removing the need for costly custom solutions.
AWS Backup goes beyond backing up Amazon EFS
and centralizes the backup of data across other AWS services in the cloud
as well as on premises.
You do not need to perform backup tasks
service by service,
create custom scripts and manual processes for the backup activities.
Using AWS Backup, you can centrally configure and audit AWS resources,
automate backup scheduling, set retention policies, and monitor backup activity.