Amazon Timestream overview, a time series
database.
Amazon Timestream is a fast, scalable, and
serverless time-series database service for Internet of things (IoT) and other operational applications.
Time-series data is a sequence of data
points recorded over an interval for measuring events over a time span.
Examples of time-series data are stock
prices, temperature measurements, and the CPU utilization of an Amazon EC2 instance.
Amazon Timestream saves time and money
when managing the time-series data lifecycle by keeping recent data in memory, and moving historical data to a cost-optimized magnetic storage tier based upon your user defined policies.
You can use the adaptive query engine in
Timestream to access and analyze recent and historical data at the same time without having to specify whether the data is in-memory or magnetic storage.
Amazon Timestream supports timestamps with
nanosecond granularity, and provides 99.99 percent uptime availability.
Amazon Timestream features.
Performance and scale.
Amazon Timestream offers near real-time
latencies for data ingestion.
Both the built-in memory store, and lower
cost magnetic store, are optimized for rapid point-in-time queries and fast analytical queries.
Timestream automatically scales as your
applications grow.
The distributed architecture of Amazon
Timestream provides massive amounts of parallelism to process and store large volumes of data, up to exabytes in a single table, while keeping query latencies almost unchanged.
Data protection.
Amazon Timestream resources can be
backed-up using either on-demand backups or scheduled backups.
On-demand backups are one-time backups
that you can initiate through the AWS console or through AWS Backup.
On-demand backups are useful when you
want to create a backup prior to making a code change to your application that might require you to revert to an earlier point in time.
Scheduled backups are recurring backups
that you can configure using AWS Backup policies at desired frequencies, such as hourly, daily, or weekly.
Scheduled backups are useful when you
want to create ongoing backups of your data to meet promised RPO, recovery point objectives, and RTO, recovery time objectives.
Additional Amazon Timestream features
Data ingestion.
Amazon Timestream allows you to collect
time-series data from various sources such as connected devices, IT systems, and industrial equipment.
You can send time-series data to
Timestream by using data collection services such as AWS IoT Core, Amazon Kinesis Data Analytics for Apache Flink, and Telegraf, or through the AWS SDKs.
Before sending data to Amazon Timestream
you must create a database and a table using the AWS Management Console or the Timestream SDKs.
Amazon Timestream automatically detects
the schema based on the measures and dimensions of the data points sent to your tables.
Data storage.
Amazon Timestream, uniquely stores
time-series data by using its timestamp
It then organizes that data, across time,
based on its dimensional attributes.
Amazon timestream allows you to automate
the data lifecycle by configuring data retention policies to move data from memory to the magnetic store as the data reaches the configured age.