Amazon DynamoDB Queries - Features.
Limiting the number of items in the results set.
You can limit the number of items in the results set
by setting the limit parameter
to the maximum number of items that you want.
For example,
suppose that you query a table with a limit
value of four and without a filter expression.
The query result contains
the first four items from the table
that match the key condition expression from the request.
Now suppose that you had a filter expression to the query. In this case,
DynamoDB applies the filter expression to the four items that were returned,
discarding those that do not match.
The final query result contains four items or fewer
depending on the number of items that were filtered.
Counting the items and the results.
The query response contains the following elements, "ScannedCount" and "Count."
"ScannedCount" is the number of matching items
to the key condition expression before the filter expression,
if present, was applied.
"Count" is the number of items in the response result.
If you used a filter in the request,
then "Count" is the number of items returned after the filter was applied.
If the size of the query results set is larger than one megabyte,
"ScannedCount" and "Count" represent only a partial count of the total items.
You need to perform multiple query operations to retrieve all the results.
Capacity units consumed by query.
If you query a table,
DynamoDB consumes read capacity units
from the table's provisioned read capacity.
If you query a global secondary index, or GSI,
DynamoDB consumes read capacity units
from the index's provisioned read capacity.
In the case of a local secondary index, or LSI,
DynamoDB consumes read capacity units
from the base table's provisioned read capacity.
DynamoDB calculates the number of read capacity units consumed based on item size,
not on the amount of data that is returned to an application.
Read consistency for query.
A query operation performs eventually consistent reads by default.
This means that the query results might not reflect latest changes
due to recently completed put item or update item operations.
If you require strongly consistent reads,
set the ConsistentRead parameter to true in the query request.
Paginating query results.
With pagination,
the query results are divided into pages of data
that are one megabyte in size or less.
An application can process the first page of results, then the second page, and so on.
To determine whether there are more results,
you need to query with the debug mode
in order to examine the low-level query result,
and check if the result contains the LastEvaluatedKey element.
In this example,
the query also limits the number of items per page using the page-size parameter.
The query result contains information in the LastEvaluatedKey.
This indicates that there are more results data available for the operation.
To retrieve the next page of information,
you will need to set the ExclusiveStartKey value to the LastEvaluatedKey value,
and query again until the absence of the LastEvaluatedKey in the query result.
When there is no LastEvaluatedKey, you have retrieved the final page of results.