Amazon CodeWhisperer Overview
Amazon CodeWhisperer is a general purpose,
machine learning-powered code generator, that provides you with code recommendations in real time.
As you write code, CodeWhisperer
automatically generates suggestions based on your existing code and comments.
Your personalized recommendations can
vary, in size and scope, ranging from a single line comment to fully formed functions.
CodeWhisperer can also scan your code to
highlight, and define security issues.
Features
Get more done faster
CodeWhisperer is trained on billions of
lines of code and can generate full function code suggestions.
Bypass time-consuming coding tasks and
accelerate building with unfamiliar APIs.
Code with confidence
CodeWhisperer can flag or filter code
suggestions that resemble open source training data.
Get the associated open source project’s
repository URL and license so that you can more quickly review them, and add attribution.
Enhance code security
Scan your code to detect hard-to-find
vulnerabilities, and get code suggestions to remediate them immediately.
Align to best practices for tackling
security vulnerabilities, such as those outlined by Open Worldwide Application Security Project.
Security scans
Run Security Scan performs a security scan
on currently an active file and its dependent files in the IDE editor.
After the scan is finished, security
issues in the scanned files are highlighted in the Problems panel in the IDE editor.
CodeWhisperer's security scan is
integrated with Amazon CodeGuru.
CodeGuru does multiple layers of filtering
before scanning code to ensure that you can focus on the most critical issues.
View code references
CodeWhisperer learns, in part, from open
source projects. Sometimes, a suggestion it's giving you might be similar to a specific piece of training data.
You can view references to code
recommendations that are similar to training data.
Turn code references off and on
With the reference log, you can view
references to code recommendations.
You can also update and edit code
recommendations suggested by CodeWhisperer.
In some cases, you can, at the enterprise
level, opt out of receiving code recommendations.
IDEs supported by Amazon CodeWhisperer
CodeWhisperer can be used in the following
integrated development environments - Visual Studio Code, Amazon Sagemaker Studio, JetBrains, and JupyterLab.
CodeWhisperer runs in AWS Cloud9, an IDE
offered by AWS as a service.
You need an AWS account to use it, and you
use it inside your web browser.
CodeWhisperer is integrated in AWS Lambda,
an AWS Compute service.
You need an AWS account to use it, and
you use it on the AWS Management console.
You can use CodeWhisperer to help you
write those functions.
Language support in Amazon CodeWhisperer
CodeWhisperer fits the way that you work.
CodeWhisperer supports code generation for
15 programming languages.
The accuracy and quality of the code
generation for a programming language depends on the size and quality of the training data.
In terms of the quality of the training
data, the programming languages with the most support include Java, Python, JavaScript, and C#.