Amazon DynamoDB Overview
Amazon DynamoDB is a key value and
document database.
It delivers single-digit millisecond
performance at any scale.
It's a fully managed, multi-region,
multi-active, durable database with built-in security, backup and restore, and in-memory caching for internet-scale applications.
DynamoDB can handle more than 10 trillion
requests per day and can support peaks of more than 20 million requests per second.
Here are the key benefits.
Performance at scale.
DynamoDB is a key-value and document
database that can support tables of virtually any size with horizontal scaling.
Since DynamoDB is both a key value and
document data models, it enables flexible schema, which allows you to adapt to your business requirement change easily.
For use cases that require even faster
access with microsecond latency, DynamoDB Accelerator, or DAX provides a fully managed-in-memory cache.
Using DAX, you can improve the read
performance of your DynamoDB tables by up to 10 times.
The time required for reads reduces from
milliseconds to microseconds, even at millions of requests per second.
DynamoDB Global Tables replicate your data
across multiple AWS regions to give you fast, local access to data for your globally distributed applications.
DynamoDB Streams capture a time-ordered
sequence of item-level modifications in any DynamoDB table and store this information in a log for up to 24 hours.
DynamoDB provides both provisioned and
on-demand capacity modes.
Tables using Provisioned Capacity mode
require you to set Read and Write Capacity.
For workloads that are less predictable,
On-Demand Capacity Mode takes care of managing capacity for you, and you only pay for what you consume.
With the two capacity modes, you can
optimize costs by specifying capacity per workload, or paying for only the resources you consume.
For tables using on-demand capacity mode,
DynamoDB instantly accommodates your workloads as they ramp up or down to any previously reached traffic level.
For tables using provisioned capacity,
DynamoDB delivers automatic scaling of throughput and storage.
If your application traffic grows,
DynamoDB increases throughput to accommodate the load. If your application traffic shrinks, DynamoDB scales down, so that you pay less for unused capacity.
DynamoDB integrates with AWS Lambda to
provide triggers.
With Triggers, you can build applications
that react to data modifications in DynamoDB tables.
The Lambda function can perform any
actions you specify, such as sending a notification or initiating a workflow.
Encryption at rest.
DynamoDB encrypts all data by default.
Encryption at rest enhances the security
of your data by using encryption keys stored in AWS Key Management Service.
ACID Transactions
It provides native server-side support for
transactions, simplifying the developer experience of making coordinated, all-or-nothing changes to multiple items both within and across tables.
Point-In-Time Recovery, or PITR, helps
protect your DynamoDB tables from accidental write or delete operations.
PITR provides continuous backups of your
DynamoDB table data.
You can recover to any point in time up to
the second, during the preceding 35 days with no downtime.
On Demand Backup and Restore
You can create full backups of hundreds of
terabytes of data instantly with no performance impact to your tables.
The archived data can help you meet your
corporate and governmental regulatory requirements.
DynamoDB is also backed by a service level
agreement for guaranteed availability.