Amazon SNS Overview.
Amazon Simple Notification Service, or Amazon SNS,
is a highly available, durable, secure,
fully managed publish-and-subscribe messaging service
that enables you to decouple microservices,
distributed systems, and serverless applications.
Amazon SNS provides topics for high-throughput push-based, many-to-many messaging.
Using Amazon SNS topics,
your publisher systems can fan out messages to a large number
of subscriber endpoints for parallel processing, including Amazon SQS queues,
AWS Lambda functions, and HTTPS webhooks.
Additionally,
SNS can be used to fan out notifications to end users using mobile push, SMS, and email.
Let's review some of the benefits of Amazon SNS.
Amazon SNS uses cross-Availability Zone message storage
to provide high message durability. Running within Amazon's proven
network infrastructure and data centers,
Amazon SNS topics are available whenever your applications need them.
All messages published to Amazon SNS are stored
redundantly across multiple geographically separated servers and data centers.
Amazon SNS reliably delivers messages to all supported AWS endpoints,
such as Amazon SQS queues and AWS Lambda functions.
In case the subscribed endpoint isn't available,
Amazon SNS executes message delivery retry policies
and can also move messages to dead-letter queues.
Amazon SNS
helps you simplify your publisher-subscriber messaging architecture
by offloading the message-filtering logic from your subscriber systems
and message-routing logic from your publisher systems.
With Amazon SNS message filtering,
subscribing endpoints receive only the messages of interest
instead of all messages published to the topic.
Amazon CloudWatch gives visibility into your filtering activity,
and AWS CloudFormation enables you to deploy subscription
filter policies in an automated and secure manner.
Amazon SNS leverages the proven AWS Cloud
to dynamically scale with your application.
Amazon SNS is a fully managed service,
taking care of the heavy lifting related to capacity planning, provisioning,
monitoring, and patching. The service is designed to handle high-throughput,
bursty traffic patterns.
Moreover, there is no up-front cost and no need to acquire, install,
configure, or upgrade messaging software.
Amazon SNS topic owners can keep sensitive data secure by setting topic
policies that restrict who can publish and subscribe to a topic.
Amazon SNS also ensures that data is encrypted in transit
by applying Amazon ATS certificates to support its HTTPS API
and can also encrypt data at rest by using AWS KMS keys.
Additionally, using AWS PrivateLink,
you can privately publish messages to Amazon SNS topics from
your Amazon VPC subnets without traversing the public internet.
Amazon SNS can also support use cases in regulated markets
and is in scope with compliance programs, including FIPS, HIPAA, and FedRAMP.