Amazon Elastic Block Store Overview.
Amazon Elastic Block Store, or Amazon EBS,
is a service that provides block-level storage volumes
for use with Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud, or
EC2, instances.
EBS volumes behave like raw, unformatted block devices in the cloud.
You can mount EBS volumes as a device on your EC2 instance.
Each EBS volume can be attached to only one instance at a time,
but multiple volumes of EBS can be on the same instance.
Since EBS volumes are mounted to the instances,
they can provide single-digit millisecond latency,
which is extremely low latency between where the data is stored
and where it might be used on the instance.
EBS volumes are designed for both
throughput- and transaction-intensive workloads at any scale.
Amazon EBS offers data persistence.
All the data on the attached EBS volume remains available
even after you stop or terminate an Amazon EC2 instance.
Amazon EBS provides two major storage volume types.
Solid-state drive, or SSD-backed storage, and hard disk drive, or HDD-backed storage.
SSD-backed storage is optimized for transactional workloads, which
involve frequent read/write operations with small I/O size.
Some use case examples include databases and boot volumes.
SSD-backed volumes include the highest-performance
provisioned IOPS SSD, io2 and io1,
for latency-sensitive transactional workloads.
General-purpose SSD volumes, gp3 and gp2,
balance price and performance for a wide variety of transactional data.
gp3 volumes enable customers
to provision performance independent of storage capacity.
The dominant performance for SSD-backed volumes depends primarily on IOPS (input/output operations per sec).
HDD-backed storage is for throughput-intensive workloads such as MapReduce,
data warehouse, and log processing.
HDD-backed volumes include throughput-optimized HDD,
st1, for frequently accessed throughput-intensive workloads.
The lowest cost Cold HDD, sc1, is for less frequently accessed data.
Dominant performance for HDD-backed volumes depends primarily
on throughput measured in megabytes per second.