Amazon Elastic Block Store (Amazon EBS) Benefits.
Here are the key benefits. Performance for any workload.
EBS volumes are performant for your most demanding
workloads, including mission-critical applications such as SAP,
Oracle, and Microsoft products.
Relational and non-relational databases,
enterprise applications, containerized applications,
big data analytics engines,
file systems, and media workflows are also widely deployed on Amazon EBS.
You can choose from different volume types
to balance optimal price and performance.
Highly available and durable. Designed for mission-critical systems,
EBS volumes are automatically replicated within an
Availability Zone, or AZ, and offer 99.999% availability.
EBS offers a high-durability volume io2
for customers that need 99.999% durability,
especially for their business-critical applications.
Since EBS volumes are for persistent data, it is important to back up the data.
EBS Snapshot with Amazon Lifecycle Manager, or DLM,
provides a simple and robust backup
solution to protect your data and can be used to enable disaster recovery.
Cost-effective. EBS offers different volumes
at various price points and performance benchmarks. Options
range from highly cost-effective dollar-per-gigabyte
volumes to high-performance volumes with high IOPS
and high throughput designed for mission-critical workloads.
This enables you to optimize costs and invest in
a precise level of storage for your application needs.
Additionally, Amazon EBS snapshots are stored incrementally,
which means you are billed only for the changed blocks stored and save storage cost.
Easy to use. Amazon EBS volumes are easy to create, use, encrypt, and protect.
Elastic volumes is a feature that allows you to easily adapt
your storage volumes as the needs of your applications change.
You can also easily create backups of your volume using EBS Snapshot,
and easily automate snapshot management using Data Lifecycle Manager, or DLM,
without any additional overhead or cost.
Virtually unlimited scale.
You can build applications that require as little as a single
gigabyte of storage or scale up to petabytes of data -
all in just a few clicks.
Snapshots can be used to quickly restore new
volumes, enabling rapid scale. Secure. Access to Amazon EBS volumes
is integrated with AWS Identity and Access Management, or AWS IAM,
which enables access control to your Amazon EBS volumes.
EBS is built to be secure for data compliance.
Newly created EBS volumes can be encrypted by
default with a single setting in your account.
EBS volumes support encryption of data at rest,
data in transit, and all volume backups.
EBS encryption is supported by all volume types,
includes built-in key management infrastructure,
and has zero impact on performance.