Amazon EMR Overview.
Amazon EMR is a managed cluster resource that helps you run big data frameworks,
such as Apache Hadoop and Apache Spark,
on AWS to process vast amounts of data
for analytics purposes and business-intelligence workloads.
With Amazon EMR,
you can also transform and move large amounts of data into and out of other
AWS datastores and databases,
such as Amazon Simple Storage Service, or Amazon S3,
and Amazon DynamoDB.
Amazon EMR consists of a cluster made up of Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud,
or Amazon EC2, instances called nodes.
Each node contains different software components based on the role of the node.
The primary node manages the cluster by distributing tasks to other nodes.
The primary node also monitors the status of the tasks.
A core node runs tasks and stores the data on the cluster's file system.
A task node only runs tasks and does not store data.
These nodes are optional.
Benefits and features.
User-friendly.
You can launch an Amazon EMR cluster in minutes.
You don't need to worry about infrastructure provisioning, cluster setup,
configuration, or tuning.
And you can let your Amazon EMR cluster automatically manage
the compute resources to meet your usage and performance needs.
Open-source applications.
With version releases on Amazon EMR,
you can quickly select and use the latest
open-source projects on your Amazon EMR cluster,
including applications in the Apache Spark and Hadoop ecosystems.
Low cost.
Some of the features that make Amazon EMR low cost include low pricing per second,
Amazon EC2 spot integration,
Amazon EC2 reserved-instance integration,
and Amazon S3 integration.
Use cases. Perform big data analytics.
Run large-scale data processing and what-if analysis using statistical
algorithms and predictive models to uncover hidden patterns and market trends.
Process real-time data streams.
Analyze events from streaming data sources in real time
to create fault-tolerant streaming data pipelines.
Accelerate data science and ML adoption.
Analyze data using open-source machine learning frameworks,
such as Apache Spark MLlib, TensorFlow,
and Apache MXNet.
Connect to Amazon Sagemaker Studio for large-scale model training,
analysis, and reporting.