Amazon Elastic Load Balancing (ELB) Overview.
Elastic Load Balancing, or ELB,
automatically distributes incoming application traffic across multiple targets,
such as Amazon EC2 instances, containers,
IP addresses, Lambda functions, and virtual appliances.
ELB automatically scales your load balancer
as your incoming traffic changes over time.
Elastic Load Balancing is a regional service.
It can handle the varying load of your application traffic
in a single Availability Zone or across multiple Availability Zones.
This increases the availability and fault tolerance of your applications.
ELB can be internet- or internal-facing.
Internet-facing load balancers can route requests from clients over the internet.
On the other hand,
internal load balancers can only route requests
from clients with access to the VPC
for the load balancer.
You can figure your load balancer to accept
incoming traffic by specifying one or more listeners.
A listener is a process that checks for connection requests using the protocol
and port that you configure and forwards requests to a target group.
Each target group routes requests to one or more registered targets,
such as EC2 instances.
The rules that you define for a listener
determine how the load balancer routes requests to its registered targets.
ELB monitors the health of the targets
and routes traffic only to the healthy targets.
You can also offload the work of encryption and decryption
to your load balancer so that your compute resources can focus on their main work.
Elastic Load Balancing offers four types of load balancers
that all feature the high availability,
automatic scaling,
and robust security necessary to make your applications fault-tolerant.
Now, let's look at each of these load balancers.
Application Load Balancer
functions at the application-level layer 7.
It is best suited for load balancing of HTTP,
HTTPS, and gRPC traffic and provides advanced request routing
targeted at the delivery of modern application architectures,
including microservices and containers.
Application Load Balancer also routes traffic to targets within
Amazon VPC based on the content of the request.
Network Load Balancer functions at the connection-level layer 4.
It is best suited for load balancing of TCP,
UDP, and TLS traffic where extreme performance is required.
Network Load Balancer can also route traffic to targets within Amazon VPC ,
and is capable of handling millions of requests per second
while maintaining ultralow latencies.
It supports static IP addresses.
You can also assign one elastic IP address per subnet enabled for the load balancer.
Gateway Load Balancer
functions at the network level as layer-3 gateway
and a layer-4 load balancer.
It listens for all IP packets across all ports.
Gateway Load Balancer makes it easy to deploy, scale,
and run third-party virtual networking appliances,
such as firewalls, intrusion detection and prevention
systems, and deep packet inspection systems.
It gives you one gateway
for distributing traffic across multiple virtual appliances.
Gateway Load Balancer also provides autoscaling
for fleets of third-party appliances.
It is transparent to source and destination of traffic.
They are well-suited for working with third-party appliances for security,
network analytics, and other use cases.
Classic Load Balancer functions at both layer-4 connection level
and layer-7 request or application level.
It supports TCP, SSL, TLS, HTTP, and HTTPS traffic.
It is intended for applications that were built within the EC2-Classic network.
With Elastic Load Balancing,
you can select the appropriate load balancer based on your application needs.