Amazon Simple Storage Service (Amazon S3) Access Management.
By default,
all Amazon S3 resources, such as buckets and objects, are private.
Only the resource owner,
an AWS account that created it, can access the resource.
The resource owner can optionally grant access
permissions to others by writing an access policy.
Amazon S3 offers access policy options that can be
broadly categorized as resource-based policies and user policies.
Resource-based policies are access policies that you attach
to your resources such as buckets and objects.
Bucket policies and access control lists, or ACLs,
are resource-based policies.
You can also authenticate certain types of data access using
query-string authentication to grant temporary access to others
with time-limited URLs.
User policies are access policies that you attach to users.
Access can be granted to users using AWS IAM policies.
You may choose to use resource-based policies,
user policies, or some combination of these to manage permissions
to your Amazon S3 resources.
Access Control List is a legacy access control mechanism.
As a general rule,
AWS recommends using S3 bucket policies or IAM policies for access control.
When Amazon S3 receives a request,
it must evaluate all the access policies to
determine whether to authorize or deny the request.
First, let's look at resource-based policies.
Access control lists.
Each bucket and object has an access control list,
an ACL associated with it.
Access control lists use Amazon S3-specific XML schema.
It defines which AWS accounts or groups
are granted access and the type of access they have.
When you create a bucket or an object, Amazon S3 creates a default ACL
that grants the resource owner full control over the resource.
You can use access control lists to grant
basic read/write permissions to other AWS accounts.
A Bucket policy, written in JSON, is attached to an S3 bucket.
It provides access permissions to the S3 bucket and all objects in it.
Here is an example of an S3 bucket policy.
This S3 bucket policy allows the principal,
the root account, and the IAM user Alice
under that account to perform any S3 operation.
The wildcard asterisk character after the S3 in the action statement
indicates that all S3 operations are allowed.
Particularly, you can perform S3 operations
only on specific resources as shown in
the resource statement.
In this case, only the S3 bucket with name
my_bucket and all objects in it are allowed.
As you can see, you can use the slash and asterisk
after the bucket name to indicate all objects in the bucket.
User policies control who has access to your Amazon S3 resources
and is written in JSON.
You can use AWS Identity and Access Management, or AWS IAM,
to create users, groups, and roles in your account
and attach access policies to grant them access to Amazon S3.
Let's look at an IAM policy example.
Unlike bucket policies,
IAM policy does not require a principal
element because the principal is, by default,
the entity that the IAM policy is attached to.
The first part of the policy specifies bucket-level permissions.
It allows the ListBucket action so that applications
can list all objects in the test bucket.
The second part specifies object-level permissions.
It allows PutObject,
GetObject, and DeleteObject actions so that applications can write,
read, and delete any objects in the test bucket.