Amazon Simple Queue Service (SQS) Overview.
Amazon Simple Queue Service, or SQS,
is a fully managed message queuing service.
SQS lets you decouple application components
and scale microservices,
distributed systems, and serverless applications.
Using SQS,
you can send, store, and receive messages between
software components at any volume,
without losing messages
or requiring other services to be available.
You can get started with SQS in minutes using the
AWS Console Command Line Interface or SDK of your choice
and three simple commands.
SQS offers two types of message queues.
Standard queues offer maximum throughput,
best-effort ordering, and at-least-once delivery.
SQS FIFO queues are designed to guarantee that messages are
processed exactly once in the exact order that they are sent.
Here are the key benefits.
Amazon SQS eliminates all your administrative overhead.
AWS manages all ongoing operations
and underlying infrastructure needed to provide
a highly available and scalable message queuing service.
With SQS,
there is no up-front cost, no need to acquire,
install, and configure messaging software and no time-consuming
build-out and maintenance of supporting infrastructure.
Amazon SQS reliably delivers messages for you.
SQS lets you decouple application components so
that they run it and fail independently,
increasing the overall fault tolerance of the system.
Multiple copies of every message are stored redundantly across multiple
Availability Zones so that they are available whenever needed.
You can use Amazon SQS to keep sensitive data secure.
You can use Amazon SQS to exchange sensitive
data between applications using server-side encryption, or SSE,
to encrypt each message body.
Amazon SQS-SSE integration with AWS Key Management Service, or KMS,
allows you to centrally manage the keys that protect SQS messages,
along with keys that protect your other AWS resources.
AWS KMS logs every use of your encryption keys to AWS CloudTrail
to help meet your regulatory and compliance needs.
Amazon SQS leverages the AWS Cloud to scale
elastically and cost-effectively based on demand.
You don't have to worry about capacity planning and pre-provisioning.
There's no limit to the number of messages per queue. Standard queues provide
nearly unlimited throughput.
Costs are based on usage,
which provides significant cost savings versus the
always-on model of self-managed messaging middleware.
Let's look at some of the SQS functionalities.
You can create unlimited Amazon SQS queues with
an unlimited number of messages in any region.
In terms of payload size, message payloads can contain up to
256 kilobytes of text in any format.
Each 64 kilobytes chunk of payload is billed as one request.
Batch operation is also available.
You can send, receive, or delete messages in
batches of up to 10 messages or 256 kilobytes.
Messages can be retained in queues
for up to 14 days.
SQS can send and read messages simultaneously.
Message locking.
When a message is received, it becomes locked while being processed.
The locked message keeps other computers
from processing the message simultaneously.
When processing is completed, you can delete the message from the queue.
If the message processing fails,
the lock will expire, and the message will be available again.
Long polling. When your queue is empty,
long-poll requests wait up to 20 seconds for the next message to arrive.
This reduces extraneous polling to minimize cost while
receiving new messages as quickly as possible.
Dead Letter Queues,or DLQs.
Dead Letter Queue is a queue of messages that could not be processed.
It receives messages after a maximum number
of processing attempts has been reached.
DLQs must be of the same type as the source queue (standard or FIFO).
Queue sharing.
You can securely share Amazon SQS queues
anonymously or with specific AWS accounts.
Queue sharing can also be restricted by IP address and time of day.
In summary,
Amazon SQS is a fully managed message queuing service
that provides many benefits and features
over building your own software for managing message queues.