Amazon Aurora Serverless Overview.
Unpredictable workloads are challenging.
Manually managing database capacity can take up valuable time
and can lead to inefficient use of database resources.
If you overprovision, you pay for unused resources.
If you underprovision, you risk a bad user experience.
Amazon Aurora Serverless is an on-demand autoscaling configuration for
Amazon Aurora, MySQL-compatible and
PostgresSQL-compatible relational database.
It is ideal for infrequent, intermittent, or unpredictable workloads.
Why Aurora Serverless? Here are the key benefits.
First, it is simple. It is a serverless database.
You do not need to manage any database instances and capacity.
The database will automatically start up, shut down,
and scale capacity up or down based on your application's needs.
Aurora Serverless is scalable.
Compute and memory capacity can seamlessly scale as
needed with no disruption to client connections.
Cost-effective.
You pay only for the database resources you consume on a per-second basis,
while instance is active. You don't pay for the database
instance when it is not running.
Highly available. Amazon Aurora Serverless is
built on distributed fault-tolerant, self-healing
Aurora storage with six-way replication to protect against data loss.
Data blocks and disks are continuously
scanned for errors and repaired automatically.
Your database volume is replicated six ways across three Availability Zones.
What are the common use cases? Infrequently used applications.
You have an application that is only used for
a few minutes several times per day or week,
such as a low-volume blog site. With Aurora Serverless,
you only pay for the database resources you consume.
New applications.
You are deploying a new application and are unsure which instance size you need.
Unpredictable workloads.
You're running workloads where there is database usage throughout the day
and also peaks of activity that are hard to predict,
for example, a traffic site that might see a surge of activity when it starts raining.
Development and test databases.
Your software development and QA teams are using databases during work hours
but don't need them on nights or weekends.
With Aurora Serverless,
your database automatically shuts down when not in use and starts
up much more quickly when work starts the next day.
Multitenant applications.
You have a web-based application with a database for each of
your customers. Aurora manages individual database capacity for you,
saving you valuable time.