Amazon Comprehend Medical
Amazon Comprehend Medical is a fully
managed
Natural Language Processing, NLP, Service.
that is HIPAA certified.
Comprehend Medical, uses machine learning,
ML,
and has being pre-trained to understand and
extract
unstructured clinical data
using medical entity detection.
An entity is a textual reference to
medical information.
such as a medical condition,
medications,
or Protected Health Information, PHI.
Amazon Comprehend Medical can be accessed
through a simple API call.
No ML experience is required.
No complicated rules to write
and no need to do your own model training.
Comprehend medical benefits.
Application Enhancement.
Use Comprehend Medical APIs
to build text analysis capabilities
into your medical applications
for powerful and accurate
Natural Language Processing.
Accurate, scalable, and low-cost.
Amazon Comprehend Medical
uses deep learning technology
to accurately perform text analysis.
Amazon Comprehend Medical
scales automatically,
allowing you to detect information
from hundreds of documents at a time.
This allows you to gain insights into
patient health faster
and improve patient outcomes.
with Amazon Comprehend Medical
you only pay for the API calls that you
make,
and as you use it more, you pay less per
API call.
AWS Service Integration.
Amazon Comprehend Medical is designed
to work seamlessly with other AWS
services
such as Amazon Simple Storage Service,
Amazon S3,
and AWS Lambda,
or use Amazon Transcribe along with
Comprehend Medical
to convert patient narratives into medical
ontology text.
Comprehend medical features
Fully managed.
Amazon Comprehend Medical is a fully
managed service.
So there is no need to provision your own
servers.
Comprehend Medical is maintained by Amazon
and is continuously trained.
So you do not have to build,
train,
or deploy your own models.
You pay only for medical texts that you
analyze,
and there are no minimum fees or upfront
commitments.
Detect PHI.
Amazon Comprehend Medical
can detect PHI,
and searching for PHI uses safe harbor
guidelines.
The Detect PHI feature
allows you to remove or mask PHI
so the data can be used for other
purposes
such as medical research.
Medical ontology linking.
The Comprehend Medical APIs
can identify medical information
and link them to the codes and concepts
in medical ontology standards such as
SNOMED CT.
Medical conditions
are also linked to ICD-10-CM codes.
For example,
a patient complaining of headache symptoms
would automatically
be mapped to the A51.9 code.
Medical ontology features of Comprehend
Medical
enables the sharing of electronic health
records.