Amazon AppStream 2.0 Overview
Amazon AppStream 2.0 is a fully managed
application streaming service that provides users with instant access to their desktop applications from anywhere.
AppStream 2.0 manages the AWS resources
required to host and run your applications, scales automatically, and provides access to your users on demand.
With AppStream 2.0, you can quickly add
your existing desktop applications to AWS and enable your users to instantly stream them.
Windows users can use either the AppStream
2.0 client or an HTML5-capable web browser for application streaming.
Key Benefits
Streamline SaaS administration
With Amazon AppStream 2.0, applications
are streamed to your users' web browser.
Install your desktop applications on
AppStream 2.0 as you would on any computer. Then start streaming them to your users.
Scale without infrastructure
As you stream applications to users, auto
scaling allows AppStream 2.0 to quickly adapt to usage patterns.
You can scale your applications to users
across the globe without obtaining, deploying, and managing any infrastructure.
Reduce time to market
AppStream 2.0 can accelerate the SaaS
transformation for your Windows or Linux desktop applications.
With AppStream 2.0, you can deliver
applications from AWS to an HTML5 browser without rewriting or refactoring your applications, which can help shorten your time to market.
Key Features
Image builders
Amazon AppStream 2.0 uses Amazon Elastic
Compute Cloud, or Amazon EC2, instances to stream applications.
You launch EC2 instances from base images,
called image builders, which AppStream 2.0 provides.
To create your own custom image, you
connect to an image builder instance, install and configure your applications for streaming, and then create your image by creating a snapshot of the image builder instance.
Fleets and stacks
With AppStream 2.0, you create fleet
instances and stacks as part of the process of streaming applications.
A fleet consists of streaming instances
that run the image that you specify.
A stack consists of an associated fleet,
user access policies, and storage configurations.
User authentication
AppStream 2.0 supports identity federation
to AppStream 2.0 stacks through SAML 2.0.
Additionally, you can connect your
AppStream 2.0 Windows fleets and image builders to domains in Microsoft Active Directory.
AppStream 2.0 user pools provide a
streamlined way to manage access to applications for your users through a persistent portal for each AWS Region.