Amazon QuickSight
Introduction
Amazon QuickSight is a cloud-scale
business intelligence service that you can use to deliver easy-to-understand insights to the people who you work with, wherever they are.
In a single data dashboard, QuickSight can
include data from AWS, third-party sources,
big data sources, spreadsheets,
software-as-a-service sources, business-to-business sources, and more.
A dashboard is the published version of an
analysis that you can share with other users of QuickSight for reporting purposes.
A data analysis is the basic workspace for
creating data visualizations, which are graphical representations of your data.
QuickSight uses a superfast parallel
in-memory calculation engine, called SPICE.
The storage and processing capacity
available in SPICE speeds up the analytical queries that you run against your imported data.
By using SPICE, you save time because you
don't need to retrieve the data every time you change an analysis, or update a visual.
Amazon QuickSight Key Features
Use QuickSight Q to provide business
intelligence for everyone.
With QuickSight Q, you can ask
conversational questions of your data,
and use Q's machine learning-powered
engine to receive relevant visualizations
without the time-consuming data
preparation from authors and admins.
Use machine learning insights to perform
advanced analytics.
You can use AWS expertise in machine
learning to discover hidden insights from your data,
perform accurate forecasting and what-if
analysis,
or add easy-to-understand natural language
narratives to dashboards.
Embed analytics to differentiate your
applications.
You can embed interactive visualizations
and dashboards,
sophisticated dashboard authoring,
or natural language query capabilities in
your applications,
which can differentiate user experience
and unlock new monetization opportunities.
Amazon QuickSight Benefits
Build Customizable Dashboards
With QuickSight, you can build
pixel-perfect dashboards that are use-case specific.
You can also deliver personalized email
reports and alerts for end-users and provide on-the-go access through iOS and Android on the QuickSight mobile app.
Native AWS Service Integration
QuickSight integrates natively with other
AWS services, such as Amazon Redshift, Snowflake, Exasol, Amazon Relational Database Service, and many others.
You can use AWS Identity and Access
Management to grant QuickSight permissions for Amazon S3 and Amazon Athena with fine-grained access control.
QuickSight can also integrate with Amazon
SageMaker to create sophisticated machine learning models without the need for complex data pipelines.
Serverless Pay-by-Usage Design
QuickSight is completely serverless and
will automatically scale to hundreds of thousands of users with built-in high availability.
With QuickSight, you only pay for what you
use,
which means no more over-provisioning for
peak usage or requirements for thousands of end-user licenses.