Amazon Relational Database Service (RDS) Features - Security.
Here are the key features.
Network isolation.
AWS recommends that you run your database instances
in a virtual private cloud, or VPC,
which allows you to isolate your database in your virtual network.
VPC enables you to run a DB instance within a private subnet,
making it secure from direct public routes on the internet.
You can control network access to your DB instances in VPC
using security groups at the instance level
and network ACLs in the subnet level.
VPC traffic is connected to your on-premises IT infrastructure
using industry-standard encrypted IPsec VPNs
and can be further inspected
by your on-premises security infrastructure,
including network firewalls and intrusion detection systems.
Resource-level permissions.
Amazon RDS is integrated with AWS Identity and Access Management, or AWS IAM.
It provides you the ability to control the actions
that your AWS IAM users and groups can take on specific Amazon RDS resources,
from database instances through snapshots,
parameter groups, and option groups.
You can also tag your Amazon RDS resources
and control the actions that your IAM users and groups
can take on groups of resources
that have the same tag and associated value.
For example,
you can configure your IAM rules
to ensure developers are able to modify development database instances,
but only database administrators
can make changes to production database instances.
Encryption at rest and in transit.
Amazon RDS allows you to encrypt your databases
using keys you manage through AWS Key Management Service, or AWS KMS.
The database uses a customer master key stored in AWS KMS
to encrypt the data keys which encrypt the data at rest in the database.
Its automated backups, read replicas, and snapshots are also encrypted.
Amazon RDS supports transparent data encryptio, or TDE, and SQL Server, and Oracle.
Transparent data encryption in Oracle is integrated with AWS CloudHSM,
which allows you to securely generate, store,
and manage your cryptographic TDE master encryption keys
in single-tenant hardware security module, or HSM,
appliances within the AWS Cloud.
With TDE, the database software encrypts data before storing it on disk.
In addition, Amazon RDS secures data in transit.
You can use Secure Socket Layer, or SSL, or Transport Layer Security, or TLS,
from your application to encrypt a connection to an RDS DB instance.