Amazon Transcribe Overview.
Amazon Transcribe is a service
that employs machine-learning models
to convert speech audio to text,
allowing you to add it as a feature to any application.
Amazon Transcribe features
allow you to take an audio or video file
and ingest it to produce easy-to-read transcripts,
improve accuracy with language customization,
and filter content to ensure customer privacy.
Common use cases for Amazon Transcribe include
transcribing and analyzing customer-agent calls
and creating subtitles for videos.
Amazon Transcribe Benefits.
Custom Vocabularies.
Amazon Transcribe allows you to
specify a list of words
you want the service to recognize
in your audio input.
Custom vocabularies can be used to
recognize industry-specific terms
that are incorrectly transcribed,
spell out acronyms correctly,
or improve the accuracy
of your transcription output.
PII Redaction.
Amazon Transcribe can help customers
identify and redact
personally identifiable information, or PII,
from transcripts.
An example use case for this
would be call-center agent training
to improve customer satisfaction.
Subtitles.
Amazon Transcribe can be used to create subtitles
for your video files.
Amazon Transcribe supports
WebVTT and SubRip subtitle formats.
You can select one or both formats to
output when setting up your batch video transcription job.
Vocabulary Filtering.
Remove or tag
words you want to eliminate from your transcripts.
Vocabulary filtering helps you filter
for any word you consider offensive
and mask or remove it from your transcript.
Use vocabulary filtering to
generate family-friendly captions of a TV show or
remove proprietary information from
transcripts of confidential discussions.