Amazon EventBridge Overview.
Amazon EventBridge is a serverless,
fully managed, and scalable event bus
that you can use to connect your applications
with data from a variety of sources,
such as an AWS environment,
a SaaS partner service, or one of your applications or services.
Events are represented as JSON objects,
and they all have a similar structure and the same top-level fields.
An event indicates a change in an environment. When EventBridge receives an event,
it applies a rule to rig the event to a target.
Rules are based either on an event pattern or a schedule.
An event pattern defines the event structure in the fields that a rule matches.
A target is a resource or endpoint that EventBridge sends an event to,
such as a function in AWS Lambda,
a task in Amazon Elastic Container Service,
or a topic in Amazon Simple Notification Service.
You can use
AWS Identity and Access Management to control access to EventBridge.
Amazon EventBridge is directly integrated with
AWS services as event sources or targets.
EventBridge also supports integration
with SaaS applications from many providers.
Amazon EventBridge Benefits.
Reliable event delivery.
Amazon EventBridge provides at least one event delivery to targets,
including retry with exponential backoff for up to 24 hours.
Events are stored durably across multiple Availability Zones,
providing additional assurance that your events
will be delivered to their destination.
Build event-driven applications at scale.
An event-driven architecture uses events to invoke and communicate
between decoupled services. By decoupling
your applications into multiple services,
each component operates independently.
EventBridge acts like a connector,
sending data across components.
Using this architecture,
you can build and innovate faster
while increasing the resiliency
and scalability of your application.
This is the end of Amazon EventBridge overview.
Thanks for watching.