Amazon Lookout for Vision Overview
Amazon Lookout for Vision is a machine
learning service that uses computer vision, to spot visual defects in manufactured products accurately, and at scale.
It uses computer vision to identify
missing components in an industrial product, damage to vehicles or structures, irregularities in production lines, and even minuscule defects in silicon wafers—or any other physical item where quality is important, such as a missing capacitor on printed circuit boards.
Benefits
Quickly and efficiently improve processes
You can provide as few as 30 baseline good
images, and Amazon Lookout for Vision can automatically build a custom machine learning model for defect detection
You can then process images from IP
cameras, in batch or in real time, to quickly and accurately identify anomalies, such as dents, cracks, and scratches.
Increase production quality, fast
Lookout for Vision identifies and reports
visual anomalies in a dashboard, so you can take action quickly to stop more defects from occurring—increasing production quality and reducing costs.
Reduce operational costs
Lookout for Vision reports trends in your
visual inspection data, such as identifying processes with the highest defect rate or flagging recent variations in defects.
Using this information, you can determine
whether to schedule maintenance on the process line or reroute production to another machine before costly, unplanned downtime occurs.
Features
Dashboard view
The Amazon Lookout for Vision console
provides a holistic view across all your production lines with an easy-to-use dashboard.
The dashboard shows the projects by most
defects, recent defects, and highest anomaly ratio, so you can quickly identify the production lines and processes that need immediate attention.
Simplified labeling
The Lookout for Vision console provides a
visual interface to label your images quickly by applying a normal or anomaly label to the entire image with a click of a button.
If you organize your images in Amazon
Simple Storage Service, or Amazon S3, into Normal and Anomaly folders, you can use the Auto Labeler feature to automatically label each image when creating a dataset.
Quick evaluation
Evaluate your anomaly detection model’s
performance on your test dataset.
For every image in the test dataset, you
can see a side-by-side comparison of the model’s prediction compared to the label assigned.
You can also review detailed performance
metrics, such as precision and recall metrics, F1 score, and confidence scores.
Trial anomaly detection tasks and feedback
You can instantly run test detection tasks
on additional images to get normal or anomaly predictions using your model.
You can track your predictions, correct
any mistakes, and provide the feedback to retrain newer models to improve anomaly detection accuracy.
Using your trained models at the edge
Your trained models can be deployed on any
NVIDIA Jetson edge appliance or x86 compute platform running Linux with an NVIDIA GPU accelerator.
You can use AWS IoT Greengrass V2 to
deploy and manage your edge-compatible customized models on your fleet of devices.
Manufacturing line integration
You can integrate Lookout for Vision with
your manufacturing lines, and implement automated visual inspection workflows for your use cases with just a few clicks in the Lookout for Vision console, and a few API parameters.