Amazon Kinesis Data Firehose Overview.
Amazon Kinesis Data Firehose, or Amazon Kinesis Firehose,
provides an easy and reliable way to load streaming data
to AWS destinations,
such as data lakes, datastores, and analytics services.
The streaming data can be captured,
transformed, and delivered to
Amazon S3,
Amazon Redshift,
Amazon OpenSearch Service, and
third-party service partners such as Datadog,
New Relic, and Splunk.
It is a fully managed service that automatically scales
to match the throughput of your data
and eliminates the need for ongoing administration.
Amazon Kinesis Firehose allows you to configure batching,
compression, and encryption
of your data streams before loading,
minimizing the amount of storage used
and maximizing security.
You can easily create a Firehose delivery stream
from the AWS Management Console,
configure it with a few clicks,
and start ingesting thousands of data streams
to your AWS destinations.
You can also configure
your data streams to automatically convert
the incoming data to open standard formats,
like Apache Parquet and Apache ORC before the data is delivered.
Amazon Kinesis Firehose Benefits.
Near Real-Time Delivery.
You can specify a batch size or batch
interval to control how quickly data is uploaded
to their cloud destinations.
For example, for new data you can set the
batch interval to 60 seconds, and the service
will return processed data within that time frame.
Additionally, you can specify if the data should be compressed.
This service supports common compression algorithms
including gzip, Hadoop, Zip, and Snappy.
Batching and compressing data
before uploading enables you
to control your data delivery speed.
Integrated Data Transformations.
Amazon Kinesis Firehose is integrated with AWS Lambda
to allow you to transform your streaming data
before it is loaded to their AWS destinations.
The Amazon Kinesis Firehose console allows you to choose and configure
the Lambda function, and it will then
automatically apply that function to every input
record processed.
Amazon Kinesis Firehose provides pre-built Lambda
blueprints that you can use out of the box
for converting common data sources,
such as system logs, to JSON format,
or you can customize and create your own blueprints.
Pay-As-You-Go Pricing.
With Amazon Kinesis Firehose,
you are charged only for the volume of data
transmitted to the AWS destination
as well as data delivery fees to Amazon VPC.
Optional fees may apply for data format conversion.
With Amazon Kinesis Firehose,
you eliminate minimum usage fees or up-front costs.
You don't need staff to operate,
scale, or maintain infrastructure
or custom applications to load
and capture streaming data.