Amazon Relational Database Service (RDS) - Features
Availability and Durability.
Amazon RDS also offers features to enhance availability
and durability for your production workloads. Turned on by default,
the automated backup feature of Amazon RDS
will back up your databases and transaction logs,
and saves them securely in Amazon S3 for a user-specified retention period.
Your automatic backup retention period can be configured to up to 35 days.
Automated backups enables point-in-time recovery for your database instance.
It allows you to restore your database instance to any second
during your retention period, up to the last five minutes.
Database snapshots are user-initiated backups of your instance
stored in Amazon S3 that are kept until you explicitly delete them.
You can create a new instance from a database snapshot whenever you desire.
Although database snapshots serve operationally as full backups,
you're billed only for incremental storage use.
Amazon RDS will automatically replace the compute instance
power in your deployment in the event of a hardware failure.
Amazon RDS Multi-AZ deployments
provide enhanced availability and durability for database instances,
making them a natural fit for production database workloads.
When you provision a Multi-AZ DB instance,
Amazon RDS automatically creates a primary DB instance
and synchronously replicates the data to a standby DB instance
in a different Availability Zone
in the same or different Region.
In case of an infrastructure failure,
Amazon RDS performs an automatic failover to the standby.
The standby DB instance is promoted to become the primary DB instance.
Data is replicated back to a new standby DB instance
to retain high availability. Since the end point for your DB instance
remains the same after a failover,
your application can resume database operations
as soon as the failover is complete.
No manual administrative intervention is needed.