Welcome to an Overview of Amazon SageMaker.
Amazon SageMaker
is a fully managed service
that provides developers and data scientists
with the ability to collect and prepare,
build, train,
and deploy machine-learning models quickly.
Amazon SageMaker
removes the heavy lifting from each step of the machine-learning process
to make it easier to develop high-quality models.
Amazon SageMaker
provides all of the components used for machine learning
in a single toolset,
so models get to production faster
with much less effort
and at a lower cost.
Here are some of the benefits of using Amazon SageMaker.
Make machine learning more accessible.
With Amazon SageMaker,
machine learning becomes more accessible, enabling people to innovate with ML,
through a choice of tools,
an integrated IDE,
and no-code visual interfaces.
Prepare data at scale.
With Amazon SageMaker, you can access, label,
and process large amounts of structured data like tabular data from spreadsheets
and unstructured data like photos, video,
and audio.
Accelerate ML development.
With Amazon SageMaker,
you can reduce training time from hours to minutes
with an optimized infrastructure,
and you can boost productivity
with purpose-built tools.
Amazon SageMaker also enables you to automate
and standardize MLOps practices across your organization,
allowing you to train and deploy models at scale.
Amazon SageMaker can be utilized for specific use cases as well.
With Amazon SageMaker Canvas, business analysts can easily prepare data,
train models,
and generate predictions using a point-and-click interface.
They can then share the results with data scientists
and integrate them into common business intelligence tools.
With Amazon SageMaker Studio Notebook,
data scientists can access data from structured and unstructured data sources,
improve productivity with purpose-built tools
and fully managed Jupyter notebooks with just a few clicks.
And with Amazon SageMaker MLOps,
software developers can build CI/CD pipelines to reduce model management overhead,
automate ML workflows to accelerate data preparation and model building, training,
and experiments.
It can also monitor ML model quality by automatically detecting bias and drift,
and automatically track code datasets and artifacts
at each step of the ML lifecycle.