Amazon Location Services Overview
Amazon Location Service is a fully managed
service that developers can use to add location data to applications without sacrificing data security and user privacy. Amazon Location provides maps from multiple sources, built-in tracking, and geofencing capabilities.
Here are some key benefits
AWS Integration
Amazon Location Service is fully
integrated with services such as AWS CloudTrail, Amazon CloudWatch, Amazon EventBridge, and AWS Identity and Access Management. Amazon Location streamlines your development workflow with data integration, and it fast tracks apps to production with built-in monitoring, security, and compliance features.
Secure and private
With Amazon Location Service, you retain
control of your organization’s data. Amazon Location anonymizes all queries sent to data providers by removing customer metadata and account information. Additionally, sensitive tracking and geofencing location information, such as facility, asset, and personnel locations, does not leave your AWS account at all.
Location functionalities
Using Amazon Location, you can add
location data and functionality to applications, which includes capabilities such as maps, points of interest, geocoding, routing, geofences, and tracking with high-quality data from trusted providers.
Here are some key features
Maps
Amazon Location Service Maps helps you
visualize location information and is the foundation of many location-based service capabilities. Amazon Location provides map tiles of different styles sourced from global location data providers. ESRI, GrabMaps, and HERE.
Routing
Amazon Location Service Routes helps you
find routes and estimate travel time based on up-to-date roadway and lyve traffic information. Build features that allow your application to request the travel time, distance, and directions between any two locations. Calculate the time and distance for a matrix of routes to use in route planning.
Geofencing
Amazon Location Service Geofences helps
you give your application the ability to detect and act when a device enters or exits a deﬁned geographical boundary, known as a geofence. Automatically send an entry or exit event to Amazon EventBridge when a geofence breach is detected so that you can initiate downstream actions, such as sending a notiﬁcation to a target.