Amazon Elastic Container Registry (Amazon ECR) Overview.
Amazon Elastic Container Registry,
or Amazon ECR,
is a fully managed container registry
offering high-performance hosting,
so you can reliably deploy application images
and artifacts anywhere.
You can push container images to Amazon ECR
without installing or scaling infrastructure.
And you can pull images using any management tool.
You can share and download images
securely over HTTPS with automatic encryption
and access controls.
You can access and distribute your images faster,
reduce download times,
and improve availability by using a scalable,
durable architecture.
Features.
Amazon container orchestrator integration.
Amazon ECR is integrated with
Amazon Elastic Container Service, or Amazon ECS,
and Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service, or Amazon EKS,
which means you can store and run
container images for applications with either orchestrator.
OCI and Docker support.
Amazon ECR
supports Open Container Initiative,
or OCI, standards in the Docker registry HTTP API V2.
Therefore you can use Docker CLI commands
or your preferred Docker tools to interact with Amazon ECR
maintaining your existing development workflow.
Public container image and artifact gallery.
You can discover and use container software that
vendors and community developers share publicly in the
Amazon ECR public gallery.
You don't need to use an AWS account
to search or pull a public image.
AWS Marketplace.
Amazon ECR stores containers
that you create in any container software
that you buy through AWS Marketplace.
High availability and durability.
Amazon ECR stores your container images
and artifacts in Amazon Simple Storage Service,
or Amazon S3.
Amazon S3 is designed for eleven 9s of data durability,
because it automatically creates
and stores copies of all Amazon S3 objects across multiple systems.
Access control.
Amazon ECR uses
AWS Identity and Access Management, or IAM,
to control and monitor who
and what resources can access your container images.
Through IAM,
you can define policies to allow users within the same AWS account
or other accounts to access your container images
in private repositories.
Encryption.
You can transfer your container images
to and from Amazon ECR through HTTPS.
Your images are also automatically encrypted at rest
using Amazon S3 server-side encryption.
Third-party integrations.
Amazon ECR
is integrated with third-party developer tools.
You can integrate Amazon ECR
into your continuous integration and delivery process
so you can maintain your existing development workflow.
Pull through cache repositories.
Using pull through cache repositories in Amazon ECR,
you can retrieve, store,
and sync container artifacts stored
in publicly accessible container registries.