Welcome to the overview of Amazon Lex.
Amazon Lex is a fully managed artificial intelligence, or AI,
service with advanced natural language models to design,
build,
test,
and deploy conversational interfaces and applications.
Amazon Lex is an
AWS service for building chatbots for applications using voice and text.
With Amazon Lex, no deep-learning expertise is necessary.
To create a bot,
you just specify the basic conversation flow.
Amazon Lex manages the dialogue and dynamically
adjusts the responses in the conversation.
Amazon Lex also provides integration with
AWS Lambda,
AWS Mobile Hub, Amazon CloudWatch,
Amazon Cognito, and Amazon DynamoDB.
Let's review key features of Amazon Lex. Standard Features.
Security.
Amazon Lex uses
AWS IAM for access and management,
encrypts data at rest using internal
AWS KMS keys, and encrypts data in transit using HTTPS.
Monitoring.
With Amazon CloudWatch, you can get metrics for Amazon Lex operations, and with
AWS CloudTrail,
you can monitor API calls.
Natural conversations.
Amazon Lex provides high-quality
speech recognition and natural language understanding.
Amazon Lex uses the same proven technology that powers Alexa.
Amazon Lex supports context management natively
so you can manage the context directly without the need for custom code.
The Amazon Lex speech recognition engine has been trained on telephony audio
eight-kilohertz sampling rate,
providing increased speech recognition accuracy.
Amazon Lex bots also include the ability for multi-turn conversations.
Build a productivity.
Amazon Lex allows you one-click deployment to multiple platforms and
has in-built powerful lifecycle management capabilities.
The Lex V2-enhanced console makes it easier to build,
deploy, and manage conversational experiences.
With streaming conversation APIs,
you can manage conversation flow directly as you configure the bot.
AWS service integrations.
You can search intent using Amazon Kendra to
find the most accurate answers from unstructured documents and FAQs.
You can use Amazon Polly to convert text input and respond in lifelike speech.
Amazon Lex natively supports integration with
AWS Lambda for additional business logic.
Contact center integrations.
Amazon Lex is natively integrated with Amazon Connect,
AWS's omnichannel cloud contact center.
Amazon Lex can be deployed in Genesys Cloud CX,
a cloud contact center solution,
any session initiation protocol, or SIP, using contact
centers with Amazon Chime SDK, and
AWS Contact Center Intelligence, or CCI,
partners who support Amazon Lex.
Compliance.
Amazon Lex is a HIPAA-eligible service,
It is SOC,
PCI, and ISO compliant.