Amazon Textract Overview.
Amazon Textract is a document analysis service
that detects and extracts printed text,
handwriting, structured data, and tables from images and
and scans of documents without requiring templates or configuration.
Amazon Textract uses
machine-learning models that have been trained on millions of documents,
so virtually any document type you upload is automatically recognized
and processed for text extraction.
Upon extraction,
the server returns a confidence score for each element it identifies,
so that you can evaluate how you want to use the results.
All extracted data
is returned with bounding box coordinates,
which is a rectangular frame
that fully encompasses
each piece of data identified,
so that you
can quickly identify
where a word or number
appears on a document.
You can access these features with
the AWS Management Console,
the AWS Command Line Interface,
or the Amazon Textract API.
Benefits.
Beyond OCR.
Amazon Textract uses optical character recognition
to automatically detect data
in a scan or rendering of a document, such as a legal document or a scan of a book.
Textract then extracts text, relationships,
and structure.
Document processing.
You can quickly automate document processing
and act on the information extracted,
whether you're automating loan processing
or extracting information from invoices
and receipts.
Textract can extract the data
in minutes or hours instead of days.
Application integration.
Amazon Textract simplifies building text detection capabilities
into your applications by using the Amazon Textract text APIs.
You don't need computer vision or deep-learning expertise.
Human reviews.
Insert
human reviews to provide oversight of your models
and manage
sensitive workflows using
Amazon Augmented AI, or A2I.