Amazon Route 53 Hosted Zones.
A Route 53 hosted zone
is a container for managing
Domain Name Service,
or DNS, records.
Those records hold information
about how you want to route
IP traffic for a specific domain
such as
example.com
and its subdomains,
www.example.com or
jobs.example.com.
There are two types of hosted zones,
public hosted zones and private hosted zones.
When you create a hosted zone,
it shares the name with the
domain you want to route traffic for.
Route 53 Public Hosted Zones.
A public hosted zone
holds the information
about how you want to route traffic external to AWS.
For an internet domain such as mycompany.com,
you then create DNS records
in the hosted zone to make a mapping
between a domain name
such as jobs.mycompany.com.
that route to external-facing AWS resources
like a CloudFront distribution or an EC2 instance
as well as route to on-premises servers.
When you create a public hosted zone,
Amazon Route 53 automatically creates a name server, or NS, record
and the start-of-authority, or SOA,
record for the zone.
The NS record identifies the four name servers
that you provide to the registrar so that
DNS queries are resolved successfully.
Route 53 Private Hosted Zones.
A private hosted zone contains the details
about how you want Amazon Route 53
to respond to DNS queries for domains
or
subdomains within one or more VPCs
created by Amazon VPC service.
Using private hosted zones requires
that you can figure Amazon VPC settings
and set the properties
enableDnsHostnames
and enableDnsSupport to true.
Private hosted zones only allow you to use
the following routing policies.
Simple routing,
failover routing,
multi-value answer routing,
or weighted routing.
By creating a private hosted and
public hosted zone with the same name,
you can create what is known as a split-view DNS.
Split-view DNS allows routing of DNS queries
to internal and external resources
depending on the request origin.
From a VPC, queries will go to the private hosted zone,
and the answer will route back to an internal-facing resource.
Internet queries will go to the public hosted zone,
and the response will route
to an external-facing resource.