Amazon VPC Flow Logs.
VPC Flow Logs
is a feature that enables you
to capture information about the IP traffic going to
and from elastic network interfaces, or ENIs,
in your Amazon VPC.
After you've created a flow log,
you can retrieve and view the generated data in the chosen destination,
which can be either
Amazon CloudWatch Logs or Amazon Simple Storage Service, or Amazon S3.
Flow Logs can help you with a number of repetitive tasks,
such as
diagnosing overly restrictive security group rules, monitoring the
traffic that is reaching your EC2 instance,
determining the direction of your IP traffic flows
to and from your Amazon VPCs, subnets, or ENIs.
VPC Flow Logs - Basics.
You can enable a flow log for your Amazon VPC,
a subnet,
or an ENI.
If you create a flow log at the subnet or VPC level,
each network interface in that subnet or VPC is monitored.
This could generate a lot of flow log data.
Flow log data for a monitored ENI is recorded as flow log records,
which are log events consisting of fields that describe the traffic flow.
To create a flow log, you specify
the resource for which to create the flow log, such as the VPC,
subnet, or ENI,
the type of traffic to capture, accepted traffic, rejected traffic, all traffic,
the destinations to which you want to publish the flow log data,
either Amazon S3 or Amazon CloudWatch Logs.
VPC Flow Logs - Publishing.
Flow Logs can publish flow log data directly to Amazon CloudWatch or Amazon S3.
When sending to CloudWatch Logs, flow log data is published to a log group.
You can create multiple flow logs that publish data to the same log group.
Data from each ENI is sent to a unique log stream in that log group.
Log streams are uniquely named based on the ENI ID
and the type of traffic - all,
reject, or accept - that it is collecting.
When publishing to Amazon S3,
flow log data is delivered to an existing
Amazon S3 bucket,
an optional folder that you specify.
The data is stored as a series of log file objects
that are compressed to save space.
The log file object name includes the flow log ID
and is placed in an S3 folder hierarchy
that includes
AWS account ID,
the AWS Region,
the year,
the month,
and the day of the month.
This makes it easy to query the data with other
AWS services such as Amazon Athena.