Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service.
Amazon EKS Overview.
Amazon EKS is a managed Kubernetes service that makes it
easy for you to run Kubernetes on AWS and on premises.
Kubernetes consists of two major components,
a cluster of worker nodes
running your containers and the control plane, managing when and where
containers are started on your cluster
while monitoring their status.
With EKS, you do not need to install, operate,
and maintain your own Kubernetes control plane or worker nodes.
Amazon EKS automatically
manages the availability and scalability
of the Kubernetes control-plane nodes
responsible for scheduling containers,
managing application availability,
and storing cluster data.
Amazon EKS lets you run your Kubernetes applications
on both Amazon EC2 and AWS Fargate.
When you need to run containerized applications requiring
particularly low-latency on-premises systems,
you can use Amazon EKS
on AWS Outposts.
With Amazon EKS Anywhere,
you can also easily create and operate
Kubernetes clusters on your own on-premises infrastructure.
Here are the key benefits.
Production workloads.
Amazon EKS
is designed with AWS
best practices for security, scalability,
and fault tolerance.
It is highly scalable
and built to meet the demands of production workloads.
Amazon EKS ensures a more secure Kubernetes environment
with security patches automatically applied to your cluster's control plane.
Kubernetes-conformant.
Amazon EKS runs upstream Kubernetes
and is certified Kubernetes-conformant, so you
can use all the existing plug-ins and tooling from
the Kubernetes community. Applications running on Amazon EKS are fully
compatible with applications running on any standard Kubernetes environment.
This means that you can easily migrate any standard Kubernetes
application to Amazon EKS without refactoring your code.
Seamless
AWS integration.
Amazon EKS is integrated with many AWS services
to provide scalability and security for your applications.
These integrated services include:
Elastic Load Balancing for load distribution,
AWS Identity and Access Management, or AWS IAM, for authentication.
Amazon ECR
for container registry,
Amazon Virtual Private Cloud, or
Amazon VPC, for isolation,
and AWS CloudTrail for logging.