Let's review auto scaling
and auto healing on AWS.
AWS Auto Scaling
monitors your applications and automatically adjusts capacity
to maintain steady and
predictable performance at the lowest possible cost.
AWS Auto Scaling
makes it easy to set up application scaling
for different types of resources across multiple services,
and you can configure this in minutes.
You can build scaling plans
using a simple interface to manage resources like Amazon EC2 Spot Fleets,
Elastic Container Service tasks, and
DynamoDB tables and indexes.
Scaling is simplified
with recommendations that optimize performance
and costs or
establishes a balance between them.
You can also configure smart-scaling
policies to calculate the appropriate scaling adjustments
that immediately add or remove capacity
from your applications based on targeted metrics
like CPU utilization.
Let's review how
AWS Auto Scaling can automatically heal applications.
In this example,
an application is powered by EC2 instances
that sit behind an Elastic Load Balancer.
The Auto Scaling group is configured to have an optimal capacity of six instances
spread across two Availability Zones.
If an instance in Availability Zone number one is failing,
an ELB health check will determine instance health, and
that triggers the launching of a new healthy instance.
Now ...
Now the application has returned
to its optimal state.
An Auto Scaling group can also rebalance instances when necessary.
If Availability Zone number one goes offline,
the Auto Scaling service will rebalance the instance load
by shifting instances to Availability Zone two,
until Availability Zone number one comes back online,
making your applications more available
and resilient.
Now let's review how
AWS Auto Scaling
can integrate with
AWS services using lifecycle hooks.
With lifecycle hooks,
you can perform actions on instances in an Auto Scaling group based on an event.
For example,
when an instance is flagged for termination,
a CloudWatch event detects the termination call,
which will trigger a Lambda function.
The Lambda function invokes
AWS Systems Manager,
and Systems Manager places the instance into a terminating
wait state.
While the instance is in the wait state,
Systems Manager bundles the application logs on the instance into a zip file
and stores them in an Amazon S3 bucket
before termination is complete.
The Auto Scaling service verifies with Lambda
that the log-saving process is complete
before it resumes terminating the instance.
With this automation,
you can save application logging information before instance termination
to aid in diagnosing any application issues.