AWS CloudFormation Features.
Here are the key features.
Extensibility.
Using the AWS CloudFormation registry, model, provision,
and manage third-party application resources
alongside AWS resources with AWS CloudFormation.
You can build your own resource providers using the AWS CloudFormation CLI,
which is an open-source tool that streamlines the development
process and includes local testing and code-generation capabilities.
Authoring with JSON or YAML.
AWS CloudFormation allows you to model your entire infrastructure in a text file.
You can use JSON or YAML
to describe what AWS resources you want to create and configure.
If you want to design visually,
you can use AWS CloudFormation Designer to
help you get started with AWS CloudFormation templates.
Authoring with familiar programming.
With the AWS Cloud Development Kit, or AWS CDK,
you can define your application using TypeScript, Python,
Java (developer preview) and .NET (developer preview).
AWS CDK is an open-source software
development framework that helps you model your cloud application
resources using familiar programming languages,
and then provision your infrastructure using AWS CloudFormation
directly from your IDE.
CDK provides you with high-level components
that preconfigure cloud resources with proven defaults,
so you can build cloud applications without needing to be an expert.
Preview changes to your environment.
If you want to make changes to the running resources in a stack,
you update the stack.
Before making changes to your resources,
you can generate a change set,
which is a summary of your proposed changes.
AWS CloudFormation change sets
allow you to preview how proposed changes to
a stack might impact your running resources,
for example, whether your changes will delete or replace any critical resources.
AWS CloudFormation makes the changes to your stack
only after you decide to execute the change set.
Dependency management.
AWS CloudFormation automatically manages dependencies between
your resources during stack management actions.
You do not need to worry about specifying the order
in which resources are created, updated, or deleted.
CloudFormation determines
the correct sequence of actions to use
for each resource when performing stack operations.
This is how CloudFormation works.
First, code your infrastructure from scratch with the CloudFormation
template language in either YAML or JSON format,
or start from many available sample templates.
Next, you can check out your template code locally or upload it
into an S3 bucket.
Then you can use
AWS CloudFormation via the browser console,
command-line tools, or APIs
to create a stack based on your template code.
AWS CloudFormation provisions and configures the
stacks and resources you specified on your template.