AWS X-Ray Features.
Here are the key features.
Simple setup.
It's easy to get started with AWS X-Ray.
You just integrate the X-Ray SDK with your application
and install the X-Ray agent.
End-to-end tracing.
AWS X-Ray provides an end-to-end, cross-service
view of requests made to your application.
AWS Service and Database Integrations.
AWS X-Ray supports applications running on Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud,
or Amazon EC2, Amazon Elastic Container Service, or
Amazon ECS, AWS Lambda, and AWS Elastic Beanstalk.
In addition,
the X-Ray SDK captures metadata for requests made to MySQL
and PostgreSQL databases such as self-hosted Amazon RDS,
Amazon Aurora, and Amazon DynamoDB.
It also captures metadata for requests made to Amazon Simple Queue Service, or SQS,
and Amazon Simple Notification Service, or SNS.
Support for multiple languages.
AWS X-Ray supports tracing for applications that are written
in Java, Python, Node.js, Ruby, .NET, and Go.
Request sampling.
You can set the trace sampling rate that is best
suited for your production applications or applications in development.
X-Ray continually traces requests made to your application and
stores a sampling of the requests for your analysis.
This provides you with the appropriate amount of data to make your
analysis meaningful, while avoiding the overhead
of storing and managing excessive data volume.
Console and programmatic access.
You can use AWS X-Ray with the AWS Management Console, AWS CLI, and AWS SDKs.
The X-Ray API
lets you programmatically access the service so you can easily export
trace data or ingest the data into your own tools and custom analytics dashboards.
Service map.
AWS X-Ray creates a map of services used by your application with
trace data that you can use to drill into specific services or issues.
This provides a view of connections between services in your application.
For each service,
it also provides aggregated data including the number
of traces that is sent per minute,
average latency, and failure rates.
Server- and client-side latency detection.
AWS X-Ray allows you to visually detect node
and edge latency distribution directly from the service map.
You can quickly isolate outliers, graph patterns and trends,
drill into traces,
and filter by built-in keys and custom annotations
to better understand performance issues
impacting your application and end users.
Data annotation and filtering.
AWS X-Ray lets you add annotations to data
emitted from specific components or services in your application.
You can use this to append business-specific
metadata that help you better diagnose issues.
You can also view and filter data for traces by properties such as annotation value,
average latencies, HTTP response status, timestamp, database table used, and more. Security.
AWS X-Ray is integrated with AWS Identity and Access Management,
or AWS IAM, so that you can control which users
and resources have permission to access your traces and how.