AWS CodeBuild Features
Here are the key features.
Build and test your code.
AWS CodeBuild runs your builds in preconfigured build
environments that contain the operating system, programming language runtime,
and build tools, such as Apache Maven,
Gradle, and npm required to complete the task.
You just specify your source code's location and select settings for your build,
such as the build environment to use and the build commands to run during a build.
AWS CodeBuild builds your code and stores
the artifacts into an Amazon S3 bucket,
or you can use a build command to upload them to an artifact repository.
You can create, manage, and initiate build projects using AWS CodePipeline,
the AWS Management Console, AWS CLIs,
or SDKs.
Preconfigured build environments.
AWS CodeBuild provides build environments for Java,
Python, Node.js, Ruby, Go, Android, .NET Core for Linux,
and Docker.
Customized build environments.
You can bring your own build environments to use with AWS CodeBuild,
such as for the Microsoft .NET framework.
You can package the runtime and tools for your build into a Docker image and
upload it to a public Docker hub repository,
or Amazon Elastic Container Registry, or Amazon ECR.
When you create a new build project,
you can specify the location of your Docker image.
CodeBuild will pull the image and use it as the build project configuration.
The following are the configurable settings features for AWS CodeBuild.
Specify build commands.
You can define the specific commands
that you want AWS CodeBuild to perform,
such as installing build tool packages, running unit tests,
and packaging your code.
The build specification is a YAML file
that lets you choose the commands to run at each phase of the build and other settings.
CodeBuild helps you get started quickly with sample build
specification files for common scenarios such as builds using Apache Maven,
Gradle, or npm.
Select compute type.
You can select the compute type that is best suited to your development needs.
You can choose from different levels of compute capacity
that vary by the amount of virtual CPU, memory, and disk space.
CodeBuild supports Linux
and Windows operating systems.
Choose source integrations.
You can initiate builds with AWS CodeBuild in several ways.
For example,
you can initiate builds in CodeBuild by connecting to source providers,
such as AWS CodeCommit, GitHub,
GitHub Enterprise, Bitbucket, or Amazon S3.
Continuous integration and delivery workflows.
You can integrate CodeBuild into your existing continuous integration and
continuous delivery, or CI/CD, workflow using its source integrations,
build commands, or Jenkins integration.
You can plug CodeBuild into AWS CodePipeline,
which automates building and testing code in CodeBuild
each time you commit a change to your source repository.
CodeBuild also belongs to a family of AWS code services
that helps you practice CI/CD.
You can create this continuous integration, or CI,
workflow by using the AWS CodePipeline wizard
to connect your source repository and then select CodeBuild as the build provider.
You can easily extend your continuous integration workflow into
continuous delivery with CodePipeline, by integrating third-party load
or user interface testing tools, such as BlazeMeter Ghost Inspector,
that initiate after CodeBuild completes the build.
You can then deploy to your instances or on-premises servers
using services integrated with AWS CodePipeline,
such as AWS CodeDeploy and AWS Elastic Beanstalk.
Security and permissions.
Your build artifacts are encrypted with customer-specific keys
that are managed by the AWS Key Management Service, or KMS.
AWS CodeBuild is integrated with AWS Identity and Access Management,
so you can set granular controls over which users
and AWS resources have access to your builds.
Monitoring.
You can use the AWS CodeBuild console, AWS CLI, SDKs, and APIs,
or Amazon CloudWatch to view detailed information about your builds.
AWS CodeBuild shows you information such as the build start time,
end time, status, and commit ID.
CodeBuild also streams build metrics and logs to CloudWatch.
Receive notifications.
You can create notifications for events impacting your build projects.
Notifications will come in the form of Amazon SNS notifications.
Each notification includes a status message
as well as a link to the resources whose event generated that notification.