AWS CodePipeline Features.
Here are the key features.
Workflow modeling.
A pipeline defines your release process workflow.
It comprises a series of stages
which act as logical divisions in your workflow.
Each stage is made up of a sequence of
actions that are performed on the application artifacts.
A transition is the point where a pipeline execution
moves to the next stage in the pipeline.
Parallel executions.
You can use CodePipeline to model your actions to run
in parallel in order to increase your workflow speeds.
Sequential actions.
You can also model actions sequentially.
You can visualize the status
of each stage action in the pipeline.
AWS CodePipeline provides you
with a graphical user interface,
allowing you to easily visualize
and model your release process workflow.
AWS integrations.
AWS CodePipeline can pull source code for
your pipeline directly from AWS CodeCommit,
GitHub, Amazon ECR, or Amazon S3.
It can run builds and unit tests in AWS CodeBuild.
CodePipeline can deploy your changes using AWS CodeDeploy,
AWS Elastic Beanstalk, Amazon Elastic Container Service,
or AWS Fargate.
You can model AWS CloudFormation actions that
let you provision, update,
or delete AWS resources as part of your release process.
This also enables you to continuously
deliver serverless applications built using AWS Lambda,
Amazon API Gateway,
and Amazon DynamoDB
with the AWS Serverless Application model,
AWS SAM.
You can also trigger custom functions defined by code
at any stage of your pipeline
using CodePipeline's integration with AWS Lambda.
Pre-built plug-ins.
AWS CodePipeline allows you
integrate third-party developer tools like
GitHub or Jenkins into any stage of your release process
with one click.
You can use third-party tools for source control,
build, test, or deployment.
Custom plug-ins.
AWS CodePipeline allows you
to integrate your own custom systems.
You can register a custom action
by integrating the CodePipeline
open-source agent with your servers.
The custom action allows you
to hook your servers into your pipeline.
You can also use the CodePipeline Jenkins plug in
to easily register your existing build servers
as a custom action.
Declarative templates.
AWS CodePipeline allows you to define your pipeline
structure through a declarative JSON document.
This document specifies your release workflow,
its stages, and actions.
These documents enable you
to update existing pipelines
as well as provide starting templates
for creating new pipelines.
Access control.
AWS CodePipeline uses AWS IAM
to manage who can make changes to your release workflow
as well as who can control it.
You can grant users access through IAM users,
IAM roles, and SAML integrated directories.
Receive notifications.
You can create notifications for events
impacting your pipelines.
Notifications will come in the form of
Amazon SNS notifications.
Each notification includes a status message
as well as a link to the resources
whose event generated that notification.