AWS HealthLake Overview
AWS HealthLake is a HIPAA-eligible
service
that health care and life sciences
companies
can use to store, transform, query
and analyze large-scale health data
following FHIR standard.
FHIR stands for Fast Healthcare
Interoperability Resource.
You can use HealthLake
to organize, index, and structure
patient information in a way
that is secure, compliant, and can be
audited.
HealthLake uses machine learning models
to automatically understand
and extract meaningful medical
information
from the raw data.
AWS HealthLake use cases.
Manage population health.
HealthLake helps healthcare organizations
analyze population health trends, costs,
and choose better care management options.
Improve quality of care.
Hospitals, health insurance companies
and life sciences organizations
use HealthLake
to improve quality of care
and reduce cost
by compiling a complete view of a
patient's medical history.
Optimize hospital efficiency.
HealthLake offers hospitals
analytics and machine learning tools
to improve efficiency and reduce hospital
waste.
AWS HealthLake benefits.
Quickly ingest health data.
Using the HealthLake Import API.
you can migrate FHIR files from Amazon S3
to your HealthLake datastore
including clinical notes, lab reports,
insurance claims, and more.
Store health data securely.
AWS HealthLake creates a datastore
that stores health records in a
FHIR-compliant format.
The datastore creates a complete view
of each patient's medical history in
chronological order.
AWS HealthLake supports multiple
security and access controls
to ensure patient-sensitive health data
is protected and meets regulatory
compliance.
Transform unstructured medical data.
HealthLake provides integrated medical
natural language processing, NLP, using Amazon Comprehend Medical.
Raw medical text data is transformed using
specialized ML models.
These models have been trained to
understand and extract meaningful information from unstructured healthcare data.
This is the end of Amazon HealthLake
overview. Thanks for watching.