AWS CodeStar Overview.
AWS CodeStar enables you to quickly develop,
build, and deploy applications on AWS.
AWS CodeStar provides a unified user interface, allowing you
to easily manage your software development activities in one place.
With CodeStar,
you can set up your entire continuous delivery toolchain in minutes,
enabling you to start releasing code faster.
CodeStar simplifies secure team collaboration, allowing
you to manage access and add owners,
contributors, and viewers to your projects.
Each AWS CodeStar project comes with a project management dashboard,
including an integrated issue-tracking capability.
With a CodeStar dashboard,
you can track progress across your entire software development
process from your backlog to recent code deployments.
Here are some benefits from using AWS CodeStar.
With AWS CodeStar, it's easy to start developing in minutes.
You can choose from a variety of CodeStar templates such as
Amazon EC2, AWS Lambda, and AWS Elastic Beanstalk.
For source control,
you can choose AWS CodeCommit or GitHub for your project, and you can
edit your source code using AWS Cloud9, Microsoft Visual Studio, or Eclipse.
After you make your selections,
the underlying AWS services are provisioned in minutes,
allowing you to quickly start coding and deploying your applications.
CodeStar provides an easy way to coordinate your day-to-day
development activities through a unified user interface.
AWS CodeStar's project dashboard
lets you monitor code commits,
builds, tests, and deployments from a central place.
CodeStar also integrates with Atlassian Jira software,
a third-party issue tracking and
project management tool, allowing you to easily manage
Jira issues directly in the AWS CodeStar dashboard.
AWS CodeStar also enables you to collaborate on
projects across your team in a secure manner.
You can easily manage access for project owners,
contributors, and viewers without needing to manually
configure your own policy for each service.
CodeStar simplifies the process of setting up
project access for teams by providing
built-in role-based policies that follow
AWS Identity and Access Management best practices.
AWS CodeStar accelerates software release by integrating AWS CodeBuild,
AWS CodePipeline, and AWS CodeDeploy into the CodeStar service.
Each project comes preconfigured with an automated pipeline that
continuously builds, tests, and deploys your code with each commit.
And with CodeStar's IDE integrations,
you can begin developing your code directly using AWS Cloud9,
that comes with a pre-authenticated AWS Command Line Interface.
Once your application is deployed, you can monitor its performance with
Amazon CloudWatch or Atlassian Jira.