AWS Global Infrastructure Overview.
The AWS Global Infrastructure
delivers a cloud infrastructure
companies can depend on,
no matter their size, changing needs, or challenges.
It is designed and built to deliver the most flexible,
reliable,
scalable,
and secure cloud computing environment
with the highest quality global network performance available today.
AWS provides the most extensive global footprint
to ensure your worldwide customers are served.
You can rapidly expand operations to virtually any region or country.
AWS now spans 69 Availability Zones within 22 geographic Regions around the world.
The footprint is expanding continuously,
with plans for 13 more Availability Zones,
and four more AWS Regions in Indonesia, Italy, South Africa and Spain.
This fast-paced expansion of Regions is also paired with
Amazon's long-term commitment to a sustainable future
using renewable energy sources.
The AWS Global Infrastructure consists of the following main components.
Amazon Cloud computing resources are hosted in multiple worldwide locations
referred to as AWS Regions.
Each AWS Region
is a separate geographic area
and has multiple isolated locations, known as Availability Zones.
An AWS Region
has at least two Availability Zones,
most have three,
including all new Regions, and several have as many as six.
They are fully isolated
and are many kilometers apart from each other
for complete redundancy.
Each Availability Zone consists of one or more discrete data centers,
typically three,
and at full scale, it can be hundreds of thousands of servers.
To ensure maximum reliability,
each data center has redundant power,
dedicated Metro Fiber connectivity,
and are housed in separate facilities.
Network.
Every data center, AZ, and AWS Region
is interconnected via a purpose-built, highly available
and low-latency, private global network infrastructure.
The network is built on a global,
fully redundant parallel 100 gigabit Ethernet Metro Fiber network.
Points of Presence.
With Amazon CloudFront,
AWS operates the largest global content delivery network, or CDN,
of any cloud provider.
It enables customers to securely deliver customers' data content to end users
with low latency and high transfer speeds,
through a worldwide network of global points of presence, PoP locations,
which consist of edge locations and regional edge cache servers.
Availability Zones make partitioning applications as easy as it can be.
If an application is partitioned across Availability Zones,
companies are better protected from natural disasters such as lightning strikes,
tornadoes, earthquakes,
and more.
In this example,
you can deploy your application across three Availability Zones,
and a load balancer is used to distribute traffic across them.
If one Availability Zone experiences an outage,
traffic is routed to another Availability Zone.
Customer application is still up and running.