AWS X-Ray Overview.
AWS X-Ray helps developers analyze and debug production,
distributed applications such as those built using a microservices architecture.
With X-Ray,
you can understand how your application
and its underlying services are performing
to identify and troubleshoot the root cause of performance issues and errors.
Here are the key benefits.
Review request behavior.
AWS X-Ray traces user requests
as they travel through your entire application.
It aggregates the data generated by the individual
services and resources that make up your application,
providing you an end-to-end view of how your application is performing.
The data gathered from individual services in your application
into a single unit is called a trace.
Discover application issues.
With X-Ray's tracing features,
you can follow request paths to pinpoint where in your application
and what is causing performance issues.
X-Ray annotations also make it possible to tag
and filter trace data with the appended metadata,
which helps discover patterns and diagnose issues.
Improve application performance.
AWS X-Ray helps you identify performance bottlenecks.
You can easily detect where high latencies are occurring
and visualize node and edge latency distribution for services.
And you can drill down into the
specific services and paths impacting application performance.
Ready to use with AWS.
AWS X-Ray works with Amazon EC2, Amazon Elastic Container Service, or Amazon ECS,
AWS Lambda, and AWS Elastic Beanstalk.
You can use X-Ray with applications
that are deployed on these services.
Designed for a variety of applications.
AWS X-Ray works for both simple and complex applications,
either in development or in production.
You can analyze simple synchronous event calls,
3-tier web applications, or complex microservices applications
consisting of thousands of services.
With X-Ray,
you can trace requests made to applications that span multiple AWS accounts,
AWS Regions, and Availability Zones.
Here's how it works.
First, collect traces.
AWS X-Ray collects data about the request
from each of the underlying application services it passes through.
Then record traces.
X-Ray combines the data gathered from
each service into singular units called traces.
With the traces,
it creates the service map, which is an aggregated view of the traces.
A service map shows trace data such as latencies,
HTTP statuses, and metadata for each service.
With this information provided,
you can then analyze issues.
You can drill into the service showing unusual behavior to identify the root issue.
AWS X-Ray makes it easy for developers to quickly find and address problems
in their applications and improve the experience
for end users of their applications.