AWS Step Functions - More Features.
Built-in error handling.
AWS Step Functions automatically handles errors and exceptions,
whether the task takes seconds or months to complete.
You can automatically retry failed or timed-out tasks,
respond differently to different types of errors,
and recover gracefully by falling
back to designated cleanup and recovery code.
History of each execution.
AWS Step Functions integrates with Amazon CloudWatch
and AWS CloudTrail to deliver real-time diagnostics and dashboards.
It logs every execution, including overall state, failed steps, inputs, and outputs.
If things go wrong, you can quickly troubleshoot and remediate failures.
Visual monitoring.
Launching an application is as simple as pressing a button,
then watching the steps execute visually,
so you can quickly verify that everything
is operating in order and as expected.
The console clearly highlights errors,
so you can quickly pinpoint their root cause and troubleshoot issues.
High availability.
AWS Step Functions has built-in fault tolerance
and maintains service capacity across multiple Availability Zones
in each Region to protect applications
against individual machine or data-center failures.
Automatic scaling.
AWS Step Functions automatically
scales the operations and underlying compute to
run the steps of your application for you, in response to changing workloads.
It ensures the performance of your application workflow
remains consistent as the frequency of requests increases.
Security and compliance.
AWS Step Functions is integrated with AWS Identity and Access Management, or AWS IAM,
and recommends a least-privileged IAM policy
for all of the resources used in your workflow.
Step Functions is a HIPAA-eligible service,
and can be used with applications containing healthcare-related information,
such as personal health information, or PHI.
AWS Step Functions is also compliant
with SOC, or System and Organization Controls, measures.
Pay per use.
With AWS Step Functions,
you pay for each transition from one state to the next.
Billing is metered by state transition.
You do not pay for idle time,
regardless of how long each state persists - up to one year.
This keeps Step Functions cost-effective
as you scale from a few executions to tens of millions.
High-volume orchestration.
AWS Step Functions adds express workflows
that are suitable for high- volume, short-duration workflows,
such as streaming data processing and IoT data ingestion.
Express workflows support event rates greater than 100,000 per second.
Express workflows can coordinate AWS Lambda function invocations, AWS IoT rules engine actions,
and Amazon EventBridge events
from over 100 AWS third-party SaaS event sources.