AWS Batch Overview.
Developers, scientists, and engineers use AWS Batch
to efficiently run hundreds of thousands of batch computing jobs on AWS.
Using AWS Batch, there is no need to install and manage batch computing software
or server clusters that you use to run your jobs.
So you can focus on analyzing results and solving problems.
AWS Batch plans, schedules,
and runs your batch computing workloads across the full range of
AWS Batch compute services and features,
such as AWS Fargate, Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud, or Amazon EC2, and spot instances.
You can use AWS Batch at no additional charge.
You pay only for the AWS resources that you create to store and run your batch jobs,
such as EC2 instances or Fargate jobs.
AWS Batch Benefits.
Fully managed.
AWS Batch removes the need to operate third-party commercial
or open-source batch processing solutions.
AWS Batch manages the infrastructure for you,
avoiding the complexities of provisioning, managing,
monitoring, and scaling your batch computing jobs.
Integrated with AWS.
AWS Batch is natively integrated with AWS products and services,
allowing you to use the scaling, networking,
and access management capabilities of AWS.
This integration helps you run jobs that safely
and securely retrieve and write data to and from
AWS datastores, such as Amazon S3 or Amazon DynamoDB.
Cost-optimized resource provisioning.
AWS Batch provisions compute resources
and optimizes the job distribution based on the volume
and resource requirements of the submitted batch jobs.
AWS Batch dynamically scales
compute resources to any quantity required to run your batch jobs,
freeing you from the constraints of fixed capacity clusters.
AWS Batch will use spot instances or submit to Fargate Spot on your behalf,
reducing the cost of running your batch jobs further.