AWS CodeDeploy Features.
Here are the key features - Automated
instance deployments features.
Repeatable deployments.
You can easily repeat an application deployment
across different groups of instances with AWS CodeDeploy.
CodeDeploy uses a file- and command-based install model, which enables
it to deploy any application and reuse existing setup code.
Automatic scaling.
AWS CodeDeploy allows you to integrate
software deployment and scaling activities in order
to keep your application up to date in a dynamic production environment.
For Amazon EC2 instances,
CodeDeploy integrates with auto scaling.
Auto scaling allows you to scale EC2
capacity according to conditions you define,
such as spikes in traffic. CodeDeploy is notified whenever
a new instance launches into an Auto Scaling Group.
It will then automatically perform an application deployment on the new instance.
On-premises deployments.
You can use AWS CodeDeploy to automate
software deployments running on any instance,
including instances in your own data centers.
In this scenario,
your instances will need to be able to connect to AWS public endpoints.
This enables you to use a single service
to consistently deploy applications across hybrid architectures.
Minimize downtime features.
Rolling and blue/green update.
AWS CodeDeploy can perform blue/green deployments to Amazon EC2 instances
and Amazon ECS service, including both EC2 and
AWS Fargate launch type, or an AWS Lambda function.
With a blue/green deployment,
the new version of your application is launched alongside the old version.
Once the new revision is tested and declared ready,
CodeDeploy can shift the traffic from your prior version
to your new version according to your specifications.
CodeDeploy can also perform a rolling update across a group of Amazon EC2 instances.
Only a fraction of the instances are taken offline at any one time.
CodeDeploy progressively works its way across the instances,
allowing applications to remain available and continue serving traffic.
Deployment health tracking. Deployment
health tracking works in conjunction with rolling updates
to keep applications highly available during deployments.
Unexpected downtime can occur if bad updates are deployed.
AWS CodeDeploy monitors your deployment, and if there are too many failed updates,
it will stop the deployment.
Stop and rollback.
You can stop an application deployment that is in process at any time
using the AWS Management Console, the AWS CLI, or any of the AWS SDKs.
You can simply re-deploy that revision if you want
to continue the stopped deployment at a later time.
You can also immediately roll back by redeploying the previous revision.
Centralized control features. Monitoring and control.
You can launch control and monitor deployments
of your software directly from the AWS Management Console
or by using the AWS CLI, SDKs, or APIs.
In the case of a failure, you can pinpoint the script experiencing failure.
You can also set push notifications that allow you to monitor the status
of your deployments, via SMS or
email messages through Amazon Simple Notification Service.
Deployment groups.
One application can be deployed to multiple deployment groups.
Deployment groups are used to match configurations to specific environments,
such as a testing, staging, or production environment.
You can test a revision in staging and then deploy
that same code with the same deployment instructions to production
once you are satisfied.
Deployment history.
AWS CodeDeploy tracks and stores the recent history of your deployments.
You can view which application versions are currently
deployed to each of your target deployment groups.
You can inspect the change history and success
rates of past deployments to specific deployment groups.
You can also investigate a timeline of past deployments for
a detailed view of your deployment successes and errors.
Easy-to-adopt features. Language and architecture
agnostic. CodeDeploy uses a single
application specification configuration file,
the App Spec file, which defines the deployment
actions you want CodeDeploy to execute.
You define the install, run actions,
tests, or verifications at each phase of deployment,
which is referred to as the lifecycle event.
The commands can be any code such as a shell script,
a custom program, or even a configuration management tool.
This file- and command-based install model enables it
to deploy any application and reuse existing setup code.
Tool chain integration.
It is easy to integrate application deployments with your existing
software-delivery tool chain by using the AWS CodeDeploy APIs,
AWS CodePipeline,
AWS CodeStar, and some AWS Partners-provided pre-built CodeDeploy
integrations for continuous integration and continuous delivery, or CI/CD, services,
making it simple to automatically deploy your updated application.
Received notification features - review defined events.
You can create notifications for events
impacting your deployments. Notifications will come in
the form of Amazon SNS notifications.
Each notification includes a status message
as well as a link to the resources whose event generated that notification.