AWS Fargate Overview.
AWS
Fargate is a serverless pay as you go compute engine
that is compatible with Amazon Elastic Container Service
or Amazon ECS.
Fargate is also compatible with Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service
or Amazon EKS.
Amazon
ECS and Amazon EKS
can schedule containers in Kubernetes pods
onto Fargate to automatically scale,
load balance and optimize container and pod availability.
Fargate supports multiple CPU architectures and operating systems
to help you run containers for a wide variety of applications.
AWS Fargate components.
You need to create a task definition to prepare your application
to run on Amazon ECS with a Fargate launch type.
The task definition is a JSON file that describes
how one or more containers should be launched.
You can launch an ECS service to run
and maintain the desired number of tasks simultaneously
in an ECS cluster.
You will need to use a Fargate profile to
define how Amazon EKS should run Kubernetes pods on
AWS Fargate.
Each Fargate profile contains a pod execution role,
the Subnet IDs to launch pods into and the Kubernetes
selectors to match for pods to use the Fargate profile.
This execution role provides the necessary permissions for the
Amazon EKS components that run on the Fargate infrastructure.
AWS Fargate Use Cases.
Build web apps, APIs and microservices.
Build and deploy your applications, APIs
and microservices architectures with the
speed and immutability of Fargate containers,
Remove the need to own, run, and manage the life cycle of a compute infrastructure,
so you can focus on your applications.
Run and scale container workloads.
You can use Fargate to run and scale your containerized data processing workloads.
Fargate can also be used to modernize
applications when building new applications in the cloud
or migrating a traditional application to the cloud.
Support AI and ML training applications.
With Fargate,
you can train, test, and deploy your machine learning models at scale.
Fargate can also be used to create a flexible
and portable artificial intelligence and machine learning AI
and ML development environment.
This is the end of AWS Fargate overview video.
Thanks for watching.