AWS Lambda Overview
AWS Lambda is a serverless compute service
you can configure with a trigger. AWS Lambda then runs your code automatically in response to your trigger.
AWS Lambda manages all the underlying
compute resources for you,
all you need to do is supply the code. AWS
Lambda takes care of everything required to run and scale your code with high availability.
This is how it works.
First, simply upload your code to AWS
Lambda or write code in Lambda's code editor.
The code you run on AWS Lambda is called a
Lambda function.
Next, you can set up your code to trigger
from other AWS services, HTTP endpoints, in-app activity, or run on a schedule.
Then, AWS Lambda is ready to run your code
only when invoked, using only the compute resources needed. You just pay for the compute time you use.
You can invoke Lambda functions directly
or configure triggers to invoke Lambda functions in response to incoming HTTP requests or AWS services.
You can also configure Lambda to read from
a queue or a stream and invoke a function or run on a schedule using EventBridge triggers.
Here are some examples
Amazon Simple Storage Service, or S3
When there is a change in the Amazon S3
bucket content, such as when an object file is created, deleted, or updated, the lambda function is invoked.
Amazon Simple Notification Service, or SNS
When a message is published to an SNS
topic that the lambda function subscribed to it, the lambda function is invoked.
Amazon API Gateway
You can create APIs using Amazon API
Gateway. When the API is called, API Gateway invokes the Lambda function.
Amazon Dynamo DB
When a DynamoDB record is created or
modified, the lambda function can be configured to trigger and run the code.
Amazon Simple Queue Service, or SQS
You can use AWS Lambda function to process
messages in a Amazon SQS queue. Lambda pulls the queue and invokes your function synchronously.
What are the benefits of AWS Lambda?
You do not need to provision or manage any
servers.
All you need is to write the code, upload
it to Lambda, and then AWS Lambda automatically runs your code for you.
Another benefit is continuous scaling.
In response to each trigger, AWS Lambda
automatically scales your application.
Your code runs in parallel and processes
each trigger individually, scaling precisely with the size of the workload.
Sub-second metering
With AWS Lambda, you pay only for what you
use.
Pricing is based on the number of times
your code is triggered, that is the number of requests and the duration, the time it takes to run your code.
Billing is metered in increments of 1
millisecond.
When your code isn't running, you do not
pay anything.
With AWS Lambda, it makes it easy to build
cost-effective serverless applications that respond quickly to your customer needs.