AWS CloudTrail Overview.
AWS CloudTrail is a fully managed service that records AWS API calls made to
Amazon Web Services,
or AWS accounts, helping you implement
governance,
compliance,
and operational and risk auditing
across your entire AWS infrastructure,
giving you control over
storage, analysis, and remediation actions.
Actions taken by users
and AWS service
or an IAM role
are recorded as events and delivered to CloudTrail.
Events recorded include operations
done via the AWS Management Console,
AWS Command Line Interface,
or AWS CLI,
application program interfaces, or APIs,
and the various software development kits, or SDKs.
CloudTrail helps you answer the question of
who did what,
where,
and when.
When you create an AWS account, CloudTrail is enabled by default.
Recent activity can easily be viewed by going to
event history in the CloudTrail console.
You can deliver your CloudTrail event details to Amazon S3
or Amazon CloudWatch Logs.
CloudTrail's integration with Amazon EventBridge
provides a convenient way to create
rule-based alerts that trigger remediation workflows.
AWS CloudTrail Benefits.
Log file encryption.
By default,
AWS CloudTrail
encrypts all log files
delivered to Amazon S3,
using Amazon S3 server-side encryption,
or SSE-S3.
Or add a layer of protection to your log files by encrypting them with an
AWS Key Management Service,
or AWS KMS, key.
Amazon S3 automatically decrypts your log files
if you have the KMS decrypt action assigned to your IAM role.
You can also define Amazon S3 lifecycle rules
to archive and delete log files automatically.
CloudTrail Insights.
AWS CloudTrail Insights empowers users
to identify and respond to unusual activity
by continually monitoring
CloudTrail management events.
CloudTrail Insights can be viewed by
logging into the CloudTrail console,
or they can also be delivered to the
S3 bucket configured for your trail.
CloudTrail Insights events are recorded only
when CloudTrail detects
anomalies or
excessive API executions that vary from typical usage.
Multi-Account and Multi-Region.
AWS CloudTrail can be configured to record
events from multiple accounts and regions
and deliver them to a single AWS destination.
This ensures that accounts and regions
newly created behave consistently,
thereby eliminating the need for manual intervention.
If you use AWS Organizations to manage your AWS accounts,
you can create an organizational
trail from the Organizations management account.
Once created, it will log all events across your entire organizational hierarchy.