Let's review the key features for AWS AppSync.
AppSync uses GraphQL, a data language that enables client apps to fetch,
change, and subscribe to data from servers.
In a GraphQL query, the client specifies
how the data is to be structured when it is returned by the server.
This makes it possible for the client to query only for
the data it needs in the format that it needs it in.
GraphQL also includes a feature called introspection,
which lets new developers on a project discover
the data available by querying information about the GraphQL schema.
AppSync also lets you specify
which portions of your data should be available in a real-time manner.
Using GraphQL subscriptions.
GraphQL subscriptions are simple statements in the application code
that tell the service what data should be updated in real time.
With AppSync, you can update your data using the AWS Amplify datastore.
The Amplify datastore provides a queryable on-device datastore for web,
mobile, and IoT developers to interact seamlessly
with data whether you're online or offline.
You can leverage advanced versioning and conflict detection and resolution
that allows automatic merging of data from different clients.
AppSync gives client applications data filtering capabilities with GraphQL
so only the needed data is fetched,
allowing for both server and client filtering.
Since AppSync supports AWS Lambda, Amazon DynamoDB, and Amazon Elastisearch,
the GraphQL operations can be simple lookups,
complex queries and mappings,
full-text searches,
fuzzy keyword searches, or geo lookups.
AWS AppSync server-side data caching capabilities
reduce the need to directly access data sources by making data available
in high-speed and memory-managed caches delivering data at low latency.
Being fully managed,
it eliminates the operational overhead of
managing cache clusters by providing the
flexibility to selectively cache data fields and operations defined
in the GraphQL schema with customizable expiration.
Data caching further enables developers
to configure optimal performance for their business needs.
To control your data,
AppSync allows several levels of data access and
authorization, depending on the needs of an application.
Simple access can be protected by a key, and more restrictive permission
can be done with AWS Identity and Access Management user roles.
Additionally, AWS AppSync integrates with
Amazon Cognito user pools for email and password functionality.
Social providers and enterprise federation with SAML.
Customers can use the group functionality for logical organization of users
and roles as well as OAuth features for application access.