Welcome to the AWS Config Overview.
AWS Config is a service
that enables you
to assess, audit,
and evaluate
the configurations of your AWS resources.
Config continuously monitors
and records
your AWS resource configurations.
This allows you to automate the ongoing evaluation
of recorded configurations against desired configurations.
AWS Config enables you to simplify compliance auditing, change management,
security analysis,
and operational troubleshooting.
Let's look at some benefits of
AWS Config.
Continuous monitoring.
AWS Config creates a resource inventory of your AWS resources, including
EC2 software configurations.
After the initial resource discovery,
new resources are added automatically with
continuous monitoring when configuration changes occur.
Amazon SNS
can send notifications, so you can review or take action to modify the change.
Continuous assessment.
By creating rules that
define your desired resource configuration,
you can measure resource compliance against your organization's best practices.
You can package your rules together with corrective actions
into conformance packs.
Conformance packs can be deployed across your entire organization.
Deviations against the rules trigger
SNS notifications
and EventBridge events
for continual alerting.
You can measure your overall compliance
and easily find non-compliant resources
Change management.
The configuration history allows you to view any configuration
point in the past for a specific resource.
You can easily view relationships
and resource dependencies.
This allows you to understand the impact of
potential changes before you make the change.
This helps to minimize change-related incidents.
Operational troubleshooting.
You can identify the root cause of operational issues
through AWS Config's integration with AWS CloudTrail.
CloudTrail correlates configuration changes to
particular events in your account.
This allows you to view
the details of an event API call
that invoked the change, such as who made the request,
at what time,
and from which IP address.
Enterprise-wide compliance.
With multi-account and multi-region data aggregation,
you can view compliance status
across your enterprise from a central account.
This allows you to identify non-compliant accounts.
You can dive deeper into status for a specific region or a specific account.
Third-party resource support.
With AWS Config can perform configuration audit and compliance verification
of both your AWS
and third-party resources.
You can publish the configuration of third-party resources,
such as GitHub repositories,
Microsoft Active Directory resources, or any on-premises server into AWS.
You can then view and monitor
the resource inventory
and configuration history.
You can also create
AWS config rules and conformance packs
to evaluate these third-party resources.