AWS AppSync Overview. AWS AppSync simplifies application development
by letting you create a flexible
API to securely access, manipulate, and combine data from one or more data sources.
AppSync is a managed service that uses GraphQL to make
it easy for applications to get exactly the data they need.
With AppSync you can build scalable
applications including those requiring real-time
updates on a range of data sources such as NoSQL datastores,
relational databases, HTTP APIs, and your custom data sources with AWS Lambda.
For mobile and web apps,
AppSync additionally provides local data access when devices go offline
and data synchronization with customizable conflict
resolution when they are back online.
Here are the benefits of using AWS AppSync.
With AppSync you can get started in minutes
directly from your IDE of choice, using the AppSync Management Console
or the AWS Amplify CLI to
automatically generate your API and client-side code.
AWS AppSync integrates with Amazon DynamoDB,
Amazon Aurora,
Amazon Elasticsearch,
AWS Lambda, and other AWS services,
enabling you to create sophisticated applications
with virtually unlimited throughput and storage
that scale according to your business needs.
AWS AppSync enables real-time subscriptions across millions of
devices as well as offline access to app data.
When an offline device reconnects,
AWS AppSync automatically syncs only the updates that occurred when
the device was disconnected and not the entire data set.
AppSync offers user customizable server-side
conflict detection and resolution that does
the heavy lifting of managing data conflicts so you don't have to.
AppSync also allows you to perform complex queries and aggregation across
multiple data sources with a single network call using GraphQL.
AWS AppSync makes it easy to secure your
app data using multiple concurrent authentication modes
as well as allowing to define security
and fine-grained access control at the data-definition level,
directly from your GraphQL schema.