AWS Systems Manager - Overview.
AWS Systems Manager is a collection of features that help you manage your IT infrastructure
running in the AWS Cloud or on-premises data centers.
AWS Systems Manager simplifies the management of your applications and IT inventory.
AWS Systems Manager
thereby helps reduce the time it takes to detect and resolve operational problems.
In summary,
AWS Systems Manager helps you manage your
AWS resources securely
and at scale.
AWS Systems Manager - Features.
AWS Systems Manager is the operations hub for your AWS applications and IT resources.
AWS Systems Manager functionality is broken up into four
core feature groups that help you implement operations management best practices.
Operations Management.
AWS Systems Manager OpsCenter provides
a central location where operations engineers
and IT professionals can view, investigate,
and resolve operational issues affecting AWS resources.
Change Management.
Use Systems Manager Documents
to automate common
and repetitive maintenance
and deployment tasks.
You can use automation to reset passwords on servers, apply OS patches,
and remediate compliance issues.
Application Management.
With Systems Manager Application Manager,
you can define your application components based on automated
import of service metadata from AWS services such as
AWS CloudFormation stacks,
Amazon Elastic Container Service,
Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service,
and AWS Launch Wizard.
Then view operations management data in the context of the application
and perform change management tasks.
Node Management.
AWS Systems Manager Fleet Manager
streamlines the management process for servers running in the cloud or on premises.
Fleet Manager's remote management capabilities allow you to troubleshoot
and configure your server fleet at scale,
thereby saving you time and money.
AWS Systems Manager - Use Cases.
Centralized Operations Data.
Aggregate operational data, or ops data,
and view it in a single console to gain actionable insights
across AWS services such as
Amazon CloudWatch,
AWS CloudTrail,
AWS Config as well as third-party tools.
Implement Best Practices. Automate proactive processes at scale,
such as patching and maintenance,
or reactive processes to quickly diagnose and
remediate operational issues before they affect users.
Remediate Security Issues.
Enhance your security and compliance profile and analyze security incidents
after the fact to prevent a future reoccurrence.
Auto-Resolve Issues.
Automatically resolve application issues by using ops data to easily manage applications
and identify issues quickly across associated AWS resource groups.