AWS-IoT Overview
AWS IoT, or Internet of Things, provides
the cloud services that connect IoT devices to other devices in AWS cloud services.
AWS IoT provides device software that can
help integrate your IoT devices into AWS IoT-based solutions.
AWS IoT Core supports connections with IoT
devices, wireless gateways, services, and apps.
Devices connect to AWS IoT Core so that
they can send data to and receive data from AWS IoT services and other devices.
Apps and other services also connect to
AWS IoT Core to control and manage IoT devices and process the data from your IoT solution.
AWS IoT Core supports different protocols such as MQTT, or Message Queuing and Telemetry
Transport.
MQTT over WSS, or WebSockets Secure.
MQTT over HTTPS, or Hypertext Transfer
Protocol Secure, LoRaWAN, or Long Range Wide Area Network.
AWS IoT Core Services
AWS IoT Core Messaging Services
The AWS IoT Core connectivity services
provide secure communication with IoT devices
and manage the messages that pass between
the devices in AWS IoT.
The Device Gateway enables devices to
securely and efficiently communicate with AWS IoT.
The message broker provides a secure
mechanism for devices and AWS IoT applications to publish and receive messages from each other.
AWS IoT Core for LoRaWAN, which is a
low-power, wide-area networking protocol.
makes it possible to set up a private
LoRaWAN network by connecting your LoRaWAN devices.
and gateways to AWS without the need to
develop and operate a LoRaWAN network server.
LNS
The rules engine connects data from the
message broker to other AWS IoT services for storage and additional processing.
AWS IoT Core Control Services
The AWS IoT Core control services provide
device security, management, and registration features.
Using the Custom Authentication Service,
you can define custom authorizes to provide authentication and authorization using different strategies, such as JSON Web Token Verification or OAuth Provider Callout.
Using the Device Provisioning Service, you
can provision devices
using a template that describes
a Thing object, a Certificate, and one or
more policies.
Using the group registry, you can manage
several devices at once by categorizing them into groups.
Using the job service, you can define a
set of remote operations that are sent to and run on one or more devices connected to AWS IoT.
Using the registry, you can organize the
resources associated with each device in the AWS cloud.
Using the Security and Identity Service,
you can provide shared responsibility for security in the AWS cloud.
AWS IoT Core Data Services
The AWS IoT Core data services help the
IoT solutions provide a reliable application experience even with devices that are not always connected.
A device shadow is a JSON document used to
store and retrieve current state information for a device.
The device shadow service maintains a
device's state so that applications can communicate with the device, whether the device is online or not.
AWS IoT Core Support Services
Amazon Sidewalk integration for AWS IoT
Core is a shared network that improves connectivity options to help devices work together better.