AWS Identity and Access Management Best Practices.
Let's take a look at
IAM user management best practices.
Root user access.
As a best practice,
it is recommended that the root user
not be used for everyday admin tasks.
Initially, when you first create a new AWS account,
use the root user's credentials
to create a primary IAM admin user,
then securely lock the root user credentials.
For any user, including the root user,
apply the best practices discussed in this video.
Enable multi-factor authentication, or MFA.
For extra security, require MFA
for all users in an account.
With MFA enabled,
users have to enter their credentials
and the MFA-generated challenge
to complete the sign-in process.
So if the user's password or access keys are compromised
your AWS account resources remain secure and protected
due to the additional authentication requirement.
Password complexity.
Implement an organization-wide password policy
that ensures users create complex passwords
that meet requirements such as
upper and lowercase letters,
at least one number,
special nonalphabetic characters
as well as preventing password re-use
and enforcing a minimum password length.
Access keys.
Access keys provide command-line access to AWS resources.
Access keys should never be embedded within
your applications or shared between programmers
even if they are on the same team.
When your applications require access to AWS resources,
configure the program to assume an IAM role
and retrieve temporary security credentials
that can access those resources.
Rotate credentials.
Passwords and access keys should expire periodically
and on a set schedule.
Therefore, if a password or access key is compromised,
you limit the time
a hacker has access to your AWS resources.
Use the AWS Identity and Access Management console
to directly set how many days before a password expires.
Rotating access keys can be managed and automated
by using AWS Config
and its managed rule "access-keys-rotated."
Remove credentials.
IAM credentials and access keys
for users that leave the company or team should be deleted.
If users have not used their credentials in several months,
it might be best to disable them initially
while clarifying their need for access.
Confirm what type of access is needed.
If the AWS console is the only one they use,
then delete any programmatic access keys.
If they need programmatic access or command-line access only,
then disable their AWS console password.
AWS IAM Roles - Best Practices.
Using IAM roles.
You can use IAM roles to delegate access
to applications, users, or services
that need to connect to AWS resources.
IAM roles eliminate the need for access
keys and passwords which can easily be compromised.
IAM roles grant temporary access for a limited amount of time,
which lowers the risk of your credentials being compromised.
For IAM users,
create separate IAM roles for different job tasks
and allow them to assume those roles to perform those tasks.
EC2 instance profiles.
For applications hosted on Amazon EC2,
the best practice is for temporary
credentials to be delegated to the application
by using an instance profile
and assigning it to the Amazon EC2 instance.
Instance profiles are similar to IAM roles and
can be assigned directly to one or more
Amazon EC2 instances.
The temporary credentials are rotated automatically for you.
The IAM role assigned to your
EC2 instance can be changed without incurring downtime,
making it easy to grant permissions
and reducing application development time.