AWS IoT Greengrass Overview.
AWS
IoT Greengrass is an Internet of Things, or IOT, open
source edge runtime and cloud service that helps you build,
deploy, and manage device software.
Customers use AWS
IoT Greengrass for their IoT applications on millions of devices in homes,
factories, vehicles, and businesses.
You can program your devices to act locally on the data
that they generate, execute predictions based on machine learning models,
filter and aggregate device data, and transmit
only necessary information to the cloud.
Key Benefits
Manage IOT applications at scale
using
AWS
IOT Greengrass.
You can remotely deploy and manage device software on millions of devices,
configuring the software to a subset of devices or to all devices at once.
You can also organize your devices in groups.
Over the Air Updates.
You have the ability to update
AWS
IoT Greengrass core software on IoT Greengrass devices.
You can use the
AWS management console APIs
or command-line interface to update the version of IoT Greengrass cores
or components running on your devices in order to deploy security updates,
bug fixes, and new IoT Greengrass features.
Greengrass software catalog.
The Greengrass software catalog is a collection of
IoT Greengrass components developed by the Greengrass community.
Instead of developing device components for each required capability,
you can now quickly install, use, and modify components from a
list of prebuilt software components to kickstart your IoT edge application.
Key features
Local processing for AWS Lambda
Using
AWS
IoT Greengrass, you can run
AWS Lambda functions on a device to respond quickly to local events,
interact with local resources, and process data to
minimize the cost of transmitting data to the cloud.
Local messaging.
AWS
IoT Greengrass provides messaging between the IoT
Greengrass core and devices using the AWS
IoT Device SDK on the local network which facilitates communication.
Even when there is no connection to
AWS,
your devices can process messages and deliver them to another device
or to the cloud based on business rules that you define.
Machine Learning Inference.
AWS
IoT Greengrass ML inference is a feature
that helps you perform machine learning inference locally
on IoT Greengrass devices by using models that are built and trained in the cloud.
This means you won't incur data transfer costs or
increase latency for applications that use machine learning inference.