Welcome to an Overview of Cloud Security on AWS.
In this lesson,
you will learn about the benefits of using AWS's secure infrastructure
and services.
With AWS, you will gain the control and confidence you need to securely run
your business with the most flexible and
secure cloud computing environment available today.
AWS customers benefit from AWS data centers and
a network architecture to protect your information, identities,
applications, and devices.
Automating security tasks on AWS
enables you to be more secure by reducing human configuration areas,
giving your team more time to focus on innovation and scaling.
Select from a wide variety of deeply integrated
solutions that can be combined to automate tasks,
making it easier for your security team to work closely
with developer and operations teams to create and deploy code faster
and more securely.
AWS is vigilant about your privacy.
All data flowing across the AWS global network
is encrypted at the physical layer before it leaves our secure facilities.
And additional encryption layers exist,
such as with VPC cross-Region peering traffic and service-to-service TLS connections.
AWS also features fine-grain identity and access controls that
ensure the right resources have the correct access at all times.
For compliance,
AWS regularly achieves third-party validation
for thousands of global compliance requirements
to help you meet security and compliance standards for finance,
retail, healthcare, and more.
AWS is also the only commercial cloud that has
had its service offerings and associated supply chain vetted
and accepted
as secure enough for top-secret workloads.
You can extend the benefits of AWS
by using security technology and consulting services from
familiar solution providers within the AWS Partner Network.
AWS security services help you define user permissions and identities,
infrastructure protection,
and data protection measures
for a smooth and planned
AWS adoption strategy.
You can also gain visibility into your organization's security posture
with logging and monitoring services,
then ingest this information into a scalable platform
for event management,
testing,
and auditing.
AWS enables you to automate incident response and recovery
to help shift the primary focus of security teams from response
to analyzing root cause.
With AWS,
you can utilize event-driven automation to quickly remediate
and secure your AWS environment in near real-time.