AWS Storage Gateway Overview
Storage Gateway is a hybrid cloud storage service that
gives you on-premises access to virtually unlimited cloud storage.
It provides a cost effective alternative to on-premises storage
and offers a variety of features including low latency access,
encryption, and compliance.
Here are some key features.
Multiple storage gateway types.
AWS Storage Gateway offers three types of gateways,
File gateway,  volume gateway and tape gateway.
Each gateway type is designed to cater to specific storage requirements
and use cases, providing a flexible solution for different scenarios.
Data transfer optimization.
Storage Gateway optimizes data transfer by using a
combination of buffering, compression, and bandwidth management techniques.
This helps reduce the amount of data transferred over the internet and
minimize the impact on your network
resulting in improved performance and cost savings.
Integration with AWS services.
Storage Gateway integrates seamlessly with various
AWS services such as Amazon S3, S3 Glacier,
AWS Backup and Amazon CloudWatch.
With this integration, you can use the full power of AWS
to manage, monitor and secure your hybrid cloud storage environment.
Here are some key benefits.
Cost savings.
Using AWS Storage Gateway,
you can minimize capital expenditures associated with
purchasing and maintaining physical storage infrastructure.
With this pay as you go pricing model,
you only pay for the storage and data transfer that you actually use,
thus optimizing your overall costs.
Enhanced data security.
Storage Gateway ensures the security of your data
through encryption, identity management, and access controls.
Data is encrypted in transit and at rest
while you maintain control over the encryption keys used for decryption
providing you with a secure solution for storing and managing your data.
Streamlined data management.
Storage Gateway streamlines data management by providing
a unified interface for managing your on-premises and cloud storage
with features such as lifecycle policies,
automated backups, and versioning,
Storage Gateway helps you to manage and protect your data across your hybrid environment.