AWS Cloud Development Kit Overview.
Provisioning cloud applications can be a challenging process
that requires you to perform manual actions,
write custom scripts, maintain templates, or learn domain-specific languages.
The AWS Cloud Development Kit, or AWS CDK,
is an open-source software development framework
to model and provision your cloud application
resources using familiar programming languages.
AWS CDK provides you with high-level
components that preconfigure cloud resources with proven defaults,
so you can build cloud applications without needing to be an expert.
It provisions your resources in a safe,
repeatable manner through AWS CloudFormation.
Here are some of the concepts behind the AWS CDK.
The AWS CDK supports TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, Java,
and C# over .NET.
Developers can use one of the supported programming languages
to define reusable cloud components known as constructs.
A construct represents a cloud component and encapsulates everything
AWS Cloud Formation needs to create the component.
It encodes configuration detail, Boilerplate,
and Glue logic for using one or multiple
AWS services.
Additionally,
constructs are adjustable and composable. You can easily change
any of the parameters or encode your own custom construct.
A construct can represent a single resource
or multiple AWS CDK resources.
You compose the constructs together into stacks, forming a CDK application.
Now, let's look at the power of the AWS CDK
in this example. Here is some code in an AWS CDK project.
In this example,
a VPC construct is used to create a Virtual Private Cloud
and a cluster construct to create an ECS cluster.
A Fargate service running on an ECS cluster,
fronted by an Application Load Balancer, can just be created by this one
application load-balanced Fargate service construct.
In just a few lines of code,
this class produces an AWS CloudFormation template of more than 500 lines,
and deploying the AWS CDK app produces more than 50 resources.
In addition, here are more benefits.
Easier cloud onboarding.
AWS CDK accelerates your onboarding to
AWS because there are only a few new things to learn.
You can use your existing skills and tools to
build cloud infrastructure using the preconfigured cloud resources.
Customizable and shareable. With AWS CDK,
you can design your own reusable components
that meet your organization's security, compliance, and governance requirements.
Just like with any other software library,
you can easily share components around your organization,
enabling you to rapidly bootstrap new projects with best practices by default.
Faster development process.
You can use familiar features such as objects,
loops, and conditions to accelerate your development process.
You can also use AWS CDK with your integrated development environment, or IDE,
to take advantage of existing productivity tools and testing frameworks.
There is no context switching required.
You can use your existing IDE and the same programming language
to write your runtime code and define your AWS resources.