AWS Secrets Manager Overview.
AWS Secrets Manager helps you protect secrets needed
to access your applications, services, and
IT resources.
The service enables you to easily rotate,
manage, and retrieve database credentials,
API keys,
and other secrets throughout their lifecycle.
Users and applications retrieve secrets
with a call to Secrets Manager APIs
eliminating the need to hard-code sensitive information in plain text.
Now let's go through some of the key benefits.
Rotate secrets safely.
AWS Secrets Manager
helps you meet your security
and compliance requirements by enabling you to rotate secrets safely
without the need for code deployments.
Manage access with fine-grained policies.
With Secrets Manager
you can manage access to secrets
using fine-grained AWS Identity and Access Management,
or IAM, policies and resource-based policies.
Pay as you go.
AWS Secrets Manager offers pay-as-you-go pricing.
You pay for the number of secrets
managed in Secrets Manager
and the number of Secrets Manager
API calls made.
Secure and audit secrets centrally.
Using Secrets Manager,
you can help secure secrets by encrypting them
with encryption keys.
It also integrates with AWS logging
and monitoring services for centralized auditing.
Easily replicate secrets to multiple regions.
AWS Secrets Manager enables you to
easily replicate secrets in multiple AWS Regions
to support your multi-region applications
and disaster-recovery scenarios.
Here are the key features.
Secure secret storage.
AWS Secrets Manager
encrypts secrets at rest
using encryption keys that you own
and store in AWS Key Management Service, or KMS.
When you retrieve a secret,
Secrets Manager decrypts the secret
and transmits it securely
over Transport Layer Security, or TLS,
to your local environment.
Automatic secrets rotation without disrupting applications.
AWS Secrets Manager offers secret rotation with
built-in integration for Amazon RDS,
Amazon Redshift, and Amazon DocumentDB.
The service is also extensible to other types of secrets,
including API keys
and OAuth tokens.
You can rotate secrets on a schedule or on demand.
It enables you to automate secret rotation
while ensuring applications run without interruption.
Automatic replication of secrets to multiple AWS Regions.
You can specify the AWS Regions where a secret needs to be replicated,
and Secrets Manager will securely create regional read replicas.
Multi-region applications can rely on Secrets Manager to
keep the replicas in sync with the primary secret.
Programmatic retrieval of secrets.
To retrieve secrets,
you simply replace plaintext secrets in your applications with code
to pull in those secrets programmatically
using the Secrets Manager APIs.
You can also configure
Amazon Virtual Private Cloud, or
VPC, endpoints to keep traffic between your VPC
and Secrets Manager
within the AWS network.
Audit and monitor secrets usage.
AWS Secrets Manager enables you to use AWS CloudTrail
logs to see when Secrets Manager rotates a secret.
Secrets Manager also integrates with Amazon EventBridge to
notify you of certain events that affect your secrets,
such as deleting a secret.
Compliance.
You can use AWS Secrets Manager to manage secrets
for workloads that are subject to the following compliance requirements.