AWS IoT FleetWise Overview
AWS IoT FleetWise is used to collect,
organize, and store vehicle data in a standardized way for analysis in the cloud.
After the data is in the cloud, you can
use it for applications that analyze vehicle fleet health and resources.
This analysis can help you more quickly
identify potential maintenance issues or make in-vehicle infotainment systems smarter.
You can also feed the data into machine
learning models that improve autonomous driving and advanced driver assistance systems.
Key Features
Edge Agent
The Edge Agent for AWS IoT FleetWise
facilitates communication between a vehicle and the cloud.
You can develop your Edge Agent by using
the Edge Agent Reference Implementation for AWS IoT Fleetwise, a fully functional piece of embedded software designed for vehicle data collection that can run on most embedded Linux-based platforms.
Global signal catalog
AWS IoT FleetWise provides a centralized
repository of standardized vehicle sensors and signals for your vehicle models.
You can save time by reusing signals when
creating new vehicle models.
Rules-based data collection
To transfer only the data signals that you
want to the cloud, AWS IoT FleetWise can apply rules that you define.
To start, you can define vehicle
attributes and the sensors associated with a vehicle’s make, model, and trim (such as engine temperature, vehicle speed, and parking assist system).
You can then define rules and events for
when to transfer the sensor data based on parameters, such as changes to temperature or speed for a certain vehicle type.
Use cases
Maintain EV battery health
Monitor EV battery health and charge
levels and improve range estimates for drivers.
Enhance the in-cabin experience
Use data from in-vehicle infotainment
systems to make services, audiovisual content, and features more relevant.
Improve fleet operations
Use insights from commercial fleet data to
analyze driver safety, vehicle uptime, and maintenance schedules.