AWS Cloud Map Overview.
Why use AWS Cloud Map?
Before we talk about AWS Cloud Map,
let's look at the challenges we are facing in the growing complexity of our modern architectures.
Modern applications are typically composed of multiple
services that are accessible over an API
and perform a specific function.
Each service interacts with a variety of other resources, such as databases,
queues, object stores, and customer-defined microservices.
Each service needs to be able to find the location
of all the infrastructure resources on which it depends
in order to function.
In most cases, you manage all these resource names
and their locations manually within the application code.
However, manual resource management becomes time-consuming
and error-prone as the number of dependent infrastructure
resources increases, or the number of microservices dynamically
scale up and down based on traffic.
You can also use third-party service discovery products,
but this requires installing and
managing additional software and infrastructure.
With AWS Cloud Map,
you can easily locate all these dynamic resources
used by the services in your application.
AWS Cloud Map is a cloud resource discovery service.
It builds the dynamic map of your cloud. With Cloud Map,
you can define and register custom names for your application resources.
It maintains the updated location of these dynamically changing resources.
AWS Cloud Map also integrates with open-source solutions
such as Kubernetes, Consul, and Istio.
Some common use cases include service discovery for microservices,
automated health monitoring, and continuous integration and delivery.
Here are the key benefits.
Increase application availability.
Cloud Map constantly monitors the health of every IP-based
component of your application and dynamically updates the location
of each microservice as it is added or removed.
This ensures that your applications only discover
the most up-to-date location of its resources
increasing the availability of the application.
Increased developer productivity.
Cloud Map provides a single registry for all your application services.
This increases your developer team's productivity because they don't
have to constantly store, track, and update resource
name and location information or make
changes directly within the application code.
This is how it works.
If you are not using Cloud Map, endpoints are statically coded into your application.
In this example,
backend service has updated from version one to version two. To access the backend
service, code change is required to update its endpoint
location from version one to version two.
On the other hand,
with Cloud Map, endpoints are dynamically located. In this example,
backend service has again updated from version one to version two.
AWS Cloud Map always maintains the most up-to-date resource location and
therefore has already updated endpoint from version one to version two.
The frontend service only needs a dynamic lookup
to Cloud Map to find the location of version two.
Frontend service can then be connected to a
new endpoint in version two of the backend service.