AWS Key Management Service Overview.
AWS Key Management Service, or AWS KMS, is a managed service that makes it easy
for you to create and manage keys and control the
use of encryption across a wide range of AWS services.
KMS is a secure and resilient service
that uses FIPS 140-2 validated hardware security
modules to isolate and protect your keys.
You can generate keys in AWS KMS or
import them from your own key management infrastructure.
You can submit data directly to AWS KMS to be encrypted or decrypted,
and other AWS services can use your keys
on your behalf to protect data encryption keys.
Your keys never leave AWS KMS, and you are always in control of your keys.
You can set usage policies that determine which
users can use your keys and what actions they can perform.
And all requests are logged in AWS CloudTrail so you can track usage.
Here are some benefits from using the AWS Key Management Service.
With AWS Key Management Service,
you can focus on your use of encryption while AWS handles durability,
physical security, and policy enforcement to ensure that
your keys are always available and safe.
KMS presents a single control point to manage keys and define
policies consistently across integrated AWS services and your own applications.
AWS KMS is integrated with the AWS Encryption SDK to enable you to use
KMS-protected data encryption keys to encrypt locally within
your applications. Using APIs,
you can build encryption and key management
into your own applications wherever they run.
You can also perform digital signing operations using asymmetric
key pairs to ensure the integrity of your data.
Recipients of digitally signed data can verify the signatures
whether they have an AWS account or not.
AWS KMS uses hardware security modules that have been validated under
FIPS 140-2 to protect the confidentiality and integrity of your keys.
This means that your plaintext keys are never written to
disk and only ever used in volatile memory of the HSMs
for the time needed to perform your requested cryptographic operation.
AWS KMS is designed so only you can retrieve your plaintext keys from the service.
Your keys are only used inside these devices and can never leave them unencrypted,
and KMS keys are never shared outside the AWS Region in which they were created.
AWS KMS's security and quality controls
have been validated by numerous compliance
regimes such as PCI DSS,
FIPS, HIPAA, and FedRAMP.
AWS KMS also provides the option to store your keys in single-tenant HSMs
in AWS Cloud HSM instances that you control. For auditing, AWS KMS
is integrated with AWS CloudTrail to record all API requests,
including key management actions and usage of your keys.
With CloudTrail enabled,
each request you make to AWS KMS is recorded in a log
file that is delivered to an Amazon S3 bucket that you specify.