AWS Step Functions Features.
Here are the key features.
Workflow configuration.
Using AWS Step Functions, you define your workflows of state machines
which transform complex code into easy-to-understand statements and diagrams.
Building applications and confirming that they are
implementing your desired functionality is quicker and easier.
Built-in service primitives.
AWS Step Functions provides ready-made steps for your workflow,
called states, that implement basic service primitives for you.
AWS service integrations.
Using AWS Step Functions service tasks,
you can configure your step functions workflow to call other AWS services.
This includes compute services, such as AWS Lambda, Amazon ECS,
AWS Fargate, database services
Amazon DynamoDB, messaging services, such as Amazon SNS and Amazon SQS,
data processing services, such as AWS Batch and AWS Glue,
and machine-learning services
Amazon SageMaker.
Coordination of distributed components.
AWS Step Functions can coordinate any application that can make
an https://-connection, regardless of where it is hosted.
For example, on Amazon EC2 instances, mobile devices, or on-premises servers.
Using Step Functions,
you can quickly create distributed applications
that leverage AWS services as well as your own microservices.
Component reuse.
AWS Step Functions coordinates your existing Lambda functions
and microservices into robust applications
and lets you quickly rewire them into new compositions.
Workflow abstraction.
AWS Step Functions keeps the logic of your application
strictly separated from the implementation of your application.
Through this separation of concerns,
your workflows gain modularity, simplified maintenance, scalability, and code reuse.
State management.
AWS Step Functions maintains the state of your application during execution,
including tracking what step of execution it is in and storing
data that is moving between the steps of your workflow.
This means you don't have to manage state
or build complex state management yourself.