AWS CloudFormation Overview.
AWS CloudFormation allows you to use programming languages
or a simple text file as templates to model and provision AWS
and third-party application resources in your cloud environment.
An AWS CloudFormation template is a simple text file in JSON or
YAML format that describes your AWS resources and their properties.
AWS CloudFormation uses these templates as
blueprints for building all the resources needed
for your applications in an automated and
secure manner, across all regions and accounts.
The collection of AWS resources you want to deploy
together as a group is called a stack.
You can update your CloudFormation stack
at any time by uploading a modified template.
You can also check your template into version control,
so you can keep track of all changes
made to your infrastructure and application stack
the same way you do with software code.
Provisioning infrastructure is as simple as creating
and uploading a template to CloudFormation.
This makes replicating your infrastructure very simple.
You can easily and quickly spin up a replica of your production stack
for development and testing with a few clicks in the AWS Management Console.
You can tear down and rebuild the replication stack whenever you want.
Here are the key benefits.
Model it all.
AWS CloudFormation allows you to model your entire infrastructure and
application resources with either a text file or programming languages.
The AWS CloudFormation registry and CLI make it
easy to manage third-party resources with CloudFormation.
AWS CloudFormation helps you to standardize
infrastructure components used across your organization,
enabling configuration compliance and faster troubleshooting.
Automate and deploy.
AWS CloudFormation
provisions your application resources in a safe, repeatable manner,
allowing you to build and rebuild your infrastructure and applications
without having to perform manual actions or write custom scripts.
CloudFormation takes care of determining the right
operations to perform when managing your stack,
orchestrating them in the most efficient way, and
rolls back changes automatically if errors are detected.
It's just code. Codifying your infrastructure allows
you to treat your infrastructure as just code.
You can author it with any code editor,
check it into a version control system, and review
the files with team members before deploying into production.