AWS Cloud Map Features.
Here are the key features.
Discover resources via API calls or DNS queries.
Cloud Map allows your applications to discover any web-based service
via AWS SDK, API calls, or DNS queries.
Using the Discovery API.
Cloud Map can return URLs or Amazon resource names, or ARNs,
as well as IP addresses and IP port combinations using either IPv4 or IPv6.
Over DNS, Cloud Map provides resource locations of IP addresses or IP port combinations.
Simplified service naming.
AWS Cloud Map lets you define simple custom names for services in your application.
This can include Amazon Elastic Container Service, or ECS, tasks,
Amazon EC2 instances, Amazon S3 buckets, Amazon DynamoDB tables,
Amazon Simple Queue Service, or SQS, queues, and any other cloud resource.
Assigned custom attributes.
Cloud Map lets you define custom attributes for each resource,
such as location and deployment stage.
This enables attribute-based service discovery,
which filters based on the attributes you specify in your discovery query.
Access control.
Cloud Map is integrated with AWS Identity and Access Management, or AWS IAM,
to ensure that only authenticated services can discover resources within the registry ,
and retrieve the location and credential for those resources.
Automatic health check.
AWS Cloud Map can provision Amazon Route 53 health checks for resources.
Amazon Route 53 health checks ensure that only
healthy endpoints are returned on discovery queries.
This ensures that Cloud Map always has an up-to-date registry of healthy resources.
With the health status information,
smart traffic routing can quickly stop
traffic routing to the unhealthy resources.
AWS Cloud Map also supports custom health checks.
You can control when to start and stop traffic routing.
You can set status to healthy or unhealthy to control the routing.
Deep integration with AWS container services.
Services and tasks managed by Amazon Elastic Container Service, or ECS,
or Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service, or EKS,
can be automatically registered and updated in Cloud Map.
Rapid change propagation.
When you're using API-based discovery with AWS Cloud Map,
the updates on your resource locations and attributes
are available within five seconds.
Fully managed.
AWS Cloud Map eliminates the need to set up,
update, and manage your own service discovery tools and software.