AWS Global Infrastructure benefits.
Here are the benefits of the AWS Global
Infrastructure.
Performance.
AWS Global Infrastructure ensures high
quality and uninterrupted performance.
It offers customers a high performing low
latency, highly scalable, high availability, secure cloud infrastructure and responds to changing needs fast without any drop in performance.
AWS provides customers with the highest
levels of availability and reliability.
AWS availability zones are designed for
physical redundancy and provide resilience enabling uninterrupted performance with no single points of failure.
Every component of the AWS
infrastructure is designed and built for redundancy and reliability from regions to networking links to load balancers to routers and firmware.
In addition, the AWS Global
Infrastructure is built on Amazon's own custom hardware such as custom purpose built compute servers, load balancers, routers, and silicon.
AWS optimizes this hardware for only
one set of requirements - workloads run by A.W.S. customers.
By using custom hardware, AWS provides
customers with the highest levels of reliability, the fastest pace of innovation all at the lowest possible cost.
Security.
Our core infrastructure is designed to
meet the most stringent security requirements in the world and is built to satisfy the security requirements for military, global banks, and other high sensitivity organizations.
Our infrastructure is monitored 24 7 to
help ensure the confidentiality, integrity and availability of our customers' data.
Scalability.
The AWS global Infrastructure enables
companies to be extremely flexible and take advantage of the conceptually infinite scalability of the cloud.
Customers can provision the amount of
resources that they actually need knowing they can instantly scale up or down along with the needs of their business.
Companies can quickly spin up resources as
they need them, deploying hundreds or even thousands of servers in minutes.
Low cost
With the industry's most extensive data
center footprint,  the AWS Global Infrastructure enables more customers to benefit from cloud economics of scale and reduce the total cost of ownership (TCO) of their overall IT infrastructure.