AWS Identity and Access Management Features - Manage IAM Permissions.
Permissions are granted to IAM entities including IAM users,
federated users, groups, and roles.
To give entities permissions, you can attach a policy.
A policy consists of one or more statements,
each of which describes one set of permissions.
Versions specify the version of the policy language
that you want to use.
Sid is optional and specifies the statement ID
to differentiate between your statements.
Effect specifies whether to allow or deny access.
Because access is denied by default,
you typically write policies where the effect is to allow.
Principal specifies the IAM entity that is allowed or denied access to a resource.
Action includes a list of actions that you allow or deny.
And here are some action examples for S3 service.
Resources specify which AWS resources you allow the action on.
Conditions specify which conditions must be present for the policy to take effect.
For example, you might allow access only to specific S3 buckets
if the user is connecting from a specific IP range,
or has used multi-factor authentication at login.
You create policies by using either the visual editor or JSON.
The visual editor guides you through granting permissions by using
IAM policies without having to write the JSON syntax.
You simply choose the service, actions,
resources, and request conditions to generate your policy.
You can still author and edit policies in JSON, if preferred.
The following policy example was created with the visual editor.
This policy is for Amazon S3 service.
It grants four list actions and one read action to the S3 bucket and objects in SampleBucket
if the prefix starts with MyPrefix.
To make it simpler to choose AWS service's actions,
they are categorized in these access levels: list, read, tagging,
write, and permissions management.
If you use the AWS Management Console to manage permissions,
you can view policy summaries.
A policy summary lists the access level, resources,
and conditions for each service defined in a policy.