Hello and welcome to AWS Well-Architected Overview.
AWS Well-Architected helps cloud architects design infrastructure
that is built around six pillars, operational excellence,
security, reliability, performance efficiency, cost optimization, and sustainability.
The AWS Well-Architected framework includes hands-on labs,
access to the AWS Well-Architected Partner Program,
and the AWS Well-Architected tool which architects can use to evaluate workloads,
identify high-risk issues,
and record improvements.
Let us take a closer look at the six pillars that define an
AWS Well-Architected design.
The Operational excellence pillar focuses on running and
monitoring systems and continually improving processes and procedures.
The Security pillar focuses on protecting information and systems.
The Reliability pillar focuses on ensuring workloads perform their assigned
functions and recover quickly from any failure to meet demands.
The Performance efficiency pillar focuses on
selecting suitable resource types and sizes,
monitoring performance, and maintaining efficiency.
The Cost optimization pillar focuses on understanding spending trends,
controlling fund allocation,
and scaling to meet business needs without overspending.
The Sustainability pillar focuses on minimizing the
environmental impact of running your cloud workloads,
such as energy consumption and resource use.
How does the AWS Well-Architected tool help
create a Well-Architected infrastructure?
The AWS Well-Architected tool extends the Well-Architected functionality,
best practices, measurements,
and learnings into your existing architecture processes, applications, and workflows.
It creates custom lenses where you can add best-practices
pillars and questions based on what's most important to your organization.
Using the tool,
you can share your workloads and custom lenses with up to 300 individual
AWS Identity and Access Management, or IAM,
users or accounts or across an entire organization.
Reviewing your workload against sustainability
best practices in the AWS Well-Architected tool
can help you understand energy consumption and environmental impact.
The AWS Well-Architected tool is available in the AWS GovCloud Region of the US.
So customers with specific regulatory and
compliance requirements can conduct self-service
public sector reviews.
You can learn more about the AWS Well-Architected tool and custom lenses
by visiting the AWS Well-Architected website.