AWS CodePipeline Overview.
AWS CodePipeline is a fully managed continuous delivery service
that helps you automate your release pipelines
for fast and reliable application and infrastructure updates.
Based on the release model you define,
every time there is a code change, CodePipeline automates the build,
test, and deploy phases of your release process.
You can easily integrate
AWS CodePipeline with third-party services.
With AWS CodePipeline, you only pay for what you use.
You just need to pay for the active pipeline per month.
There are no up-front fees or long-term commitments.
Here are the key benefits.
Rapid delivery.
With CodePipeline,
you can quickly iterate on feedback and get new features to your users faster.
Automating your release process allows you to quickly and easily test
each code change and catch bugs
while they are small and simple to fix.
You can ensure the quality of your application or infrastructure code
by running each change through your staging and release process.
Get started fast.
With AWS CodePipeline,
you can immediately begin to model your software release process.
There are no servers to provision or set up.
It can connect to your existing tools and systems.
Configurable workflow.
AWS CodePipeline allows you to model the different stages of
your software release process using the AWS Management Console interface,
the AWS CLI, AWS CloudFormation, or the AWS SDKs.
You can easily specify the tests to run and
customize the steps to deploy your application and its dependencies.
Easy to integrate.
AWS CodePipeline can easily be extended to adapt to your specific needs.
You can use our pre-built plug-ins or your own custom plug-ins
in any step of your release process.
For example, you can pull your source code from GitHub,
use your on-premises Jenkins build server,
run load tests using a third-party service,
or pass on deployment information to your custom operations dashboard.
This is how it works.
In this example,
when developers commit changes to a source repository,
CodePipeline automatically detects the changes.
Those changes are then built.
If any tests are configured, those tests are run.
After the tests are complete,
the build code is deployed to staging servers for testing.
From the staging server, CodePipeline runs more tests,
such as integration or load tests.
Upon the successful completion of those tests and after a manual
approval action that was added to the pipeline, the code is approved,
CodePipeline deploys the tested and approved code to production,
and delivers applications to the customers.
Developers can quickly respond to any bugs, customer ideas, and requests
with bug fixes, changes, and updates to the applications.
The new changes are committed to the source code repository,
and the entire process automatically repeats.