AWS IoT SiteWise Overview
AWS IoT Sitewise is a managed service that
industrial enterprises use to collect, store, organize, and visualize thousands of sensor data streams from Internet of Things, or IoT devices across multiple industrial facilities.
AWS IoT SiteWise includes software that
runs on a gateway device that sits onsite in a facility.
The software continually collects data and
sends it to the cloud.
With AWS IoT SiteWise, you can focus on
using your data to detect and fix equipment issues, spot inefficiencies, and improve production output.
Key Features
Sitewise Edge
AWS IoT SiteWise includes AWS IoT SiteWise
Edge, on-premises software used to collect, organize, process, and monitor equipment data locally before sending it to AWS.
SiteWise Edge runs on local hardware, such
as third-party industrial gateways and computers, or on AWS Outposts and AWS Snow Family compute devices.
SiteWise Edge uses AWS IoT Greengrass,
which provides a local software runtime environment for edge devices to help build, deploy, and manage applications.
Time series storage
Use AWS IoT SiteWise to store industrial
data generated from your equipment in a fast and scalable time series data store.
AWS IoT SiteWise storage supports two
tiers for equipment data: a hot tier optimized for real-time applications and a cold tier optimized for analytical applications.
AWS IoT SiteWise helps you reduce storage
costs by keeping recent data in the hot tier and moving historical data, based on policies, to a cost-optimized storage tier.
Asset modeling
Use AWS IoT SiteWise to build models of
your physical operations that represent your assets, processes, and facilities.
These models help you understand
industrial data in the context of your equipment.
After your models are created, you can
define an asset hierarchy to accurately represent relationships between devices and equipment within a single facility or across multiple facilities.
Use cases
Increase production efficiencies
Organize sensor data streams from multiple
production lines and facilities to drive efficiencies across locations.
Improve manufacturing operations
Monitor performance metrics from
manufacturing lines, assembly robots, and factory equipment to discover and act on opportunities for improvement.
Optimize asset maintenance
Prevent, detect, and resolve equipment
issues faster through remote asset monitoring, using historical and near-real-time data.