AWS Lambda Error Handling.
When you invoke a function, two types of error can occur.
Invocation errors occur when the invocation request
is rejected before your function receives it.
Function errors occur when your function's code
or runtime returns an error.
The error handling strategy and retry behavior varies
depending on how you invoke your Lambda function.
When you invoke a function directly, you determine the error handling strategy.
When you invoke a function indirectly,
the error handling behavior varies based on the types of invocations,
including synchronous,
poll-based,
and asynchronous invocations.
First, let's look at the error handling for synchronous invocation.
When the function response returns an error,
there is no error behavior for Lambda,
the service where the client is responsible for the error-handling strategy
such as checking the error, determining if you should retry the invoke.
Error handling for poll-based invocation.
Poll-based invocation uses event source mapping to read events from a stream or a queue.
In this model,
the retry behavior is based on data expiration in the data source for streams.
If your function returns an error,
the entire batch is reprocessed until the function
succeeds or the items in the batch expire.
For queues, you determine the length of time between retries,
the destination for failed events,
the conditions under which Amazon SQS moves
failed event messages to the dead-letter
queue by configuring the visibility timeout, and redrive policy on the source queue.
Error handling for asynchronous invocation.
If the function returns an error, AWS Lambda attempts to retry twice
for a total of three invocations.
There is a one-minute wait between the first two attempts
and two minutes between the second and third attempts.
If all three attempts fail, Lambda sends the failed event to a dead-letter queue, or DLQ,
if it's configured.
You can configure your function with a dead-letter queue to send these events
to Simple Queue Service, or SQS,
or Simple Notification Service, or SNS, for further processing.
The SQS queue holds failed events
until they're retrieved.
For SNS, a topic relays failed events to one or more destinations.
You can configure a topic to send events to an email address,
a Lambda function, or an HTTP endpoint.