AWS Lake Formation Overview.
AWS Lake Formation is a fully managed service
that builds, secures, and manages data lakes.
Lake Formation helps break down data silos
and combine different types of structured
and unstructured data from various sources
into a centralized repository.
For example,
you can use Lake Formation
to move data from your existing databases
running on Amazon Relational Database Service, or Amazon RDS,
or hosted in Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud, or Amazon EC2,
on-premises database and Amazon Simple Storage Service, or Amazon S3.
Lake Formation provides central fine-grained access
controls for data in your data lake.
You can use Lake Formation as your authorization engine to
enforce permissions to your data lake with integrated AWS services,
such as Amazon Athena,
Amazon EMR, and Amazon Redshift Spectrum.
AWS Lake Formation is an integrated data lake service
that helps you to ingest, clean, catalog,
transform, and secure your data.
Lake Formation also makes your data available for analysis and machine learning.
Lake Formation provides a central console where you can discover data sources,
set up transformation jobs to move data to an Amazon S3 data lake,
remove duplicates, and match records.
You can also catalog data for access by analytics tools,
configure data access and security policies,
and audit and control access from AWS analytics and machine-learning services.
Here are the key benefits and features.
Build data lakes quickly.
You can create, administer,
and protect data lakes by using familiar database-like features.
With AWS Lake Formation, you can build, clean, and secure data lakes in days.
Streamlined security management.
AWS Lake Formation streamlines security management and governance at scale.
You can centrally define fine-grained permissions
that restrict access to data at the database, table,
column, row, and cell levels.
You can also use transactions to allow multiple users and jobs
to insert data across multiple tables on Amazon S3.
Provide self-service access to data.
With Lake Formation,
you can grant or revoke permissions on tables defined in the central
AWS Glue Data Catalog.
You can also designate data owners by labeling your data with business metadata.
Enable cross-account data sharing.
AWS Lake Formation enables organization-wide data sharing at scale
in a secure and effective manner
without having to copy the entire database.