AWS Amplify Overview.
AWS Amplify is a set of purpose-built tools and features that
frontend web developers and mobile developers can use
to quickly build full-stack applications on AWS.
With Amplify,
you can configure a web or mobile application backend
and connect your app in minutes.
You can visually build a web frontend UI
and manage app content outside the AWS Management Console.
You can use Amplify to ship faster and
scale with little effort and cloud expertise.
AWS Amplify Features. Build.
You can use Amplify authentication to quickly set up
secure authentication flows with a fully managed user directory.
The Amplify framework uses Amazon Cognito as the main authentication provider.
Amplify DataStore is an
on-device storage engine that automatically synchronizes data
between your mobile and web apps in your database in the AWS Cloud.
This helps you build real-time and offline apps faster.
Release, Scale, and Manage.
Amplify offers a fully managed service for deploying and hosting
full-stack web applications with built-in CI/CD
workflows that accelerate your application release cycle.
The extensibility features of Amplify
give developers the flexibility to customize their AWS backend
and deployment capabilities.
Tools.
Amplify Studio generates automation templates when
you create backend resources.
These templates provide seamless integration with the Amplify CLI.
Amplify libraries are powered by
AWS services and can be used with new backends
created with the Amplify Command Line Interface, or CLI,
Amplify Studio,
or your existing AWS backend.
The Amplify CLI
is a toolchain to configure and maintain your backend from your local desktop.
Amplify UI Components is an open-source
toolkit that encapsulates cloud-connected workflows
inside of cross-framework UI components.
You can use Amplify hosting to host your frontend
web app, create or delete backend environments,
set up CI/CD on the frontend and backend.