AWS Site-to-Site VPN Overview
What is AWS Site-to-Site VPN?
AWS Site-to-Site VPN connects your virtual
private clouds, or VPCs, on AWS to your on-premises network.
The components of a Site-to-Site VPN
connection include:
A secure VPN connection between your
on-premises equipment and your VPCs on AWS.
An encrypted VPN tunnel, where data can
pass to, or from, AWS.
A customer gateway device, which is a
physical or software appliance that handles VPN traffic.
A customer gateway to provide information
to AWS about your customer gateway device.
An optional transit gateway, or hub, that
can be used to connect multiple VPCs and on-premises networks.
Target and virtual private gateways, which
are also VPN endpoints.
Site-to-Site VPN Features
You can configure Site-to-Site VPN using
the AWS Management Console, the AWS Command Line Interface, AWS software development kits, or by using the Query API.
Site-to-Site VPN can support either IP v4 traffic or IP v6 traffic.
Site-to-Site VPN supports many common
configurations including:
A single Site-to-Site VPN connection.
A single Site-to-Site VPN connection with
a transit gateway.
Multiple Site-to-Site VPN connections.
Multiple Site-to-Site VPN connections with
a transit gateway.
Site-to-Site VPN connections using AWS
Direct Connect.
Other options include configuring a
private IP Site-to-Site VPN connection with AWS Direct Connect, and using AWS VPN Cloud Hub for multiple VPN connections.
Site-to-Site VPN Benefits
Security.
Data is transferred between your VPC and
your network routes over an encrypted VPN connection.
Instances in your VPC do not require a
public IP address to connect to resources on the other side of your Site-to-Site VPN connection, which reduces the risk of certain types of security exploits.
Resilience.
A Site-to-Site VPN connection consists of
two tunnels, each terminating in a different Availability Zone, to provide increased availability to your VPC.
If there is a device failure within AWS,
your VPN connection automatically fails over to the second tunnel so that your access isn't interrupted.
Reliability.
AWS provides various tools that you can
use to monitor a Site-to-Site VPN connection, such as AWS CloudTrail, Amazon CloudWatch and AWS Health Dashboard.
You can configure some of these tools to
automatically do the monitoring for you, providing insight into your network traffic with both logs and metrics.