Welcome to an Overview
of the Types of Cloud Computing Models.
There are three main cloud computing models.
First, let's look at Infrastructure as a Service.
Infrastructure as a Service contains the basic building blocks for cloud IT
and typically provides access to data storage space,
compute services, virtual or dedicated hardware, and networking features.
It offers you the most control over IT resources, trading off convenience
instead of building it all by yourself.
You can also simplify provisioning and
management by modeling your cloud infrastructure with
a simple text file or programming languages and use as a template.
Our resources needed
for your applications can then be provisioned
and configured based on your template automatically.
This offers convenience to build your cloud environment.
Platform as a Service.
Platform as a Service removes the need for
organizations to manage the underlying infrastructure platform
and allows you to focus on the deployment and management of your applications.
This helps you be more efficient
as you don't need to worry about resource procurement, capacity planning,
software maintenance, patching, or any of the other undifferentiated
heavy lifting involved in running your application.
Here are some examples.
To deploy your application, all you need to do is to upload your application code.
Your application will be ready to use within minutes.
In this example,
you can still retain control over the resources powering your application
and can access the underlying resources.
You can also run containers without having to manage servers or clusters.
All you have to do is package your application code and runtime into a container,
and then simply deploy your container to the cloud underlying platform.
Provisioning and management will be handled for you.
In addition, you can run code without provisioning or managing servers.
All you need to do is to upload your code or function.
In this case, you do not have control of the underlying infrastructure.
The service provides you the convenience of taking care of
everything required to run and scale your code with high availability.
Software as a Service.
Software as a Service offers you end-user applications.
You do not have to think about how the service
is maintained or how the underlying infrastructure is managed.
All the heavy-lifting work is done for you behind the scenes.
A common example of a SaaS application is web-based email,
where you can send and receive email without
having to manage feature additions to the email product
or maintaining the servers and operating systems
that the email program is running on.
Here is a comparison between the level of control and convenience
within the three cloud computing models.
Software as a Service provides you with the highest level of convenience
as you are just using the end-user applications.
As you move from Infrastructure as a Service to Software
as a Service, your level of convenience increases.
Infrastructure as a Service
provides you the most control of your IT resources.
As you move from Software as a Service to Infrastructure as a Service,
your level of control increases.