Cloud Computing.
Cloud computing is
the on-demand delivery of compute power, database, storage, applications, and other IT
resources via the internet with pay-as-you-go pricing.
Whether you are using it to run applications that share photos
to millions of mobile users or to support business-critical operations,
a cloud services platform provides rapid access to flexible and low-cost IT resources.
You can access as many resources as you need
almost instantly and only pay for what you use.
With cloud computing,
you don't need to make large up-front investments in hardware and spend
a lot of time on the heavy lifting of managing that hardware.
Instead, you can provision exactly the right type and size of computing resources
you need to power your newest idea or operate your IT department.
Benefits of Cloud Computing.
Agility.
The cloud makes it easy and fast to access a broad-range technology such as compute,
storage databases, analytics, machine learning,
and many other services on an as-needed basis.
As a result, you can very quickly develop and roll out new
applications, and your teams can experiment
and innovate more quickly and frequently.
If an experiment fails,
you can always de-provision resources without risk,
lowering the cost of failure and the cost of change.
We can define agility as the ability to respond
to learning and changing circumstances quickly and inexpensively.
And the risk in a business could be more or less proportional to the lack of agility. Elasticity.
In the traditional data center-based model,
when you make a capacity decision prior to deploying an application,
you often end up either sitting on
expensive idle resources or dealing with limited capacity.
With cloud computing,
you can provision the amount of resources that you actually need, knowing
you can instantly scale in or out with the needs of your business.
This reduces cost and improves the ability to meet your user's demands.
Cost Savings. Eliminate guessing on your infrastructure
capacity needs. No more expensive idle resources.
You pay only for how much you consume.
Cloud computing lets you focus on your own customers
rather than on the heavy lifting of racking,
stacking, and powering servers. Also,
you don't need to invest heavily in data centers and
servers before you know how you're going to use them.
Because usage from hundreds of thousands of customers is aggregated in the cloud,
providers such as AWS can achieve higher economies of scale,
which translates into lower pay-as-you-go prices.
Deployed globally in minutes.
With a cloud,
you can easily deploy your application in multiple physical
locations around the world with just a few clicks.
This means you can provide a lower-latency and
better experience for your customers simply and at minimal cost.