Welcome to an Overview
of Computer Vision on AWS.
Computer vision allows machines to identify people, places, and things in images
with accuracy at or above human levels with much greater speed and efficiency.
Often built with deep-learning models,
it automates extraction, analysis,
classification, and understanding of useful information
from a single image or a sequence of images.
The image data can take many forms, such as single images, video sequences,
views from multiple cameras, or three-dimensional data.
Let's review some common use cases
for computer vision.
For public safety and home security,
facial recognition helps you quickly identify unlawful entries
or persons of interest, resulting in safer communities
and a more effective way of deterring crimes.
For medical imaging, analysis with computer
vision can greatly improve the accuracy and speed
of a patient's medical diagnosis, resulting in better treatment.
In manufacturing,
computer vision can be integrated into robotics
to enhance the quality assurance
and operational excellence
of manufacturing applications,
resulting in reliable,
cost-effective products.
For content management and analysis,
you can deploy metadata extraction
and image classification computer-vision models to millions of images
in order to improve efficiency
and identify revenue opportunities.
Now, let's review some of the
AWS computer-vision services.
Amazon Rekognition offers pre-trained and
customizable computer-vision models to extract information
and insights
from your images and videos.
Amazon Lookout for Metrics uses machine learning
to automatically detect and diagnose anomalies in business and operational data.
Amazon Lookout for Metrics
makes it easy to diagnose detected anomalies by grouping
together anomalies that are related to the same event
and sending an alert that includes a summary
of the potential root cause to a manager.
Amazon Textract is a machine-learning service
that automatically extracts text, handwriting,
and data from scanned documents.
Amazon Textract uses machine learning
to read, process, and understand extracted data
for any type of document.
This allows you to quickly automate document processing.
AWS Panorama is a machine-learning appliance and software development kit
that brings computer vision to on-premises IP cameras.
You can also connect Panorama-enabled devices
using the AWS Panorama SDK.
After gathering data,
you can route AWS Panorama application results
to AWS services, such as Amazon S3
and Amazon CloudWatch,
or to on-premises line-of-business applications
for automation.