Customizing IAM Policies.
Let's review the components of an IAM policy.
Permissions are granted to IAM entities including IAM users,
federated users, groups, and roles.
To give entities permissions, you can attach a policy.
A policy consists of one or more statements,
each of which describes one set of permissions.
Version. Specify the version of the policy language that you want to use.
Sid is optional
and specifies the statement ID to differentiate between your statements.
Effect. Specify whether to allow or deny access because access is denied by default.
You typically write policies where the effect is to allow.
Principal specifies the IAM entity
that is allowed or denied access to a resource
and is usually implied.
Action includes a list of actions
that you allow or deny.
Resources
specify which
AWS resources you allow the action on.
Conditions. Specify which conditions must be present
for the policy to take effect.
Now let's look at some examples of how you can customize your IAM policies.
Let's start with an initial policy that allows the ability to start an EC2 instance.
The effect is allow,
the principle is set to anyone.
The action is the permission to start EC2 instances.
This permission applies to any instance in any region.
If you wanted to restrict the capability to a single EC2 instance,
you can add an Amazon resource name, or ARN,
to the policy.
Adding a resource entry limits the permissions to only the resource listed.
You can also restrict permissions only to specific regions
by adding a policy condition.
You can list more than one policy condition in a single policy,
but all policy conditions must be true for the policy to take effect.
If the policy holder attempts to start an instance in any
other domain other than the one listed in the condition,
the action will be denied.
You may want to use a deny policy to explicitly protect certain resources.
The effect is set to deny.
By itself,
this deny would block the principal from stopping any EC2 instance.
By adding a condition listing a specific range of IP addresses,
this policy denies the ability to stop any instance
only within the address listed in the condition.
Security principals, such as users, can be assigned multiple IAM policies.
When multiple policies are assigned, all apply to
the principal, and the permissions are additive.
These two policies in combination allow the user to both start and stop EC2 instances.
Conversely,
it is possible that a principal is assigned multiple policies that conflict,
where one policy allows a specific action while the other denies the same action.
In any conflict between allow and deny permissions, deny always wins.
In this case, the principal would be denied the ability to start an EC2 instance.
Let's look at an example of an IAM policy which only allows a user to start or stop
EC2 instances in a single region.
VisualEditor0 in the Sid element means
this policy was created using the visual editor in the AWS console.
The Effect element states the user, or role,
this policy is attached to will be allowed to perform the specified actions.
There is no Principal element
since the principal will be the IAM user, or role, the policy is attached to.
The Principal element is only used for resource-based policies.
The Action element states the user can start or stop
EC2 instances.
The wildcard in the Resources element means the allow
effect will apply to all resources in the account
as long as there are no other similar policies with deny actions.
The Condition element states that this policy should only
allow the actions in the us-east-1 region.