Data Lakes on AWS Overview.
A data lake is a centralized repository that you can use
to store all your structured and unstructured data at any scale.
You can store your data as is, without having to first structure the data.
You can then run different types of analytics to guide
better decisions, from dashboards and visualizations to big-data processing,
real-time analytics,
and machine learning.
Essential Elements of a Data Lake Solution.
Data Movement.
You can use data lakes to import any amount of data that can come in real time.
Data is collected from multiple sources, and it is
moved into the data lake in its original format.
This process can scale to data of any size
while saving you the time of defining data structures, schema,
and transformations.
Securely Store and Catalog Data.
You have the ability to understand what data is
in your data lake through crawling, cataloging, and indexing.
You should also secure this data to protect the assets in data lakes.
Analytics. Data lakes allow various roles in your organization to
access data with their choice of analytic tools and frameworks.
You can run analytics in your data lake without the
need to move your data to a separate analytics system.
Machine Learning.
Organizations can use data lakes to generate different types of insights.
They can run reports on historical data,
and they can use machine-learning models to forecast likely outcomes,
suggesting a range of prescribed actions to achieve the optimal result.
Build a Data Lake on Amazon S3.
Amazon Simple Storage Service, or Amazon S3,
is the largest and most performant object
storage service for structured and unstructured data.
And it is the storage service of choice to build a data lake.
With Amazon S3,
you can cost-effectively build and scale a data lake of any size
in a secure environment where data is protected by eleven 9s of durability.
Amazon S3 automatically creates and stores copies of all uploaded
S3 objects across multiple systems.
This means that your data is available when needed and protected against failures,
errors, and threats.
Build a Data Lake with
AWS Lake Formation.
You can use
AWS Lake Formation to create a secure data lake in days instead of months.
In the streamlined Lake Formation process,
you define where data resides and what data access and security policies to apply.
Lake Formation then collects data from different sources
and moves it into a new data lake
in Amazon S3.
You can use machine-learning algorithms to clean,
catalog, and classify the data in Amazon S3
and define your access control policies.
Users can then access a centralized catalog of data
that lists the available datasets and their usage terms.