Difference between SQL and NoSQL
databases.
There are a few key differences between
SQL and NoSQLdatabases.
Optimal workloads.
Relational databases are designed for
transactional and strongly consistent online transaction processing, OLTP, applications.
They are also good for online analytical
processing, OLAP.
On the other hand, NoSQL, key value,
document, graph, and in memory databases are designed for OLTP for a number of data access patterns that include low latency applications.
NoSQL search databases are designed
for analytics over semi-structured data
Data model.
The relational model normalizes data into
tables that are composed of rows and columns.
A schema strictly defines the tables,
rows, columns, indexes, relationships between tables and other database elements.
The database enforces the referential
integrity and relationships between tables.
NoSQL databases provide a variety of
data models that includes key value, document, graph, in memory, and search.
Or you can design custom data models based
on your specific query patterns,
ACID properties.
Relational databases provide atomicity,
consistency, isolation, and durability.
Atomicity requires a transaction to
execute completely or not at all.
Consistency requires that when a
transaction has been committed, the data must conform to the database schema.
Isolation requires that concurrent
transactions execute separately from each other.
Durability requires the ability to recover
from an unexpected system failure or power outage to the last known state.
DynamoDB transactions provide
developers ACID across one or more tables within a single AWS account and region.
NoSQL databases are an excellent
choice for high throughput, low latency use cases that need to scale horizontally beyond the limitations of a single instance.
Performance.
Performance is generally dependent on the
disk subsystem, and optimization of queries, indexes, and table structure is often required to achieve peak performance.
However, performance is also a function of
the underlying hardware cluster size, network latency, and the calling application.
Scale.
Relational databases typically scale up by
increasing the compute capabilities of the hardware or scale out by adding replicas for read-only workloads.
NoSQL databases typically are
partitioned because key value access patterns are able to scale out by using distributed architecture to increase throughput.
APIs
Requests to store and retrieve data are
communicated using queries that conform to a structured query language.
SQL object-based APIs allow app developers
to easily store and retrieve in memory data structures.
Partition keys let apps look up key value
pairs, column sets, or semi-structured documents that contain serialized application objects and attributes.