Welcome to an overview of DNS, or Domain Name System.
Computers on the internet communicate with one another
by using numbers known as IP addresses.
When you visit a website,
you don't have to remember a long number.
Instead, you can enter a domain name like www.example.com
that is easier to remember.
A DNS service such as Amazon Route 53
is a globally distributed service
that translates human-readable names like www.example.com
into numeric IP addresses like 192.0.2.1
that computers use to connect to each other.
The internet's DNS (system) works much like a phone book
by managing the mapping between names and numbers.
DNS servers translate requests for names into IP addresses,
controlling which server an end user will reach
when they type a domain name into their web browser.
These requests are called queries.
Let's take a look at how DNS queries work.
First, the host sends a DNS request to the local DNS server.
Second, the DNS server,
which is preconfigured with the list of root name servers, randomly selects one
root name server for the "A" record www.example.com.
An "A" record maps a domain name
like example.com to an IP address
of the computer that hosts the domain.
Third, the root name server responds
with a list of authoritative name servers for the .com zone,
along with a list of the IP addresses.
Fourth, the DNS server randomly selects one of the authoritative name
servers returned in step three
and sends another DNS query for the "A" record
example.com to the top-level domain server.
Fifth, the top-level domain name server
responds with a list of name servers
that are authoritative for the domain example.com.
Sixth, the DNS server
randomly selects one of the authoritative name servers returned in step five
and sends another DNS query for the "A" record example.com.
Seventh, since the name server receiving the query in step six
is authoritative for the domain example.com,
the name server responds to the DNS server with the IP address value
of the "A" record for example.com.
And for the final step, the DNS server
sends the DNS response with the IP address back to the host,
which enables the host computer to connect to www.example.com.