Create and query a no sequel table with
Amazon DynamoDB.
Before we talk about creating tables,
let's go through a few basic terms about DynamoDB tables.
A table is a collection of data which we
call items.
Each item has some characteristics, which
we call attributes.
Each item in the table has a unique
identifier, or primary key.
DynamoDB supports two different kinds of
primary keys, partition key and sort key.
The partition key is mandatory. DynamoDB
uses the partition key's value as input to an internal hash function.
The output from the hash function
determines the partition, which is physical storage internal to DynamoDB in which the item will be stored.
The partition key enables partitions for
scalability purposes.
The sort key is optional and provides
additional flexibility for querying data.
Now let's look at how you can create a
simple table with Amazon DynamoDB service.
We will use a music library in this
example.
To create a DynamoDB table, first enter
the table name.
In this case, "music."
Next, enter a partition key.
In this example, artist.
Since each artist may write many songs,
you can enable easy sorting with a sort key.
In this example, use "song title" as the
sort key.
Next enable auto scaling.
Finally, create the table. The music table
is created and ready to use.
You can add data to the table by creating
a data record called item.
In this example, enter the artist's name
and song title for each item.
There are two ways of searching data,
query or scan.
In a query operation, you must specify a
partition key value. Sort key is optional.
For example, you can search by artist, and
also narrow down the search results by song title.
On the other hand, a scan operation always
scans the entire table.
By default, it returns all of the data
attributes for every item in the table.
If an optional filter expression is
provided, it then filters out values to provide the results you want
To delete an existing item from a table,
you must specify the primary key value to delete one item at a time.
For applications that need to read or
write multiple items, DynamoDB provides batch operations.
In addition, DynamoDB performs the
individual read or write operations in parallel. Your applications benefit from this parallelism.