Introduction to an AWS Glue Crawler.
Let's start with some key concepts.
What is an AWS Glue crawler?
An AWS Glue crawler
is a program that connects to a datastore,
extracts metadata,
and creates table definitions in the AWS Glue Data Catalog.
An AWS Glue Data Catalog is the persistent metadata store in AWS Glue.
It contains table definitions,
job definitions, and other control information
to manage your AWS Glue environment.
Actual data is not stored in the data catalog.
When a crawler runs,
it uses a classifier.
A classifier
reads the data,
determines the format,
and generates a schema.
AWS Glue provides a set of built-in classifiers
for common file types such as CSV, JSON,
Parquet,
AVRO,
XML, and others.
You can also create
custom classifiers.
Now,
let's look at how
a crawler works.
First, a crawler progresses through
a prioritized list of classifiers.
If a custom classifier is defined,
the first custom classifier
that successfully recognizes
the structure of your data
is used to create a schema.
If there is no custom classifier,
built-in classifiers are used.
The crawler
then connects to the datastore.
A crawler
can crawl multiple datastores in a single run.
For example,
a crawler can crawl datastores
such as Amazon Simple Storage Service, or Amazon S3,
Amazon DynamoDB,
and Delta Lake natively.
For Java database connectivity, or JDBC,
MongoDB,
and Amazon DocumentDB (with MongoDB compatibility) datastores,
a crawler
must use an AWS Glue connection
to connect to the datastore.
You can run the crawler
either on demand or on a schedule.
Upon completion,
the crawler then creates or updates one or more
tables with table definitions in your data catalog.
The tables are written to a database,
which is a container of tables in the data catalog.
After table definitions are added to the data catalog,
they are available for extract, transform,
and load, or
ETL, jobs.
The table definitions are also readily available
for querying in Amazon Athena,
Amazon EMR,
and Amazon Redshift Spectrum.
A crawler can run more than once.
For example, here is the output of a crawler after running the first time.
If your crawler runs again, perhaps on a schedule,
it looks for new or changed files or tables in your datastore.
The output of the crawler
includes new tables and partitions found since the previous run.