Machine Learning Algorithms.
Machine learning or ML
can help solve a variety of business problems across many industries.
An example of questions that ML can help a data scientist answer are,
Is this internet traffic pattern indicative of a hacker?
Does this mammography scan show signs of cancer?
Or how many days before this manufacturing part fails?
A data scientist must choose
the type of ML algorithm to use.
This decision is mostly dependent on the type of data available to train the model.
If the training data includes both features and labels already defined,
then you can use a supervised learning algorithm.
If the training data does not include labels,
then you would use an unsupervised learning algorithm.
Let us take a closer look at both types of algorithms.
Supervised Algorithms.
Linear Regression.
Linear-regression algorithms aim to learn the correlation
between a set of input features (x)
and a continuous output variable way.
The goal of the algorithm is to be able to predict a continuous numerical value.
For example,
a manufacturing engineer
knowing the number of weeks before a critical component fails is valuable,
allowing them to proactively schedule
focused maintenance, thereby reducing downtime.
Classification.
A classification algorithm's goal
is to understand the relationship
between feature data and an output label.
The end result should be
the ability of the ML model
to separate the data
into distinct groups.
For instance,
to predict customer sentiment, a company can collect data such as
age, gender, purchase history,
and customer service interactions.
The ML model can then use that data to compare how other customers
with similar features felt and then label their sentiment as happy or not happy.
Unsupervised Algorithms.
Clustering. Clustering algorithms analyze unordered input data
and attempts to label them into discrete groupings.
In this case, the unordered items have been analyzed
and labeled into three groups: fish, sheep, and cats.
The number of groupings
and the group labels are unknown
and part of the problem the ML model solves.
For example,
a clustering algorithm can be used to determine
what trending subjects are being discussed
in an organization's social media posts,
then cluster them into topics such as an upcoming merger,
a new product launch, or a service outage so they can be addressed by management.
Anomaly detection.
Anomaly-detection algorithms help solve a special type of ML problem
where the number of clusters is two.
This type of algorithm
excels at finding
unusual activity and large data sets.
Detecting intruders in a computer network
by analyzing log data is an anomaly-detection problem.
Unusual activity would be labeled as anomalous,
if it departed significantly from normal patterns.