NoSQL database overview.
What is NoSQL?
NoSQL databases are non relational
databases.
They do not require a fixed predefined
schema and do not have structured tables with rows and columns.
NoSQL databases are purpose built and
optimized for many modern applications.
They are a great fit for mobile, web, and
gaming applications that require large data volume, low latency, high performance, and flexible data models to provide great user experiences.
Here is an example of modeling the schema
for a simple book database in a relational database.
A book record is stored in separate tables
and relationships are defined by primary and foreign key constraints.
The book's table has columns for ISBN book
title and edition number.
The author's table has columns for author
ID and author name, and the author ISBN table has columns for author ID and ISBN.
The relational model is designed to enable
the database to enforce data integrity normalize to reduce the redundancy and generally optimized for storage in a NoSQL database.
A book record can be stored as JSON
document for each book.
The item ISBN book title edition number,
author name and author ID are stored as attributes in a single document.
In this model data is optimized for
intuitive development and horizontal scalability.
Why should you use a NoSQL database?
Flexibility.
Flexible schemas enable faster and more
iterative development.
Scalability.
NoSQL databases are generally designed
to scale out by using distributed clusters of hardware instead of scaling up by adding expensive and robust servers.
High performance.
NoSQL databases are distributed and
designed for massive parallel high performance data processing across multiple processing nodes and servers.
This enables higher performance than
trying to accomplish similar functionality with relational databases.
Highly functional.
NoSQL databases provide highly
functional API's and data types that are purpose built for each of their respective data models.
NoSQL databases use a variety of data
models.
Key value.
A key value database uses a simple key
value method to store data.
The key serves as a unique identifier that
is highly partitionable and allows horizontal scaling at scale.
Use cases include gaming, advertising,
technology, and IOT.
Amazon DynamoDB is a key value database.
Document.
A document database is designed to store
and query data as a JSON-like document.
This makes it easier for developers as
they are using the same document model format as their application code.
Typical use cases include catalogs, user
profiles, and content management systems where each document is unique and evolves over time.
Amazon DocumentDB with MongoDB
compatibility and MongoDB are popular document databases.
Graph.
Graph databases are purpose built to store
and navigate relationships.
Nodes store data entities.
Edges store relationships between
entities.
An edge always has a start node and node
type and direction.
An edge can describe parent child
relationships, actions, ownership and the like.
Typical use cases include social
networking recommendation engines, fraud detection and knowledge graphs.
Amazon Neptune is a fully managed graph
database service.
Popular graph databases include Neo4J
and Giraph
In memory.
An in-memory database relies primarily on
memory for data storage, in contrast to databases that store data on disk or SSDs.
They are designed to attain minimal
response time by eliminating the need to access disks.
In-memory databases are ideal for
applications such as gaming leaderboards, session stores and real time analytics.
These applications require microsecond
response times and can have large spikes in traffic coming at any time.
Amazon ElastiCache offers MemCached and
Redis.
Amazon DynamoDB Accelerator (DAX) makes
DynamoDB reads an order of magnitude faster.
Search.
A search engine database is dedicated to
the search of content data.
Search engine databases use indexes to
categorize the similar characteristics among data and facilitate search capability.
Typical use cases are text search,
logging, and analysis.
Amazon Elasticsearch Service is a
powerful high performance search engine for full text search use cases.