Serverless Computing.
Serverless removes the heavy lifting for you.
You can build and run applications and services without thinking about servers.
You can focus on building product which scale and that are reliable.
There are four key benefits of Serverless.
There is no more need to provision or maintain any servers.
You do not need to worry about scaling or capacity planning.
AWS automatically scales with your usage.
Pay for value.
You pay only for what you use and when you are using it.
Serverless provides built-in availability and fault tolerance.
AWS provides a broad set of managed
services to help you build serverless applications.
Here's an overview of these services.
Compute. AWS Lambda.
It allows you to code without provisioning or managing servers.
Lambda@Edge also allows you to run Lambda functions
at AWS edge locations in response to Amazon CloudFront events.
AWS Fargate is a purpose-built serverless compute engine for containers.
It scales and manages the infrastructure required to run your containers.
Storage. Amazon Simple Storage Service.
Amazon S3 provides secure, durable, highly scalable object storage.
Amazon Elastic File System.
Amazon EFS provides simple, scalable elastic file storage.
It is built to elastically scale on demand,
growing and shrinking automatically as you add and remove files.
Datastores.
Amazon DynamoDB is a fast and flexible NoSQL database service for
all applications that need consistent
single-digit millisecond latency at any scale.
Amazon Aurora Serverless is an on-demand autoscaling configuration
for Amazon Aurora, MySQL, and PostgreSQL-compatible ,
where the database will automatically start up, shut down,
and scale capacity up or down based on your application's needs.
API proxy.
Amazon API Gateway is a fully managed service
that makes it easy for developers to create,
publish, maintain, monitor, and secure APIs at any scale.
Application integration.
Amazon SNS is a fully managed publish and subscribe messaging service.
Amazon SQS is a fully managed message queuing service.
AWS AppSync simplifies application development by letting you create a flexible
GraphQL API to securely access, manipulate,
and combine data from one or more data sources.
Amazon EventBridge is a serverless event bus service that makes it easy to access
application data from a variety of sources
and send it into your AWS environment.
Analytics.
Amazon Kinesis is a platform for streaming data on AWS.
Amazon Athena is an interactive query service that makes it easy
to analyze data in Amazon S3
using standard SQL.
Orchestration. AWS Step Functions
lets you coordinate multiple AWS services into serverless workflows,
so you can build and update apps quickly.
Developer tooling.
AWS and its partner ecosystem offer tools for continuous integration
and delivery, testing, deployments, monitoring and diagnostics SDKs,
frameworks, and integrated development environment, or IDE, plug-ins.
AWS provides a set of fully managed services
that you can use to build and run serverless applications.
Using AWS and its serverless platform,
it enables you to build modern applications
with increased agility and lower total cost of ownership.