Welcome to the Solution Center.
Here you will learn about AWS services
and receive guidance
on how to build AWS solutions for common
use cases.
The Solution Center has four sections
Learn, plan, practice
and do it yourself. DIY.
Use the learn section to study the
architecture and watch AWS service videos.
The plan section provides
an overview of the building tasks.
Use the practice section
to build the first part of the solution
using the AWS
console and image based instructions.
To begin
building allow pop-ups, then launch
the AWS console in a separate browser tab.
Follow the steps to complete part
one of the solution,
then move to the do it yourself section.
In the do it yourself section.
You must build part
two of your solution, then validate it.
Read the hints on the left panel,
then build part two of your solution
using the same AWS console environment.
Use the validation
field to confirm functionality.
If your solution is valid,
you can move on to the next task.
One more important
note. The AWS console environment
starts up and shuts down
automatically with a temporary account.
You should never use your personal AWS
account in the solution center.
That's all for now.
Good luck with your search for Cloudia.