Supervised Learning.
Supervised learning
is a type of machine learning algorithm which learns from historical labeled data
and predicts future outcomes.
The input training data set
includes both the input values,
also referred as features and the known output values,
which are labels with the correct answers.
In this example,
the algorithm is given a set of training data with images of dogs,
where the data is correctly labeled as dogs.
You can then use supervised learning to generalize from these examples and
predict how likely the image provided is a dog or not.
Each machine-learning algorithm has its own strengths and challenges
the strengths of supervised learning a simplicity
and ease of design.
However, labeling millions of new data takes time
and can be a challenging task.
Supervised learning algorithms
are used to solve classification or regression problems.
First, let's talk about one of the use cases, classification.
Classification problems predicts which class or category
the object belongs to.
It is a process of sorting a given set of data into different classes.
The output of classification
are distinct values.
Binary classification predicts one of the two possible outcomes.
It predicts answers such as, "Is this email classified as spam or not?"
Multiclass classification predicts one of
multiple possible outcomes in problems.
For example, is this movie a romantic comedy, documentary, or thriller?
Some popular algorithms for classification include
logistic regression, k-nearest neighbor, or KNN,
support vector machine, or SVM, random forest and Naive Bayes.
In contrast, regression problems predict
a numeric value from continuous outcomes.
The goal is to plot a best-fit line or a curve between the data.
For example,
you can use regression to predict what price will this house sell for.
Some popular algorithms for regression include linear regression,
k-nearest neighbor, or KNN, support vector machine, or SVM,
and random forest.
However, there is no single learning algorithm
that works best on all supervised learning problems.