Supervised Learning Algorithms.
Here are some of the algorithms
used in supervised learning.
K-nearest neighbor, or KNN, classifies a data point
based on similarity of the k-nearest neighbor.
In this example,
if we choose k = four,
KNN finds the four nearest neighbors to the new data point.
Since the new data point is closer to more apples, it belongs to the apple class.
In terms of applications,
KNN algorithm can be used for recommendation systems
and search applications where you are finding similar items.
Support vector machine, or SVM:
SVM algorithm creates a line, or a hyper plane,
which separates the data into classes in classification
or predicts a specific value in regression.
It is a popular approach in research.
Random forest:
A random-forest algorithm consists of many decision trees.
The algorithm predicts by taking the average of the output from various trees.
Some random-forest algorithm applications include credit-card fraud detection
and disease prediction.
Naive Bayes:
Naive Bayes algorithm is based on applying Bayes's theorem,
which calculates the probability, the likelihood of
an event A happening given B happens.
Common applications include text classification and spam filtering.
Linear regression:
Linear regression trains an algorithm to find
a linear relationship between the input and output data.
It predicts a numeric value within a continuous range.
For example,
linear regression can be used for weather forecasting,
price estimation, and stock price prediction.
Logistic regression:
Logistic regression is used to predict one of the two possible outcomes,
such as the likelihood of an event.
For example,
logistic-regression algorithms can be used to predict election results,
probabilities of a natural disaster,
and other such events.