TensorFlow Framework Overview,
TensorFlow framework on Amazon SageMaker.
TensorFlow is an open-source machine learning
and artificial intelligence framework.
With TensorFlow,
you can use custom code
along with Amazon SageMaker
to train and deploy a machine-learning model.
The SageMaker Python SDK, along with the open-source TensorFlow containers,
makes it easy to write TensorFlow taining scripts.
TensorFlow 2
focuses on simplicity and ease of use
with updated features like eager execution,
intuitive high-level APIs,
and flexible model building on any platform.
TensorFlow Framework Benefits.
Easy Model Building.
TensorFlow offers multiple levels of abstraction
for their APIs.
Using the Keras API,
quickly build and train ML models to get started with machine learning.
The distributed strategy API
lets you distribute larger training jobs across multiple
hardware configurations with minimal or no code changes.
Robust ML Production Anywhere.
Whether it's on servers,
edge devices, or the cloud,
TensorFlow lets you train and deploy your models anywhere,
no matter what language your platform uses.
Powerful Experimentation for Research.
Build and train
state-of-art ML models without sacrificing speed or performance.
TensorFlow also supports an ecosystem
of powerful add-on libraries and models to experiment with.
This includes ragged tensors,
TensorFlow probability, Tensor2Tensor, BERT and Mixture of Experts.