Unsupervised Learning Algorithms.
Unsupervised learning uses a range of algorithms, and here are some examples.
Hierarchical clustering.
Hierarchical clustering is based on a cluster tree.
In this algorithm, each data point is considered as an individual cluster to start with.
At each iteration, similar clusters merge with other clusters
until a desired number of clusters are formed.
Hierarchical clustering
is widely used for analyzing social network data.
K-means clustering.
When using the k-means algorithm, you specify an input k
that specifies the number of clusters to find in the data.
The centroid of a plane
is the arithmetic mean position of all the points.
In this example,
we choose k equals to two
and start to place the two centroids in random locations.
The k-means algorithm
then iteratively determines the centroids
and assigns each member to the closest centroid.
Members nearest to the same centroid belong to the same group.
Eventually, the algorithm reaches the best centroids for the k clusters.
Common applications include market segmentation and image compression.
Principal component analysis, or PCA.
Principal component analysis, or PCA, algorithm
reduces the dimensionality within a dataset by projecting
data points onto the first few principal components.
Principal components
are new variables that are constructed as
linear combinations of the initial variables
with the help of orthogonal transformation.
The objective is to reduce the dimensions
while retaining as much information or variation as possible.
In this example,
the two-dimensional datasets are reduced to a one-dimensional representation,
which is a function of the principal component.
Common applications for PCA algorithm
include facial recognition and computer vision.